This is it my friend the object I spoke
of thanks to our progress with the steam
engine we've excavated deeper than
ever found new minerals and refined them
creating revolutionary sources of fuel
and it was in that search for industrial power
that we discovered it the ultimate element by splitting
its atom massive amounts of energy are released.
I've chosen to call this all
mighty element Uranium
As a respected
ambassidor for the Military
Please help me bring this bomb
to the attention of central command.
No.
You claim it has ultimate potential, but
all you've made is another weapon for war.
That's the last thing
our country needs.
Sorry.
But I wont introduce it
Is the young and
promissing Alchemist afraid?
You give such lofty speeches,
but your real reasons are clear.
The state only gives you authority
because of your alchemic power.
Authority?
You're scared a weapon like
this will render you obsolete in war.
And without that leverage, the Alchemist's
stranglehold of this state will vanish.
Now let's see what the alchemist
of the people really looks like.
hahahaha!
Are you so fragile?
A hack in a cheap suit of armor.
Impossible!
It's empty!
How can that be?
It couldn't just
move on its own.
It's unexplainable!
Everything can be explained.
Huskisson!
You made two big mistakes.
What?
Who are you?
Brother, what took you so long?
He put holes in me!
Sorry.
I got held up.
Tell me who you are!
Mistake number one.
You thought we cared
about your invention.
We only came because
you wouldn't shut up about it.
What?
That and the off chance that it
could help us on our own search.
You'll take me to Central
if you value your life.
And mistake number two.
That young and promising state
alchemist you were looking for is me.
A mechanical arm.
Automail.
So that's what it means.
The Fullmetal Alchemist!
Damn you!
And your mystical Alchemy.
If it wasn't for you zealots, physicists would be
guiding the state into a new and enlightened age.
Enlightenment like that?
Uranium mining is dangerous.
It's the cost of progress.
Science that doesn't benefit
people is no science at all!
Stand back!
You know what this is now.
Interfere and I'll use it!
I may not respect your sorcery, but
that hasn't stopped me from learning it.
For a man first in atomic equations, a
few circles were easy enough to understand.
What are you planning now?
It's my backup plan, Fullmetal.
An army of men
fused with machines.
You won't stand a chance.
Don't do it!
That's human transmutation!
Listen to me!
Life only flows in one direction and
humans aren't supposed to be brought back.
It's Alchemy's greatest
taboo for a reason.
Your arcane rules
mean nothing to me!
I'm a man of science!
Huskisson!
Noooooooo!
What is this?
It's just like what happened to us
when we tried to bring Mom back.
You mean almost like us.
You kept my soul here, attaching
it to this armor by trading your arm.
While for his
attempt, he lost it all.
We didn't respect
equivalent exchange.
And that's why we need the
stone to get your body back.
Your arm and leg too, brother.
Let's go.
This whole castle's
about to explode.
Why?
Because I don't like it.
I made some adjustments
to the steam tanks.
Why do you have
to be so excessive?
You should have told me!
There's no point in arguing now.
Come on, let's go.
Go where?
We're floating on the water and if I
get wet I can wash off my blood seal!
Then stop whining
and help me think!
We're sinking, we're sinking,
we're sinking, we're sinking!
I know, I know!
I'm trying!
Faster, Al!
Give me your head!
Hey, brother, stop!
Get that back!
Stop complaining, would you?
I gotta get the water out!
Well, then transmute something!
You don't have to use my head!
Hahahahahahahaha.
So, after that, the story of the champion
of the people, Alchemist, spread from a
few little mining regions to
every corner of the continent.
The end.
You know, you should become
a novelist with the stories you tell.
Saying you don't believe me?
Oh, come on, Ed.
Ed, a place where Alchemy kept evolving
and was more important than the steam engine?
Hmph.
Newton's laws eclipsed Alchemy,
ushering in the modern age.
That's a historical fact.
Yeah, and this world, you mean.
I'm telling you!
Heeeeeeeeeeeeey!
Hey, stop!
You okay, Alphonse?
It's just a little
cold, that's all.
Going to the carnival?
We sure are.
Hop in!
If you don't mind sitting with gypsies,
we're on our way to the carnival, too.
So, what kind of a show
are you ladies setting up?
You name it.
Singing, theater.
What's your act?
She's a fortune teller,
and she always gets it right.
So much so, it's eerie.
She'll find out all those secrets
you don't want anyone else to know.
So, can you tell me mine?
Cut it out.
You know how
unscientific that is?
You're the same as we are.
You have no home.
There it is!
The carnival!
Ah, Noah!
It's been too long!
I'm paying you in francs.
At this point, blank paper
is worth more than a Mark.
What's going on?
You're staying here, Noah.
I see now.
You brought me here
just so you could sell me.
Able to gaze into a person's
heart just by touching them.
Your clairvoyance
is the genuine article.
There are important people who
have use for gifts like that, such as...
Where's Lieutenant Hess?
He's outside.
So this is the girl.
Stop her!
Well, aren't you popular.
Dr. Oberth's book on space flight
has captured the public's imagination.
Thanks for the help.
Done up here, Mr. Heiderich!
Great!
Uh, Ed, where you going?
I'm taking a nap
out by the trucks.
My neck's sore from the crash.
You're not gonna watch?
He was the most enthusiastic of all of
us when we met him at Dr. Oberth's place.
Someone help me!
Aren't you a Gypsy
The men!
They're chasing me!
Yeah, probably because
you stole their wallets.
Everyone knows you
Gypsies are thieves.
As far as I've traveled, I still
can't escape from this place.
If I were you, I wouldn't
go digging around in there.
That rocket's set to launch.
There she is!
Hurry!
Nice try, girl.
Hey!
This woman has
a contract with us!
Come on!
Help me!
This is a carnival!
Go have some fun!
Hey, I don't think
you heard me right!
We bought this Gypsy
fair and square, boy!
Okay, you asked for it!
Sorry, just an
old habit of mine.
You might want to run.
It's a sight to behold.
Mr. Hess!
Hey, this is the guy.
The one who's offering
to sponsor our research.
You can build what we seek and
lead aeronautics into a new age.
I definitely want
you on our side.
Sure.
Thanks.
Lieutenant!
We've got a problem.
The girl escaped.
I'm sorry.
Escaped how?
Where's your home?
I told you.
I don't have one.
Preposterous.
I bet you never stepped
foot on the battlefield.
Sure I did.
I spent three years in the trenches,
crawling around in the mines.
Then you know it
was breaking us.
And what are we now?
The only thing the Treaty of Versailles did was
humiliate us and leave all Germans in poverty.
Except the aristocrats
and the Jews.
She escaped.
That is a problem.
I was Wrather hoping she could
find the Great Serpent for us.
I'm terribly sorry.
Let's go to the villa.
We need to report
this to Eckhart.
Sir!
You sure it's okay?
Me staying here?
They're looking for you.
There's no choice.
Besides, I'm kinda glad.
You are?
It's the first time Ed's really
taken an interest in a girl.
I mean, I'm not trying to say
Ed's some anti-social person.
He just doesn't get
close to anybody.
Not emotionally, anyway.
He's too busy telling stories
about some other world.
You mean his... his home?
That's what he'd say.
Well, gotta run.
I can't believe we have
our own factory now.
Winry.
Listen, about Al...
He already left?
Really?
Yes.
He said he had
his own factory now.
Do you need any help?
It's been two years.
I'm used to him by now.
You can move them that much?
Yeah, the simple stuff.
My arm and leg are gone, but my brain's
still sending out signals to move them.
These machines take those
signals and amplify them.
To be honest, I
don't understand it all.
My dad's the one who made them.
Where is your father?
I don't know.
One day he just left
and never came back.
So I ended up living
here with Alphonse.
We became friends when we studied
rocketry together with Dr. Oberth.
Armor.
I saw a suit of armor
walking beside you.
Then you looking
up at a smiling face.
That must have been your mother.
And then... a village on
a hill in a grassy plain.
You said these visions are unscientific, but
to me they're as clear as this stairway now.
Please, tell me
about this other world.
What is it like there?
The same as this
one, pretty much.
Names for things are a little different,
and the places aren't the same.
But I've seen a whole
lot of familiar faces.
So if that other world's your
home, then why are you here?
In the world that I'm from,
my younger brother was killed.
In trying to bring him
back, I wound up here.
It seems that's the
price I had to pay.
Or maybe not.
Maybe this is just the hell I've been
allotted for trying the Forbidden again.
Two years ago, I met the
Alphonse who lives here.
Alphonse Heiderich.
And if my brother
Al had grown up...
I'm sure he'd look
exactly the same.
So who knows what
is and isn't science.
Maybe this whole
world's just a dream.
Good morning, Gracia.
Good morning, Edward.
Oh, there you go
with that face again.
Who do I remind you of?
Your mother?
Or is it a girlfriend?
It's nothing, really.
Oh, thanks for lending
Noah these clothes.
Mm-hmm.
So you two are going out today?
Just be careful, all right?
Did you hear?
They're saying we have to pay our
taxes in gold now instead of marks.
You know it's bad when the
people who print it don't want it.
All these marks won't
even buy me a beer.
Burn them, then.
Yeah, right.
Then what would I slap you with?
If you don't want them,
just give them to me.
That's okay, Hughes.
I got it saved for retirement.
Hey!
Edward!
Morning, Officer Hughes.
You do know that girl who's
moved in with you is a Gypsy, right?
I hadn't noticed.
Watch out.
You and Alphonse think you're being noble by
helping someone in need, but that's her game.
Gypsies are smooth talkers.
What?
They trick men to steal their wallets,
then they're on to their next Mark.
They are drifters, after all.
Well, I'm a drifter, too.
Look, I'm telling
you this as a friend.
If something bad happens,
it'll be trouble for Gracia.
Well, how about this?
Confess your love to her
instead of bothering us.
Save you some time.
Trust me, she'll
be good for you.
Have you ever heard of
respecting your elders, Ed?
I don't think I'm being hustled.
There are all sorts of people who'd like the
power to see into human hearts with a touch.
Especially in this country,
with all that's going on.
And I think they would
chase you down to get it.
So you believe my gift is real?
A suit of armor
walking beside me.
I've never told
anyone here about that.
Not even Alphonse.
You had my hand.
What did you see this time?
Nothing strong, really.
My power works best
when people are asleep.
Oh yeah?
Why's that?
Because when they're sleeping,
I can see what they dream.
The Berlin government
is spineless.
They have no intention of
protecting Germany at all.
What can they really do?
Germany lost the war.
We can't complain about
our territory being taken.
Germany didn't lose.
The Communists and the Jews just
surrendered before we could finish it.
- Don't get so
worked up. Hey Noah,
- It's not good for you.
Can i have my coat?
What's wrong with you?
Get her out of here!
Why should I?
Gypsies like her
are just like the Jews!
They don't have their own country, so
they come into ours and steal our money
and our jobs until
there's nothing left to take!
They're just a
race of parasites!
I'm sure it gets to you.
hearing speeches like that.
Not really.
My people have gotten used
to ignorance about who we are.
The name Gypsy comes from a myth we
spread that we were fortune-tellers from Egypt.
Bohemians, Satanos, Cowleys, Sigourners,
Nomads... Outsiders can call us what they want.
I see.
But then how do you
refer to yourselves?
You must have some name.
Roma.
Roma?
It's our word for human.
I'll see you back at
the apartment, okay?
Wait, what's wrong?
Why?
Why is a Homunculus here?
Very funny.
A rock in the road.
Kids in this country need
something better to do with their time.
Führer Bradley.
Führer?
But if you made it here after the
General's assault, that means he...
General?
Are you talking about the war?
Don't play dumb with me!
Your left eye.
Let me see it.
If you insist.
Thanks.
Of course.
That would make sense.
Homunculi take the appearance of
the human they were meant to replace.
So if those people survived here,
then they would look like them too.
Mistook for someone else?
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
I'm Jewish, so
I'm used to worse.
Men in this country have convinced themselves that I'm
some conniving aristocrat, try to take me for all I'm worth.
Anyhow, do you by chance
know how to drive a car?
More or less.
Then perhaps you'll be
so kind as to take his place.
At least until he wakes up.
Magnificent.
With that propulsion system,
we'll have a ship in no time.
Look at you all.
Blonde hair, blue eyes.
You are the model of the ancient Aryan
race and the pride of the German people.
I'm sure Chairman Eckhart will be
most delighted with your progress.
We've located the
Great Serpent, Professor.
Is it true, Chairman Eckhart?
You've learned where
the Great Serpent has fled?
It seems so.
We have an eyewitness report.
Lieutenant Hess, take charge.
Ma'am.
The time for our passage into
Shamballa draws near, Professor.
Actually, this couldn't
have worked out better.
I've been looking for a capable person like
yourself who could give me a little muscle.
You got people coming
after you or something?
To the contrary.
I'm the one who's hunting.
A dragon, to be exact.
A dragon?
By the way, you can call me
Mabuse, and I'll pay you a fair rate.
Here.
Rumor is some would-be burglar broke into
this abandoned castle, and that's when he saw it.
Saw what?
Well, the dragon.
I know.
It's foolish.
Most people say
it was just a snake.
You came all the way here
on a rumor from a scared thief?
I have my reasons.
The idea of finding a living, breathing
dragon is quite appealing to me.
Why, are you gonna
slay it, get knighted?
Talk about a wild goose chase.
Edward Elric.
Who said that?
I've been looking for you.
Have you missed me?
Is that really you Envy?
So this is what happened to you,
when you crossed through the gate?
Take me to Hohenheim!
To our father!
It's the one thing I thought I was safe
from in this world, fighting Homunculi like you!
Those fighters? Who are they?
All lancers to battle positions!
Fire!
These lancers were forged from the true spear
of Longinus and scattered throughout the world.
It has taken a great deal
of effort to gather them all.
Hold on!
Just tell me what
you're gonna do with him!
I suggest you forget
what you've seen here.
It's not something ordinary
people need to know.
Haushofer?
Have you forgotten me?
I guess that's no
surprise, General.
We haven't seen each other since
before the war, when we met in Japan.
I heard you were lecturing
at Munich University now.
I'd been meaning to stop
by, but with my scav...
Haushofer?
I've heard that
name from my father.
And you are?
Edward Elric.
Nice to meet you.
My father's name is Hohenheim.
Have you seen him?
This is an important
victory, Professor.
Now the Great Serpent is
once again in our possession.
He said he was Edward Elric.
And what does that mean?
It means that he's
Hohenheim's true son.
Our Hohenheim?
But how?
His sons are from Shambhala.
Yes.
To think another person has
safely passed through the gate.
Pale white and black,
with false citrine
imperfect white and red,
The Peacock's
feathers in bright colors,
The rainbow extending
across the sky above,
the spotted leopard,
the green lion,
The crow's bill, blue as lead.
My son.
How nice to see you.
Professor, time to try.
Chairman, even with the armor protecting them, they
have little hope of passing through the gate untainted.
To Shambhala!
General!
General Mustang!
Where are you?
It's us!
Lieutenant Havok.
Lieutenant Breda.
It's good to see you again.
Thanks for coming out.
By the way, you
can drop the general.
I gave that up.
I'm just an enlisted man now.
Right, I forgot.
I guess we outrank you now.
I know it was your choice, sir.
Volunteering for an outpost
way out here in the sticks.
But still... I plan to do all I can
for my country in my own way.
End of discussion.
Matches?
I haven't used Alchemy
once since that day.
I gave that up too.
But you're the
Flame Alchemist, sir.
I start to now and then.
But each time I try, I see the faces of all the
innocent people who died because of my mistakes.
That's what this eye sees.
Maybe Lieutenant Hawkeye
should have come, too.
She always knows
how to talk to him.
Don't kid yourself.
She wouldn't come.
I doubt she'd want to
see Mustang like that.
Besides, I get the feeling the
lieutenant isn't the one he's waiting for.
What do you mean?
Oh.
Two months ago, she finally
got so bad that she couldn't move.
She told Al to go, that there
was nothing left to teach him.
She just didn't want him to see.
I'm sorry.
And Al?
He still hasn't given
up on finding Edward?
Not at all.
He can't be dissuaded.
He's convinced that
Ed is alive somewhere.
He says he has these
dreams, where he's seventeen.
And he coughs the
way Izumi always did.
And he lives with
Ed in a bustling city.
The two of them design machines
together that fly up into space.
Take good care of them for me.
Looks like someone
needs some maintenance.
Let me help.
The Armstrong Foundation will work with
you all, in every aspect of the continuing
reconstruction of Lior, building a thriving Metropolis
that will rival even Central in its beauty and splendor.
We will press forward with great diligence to
create a city that will exemplify the East in this new era.
I offer this shop as a
gift between friends.
Wow, yeah, that's
really something.
that a transmutation circle?
Everyone, get inside.
Alchemy almost wiped
this city off the map.
Who would dare use it now?
Soldiers, but where
are they coming from?
He's making tornadoes.
With Alchemy.
It's Al.
Lior, this is Central.
Do you copy?
Lior!
There's an
earthquake in Lior too?
At the exact same
time as this one?
There are also reports of
enemy soldiers appearing there.
Though it hasn't been confirmed.
We have tight security
on the eastern border.
How could an enemy
cross without us knowing?
Watch out!
Alphonse Elric.
You look well.
This is Major Armstrong, Al.
He's your friend, remember?
Rose!
Of course, Major.
I've heard about you.
You helped us on
our journey, right?
So you still haven't recovered
your memory of those years?
What was that?
I'm controlling the
suits of armor I touched.
I transferred a portion
of my soul into them.
A portion of your soul?
Oh, don't worry.
I'm fine.
For some reason, it just
comes naturally to me.
Poor Al.
All those lost memories.
Four years spent
with his brother.
Still, seeing how he's progressed, it's as if
Edward's been leading him every step of the way.
The men inside
the armor are dead.
And apparently they've been dead
since before they reached the surface.
Dead from what?
I don't know.
They seem to have been subjected
to extreme levels of pressure.
So, are you really
still looking for him?
Yeah.
But Al, he's gone.
Let go, you'll dissapear too!
Look, it's the only way for the Inspector
General in Bavaria to take us seriously.
Gracia, about that Gypsy...
That went well.
But why?
Do you think there's
going to be another war?
I don't know.
I certainly hope not, but
there's a lot of talk right now.
And if it did happen, God forbid,
your people could be in danger.
There are men saying they want to reshape the country
so it's just authentic Germans and kick out everyone else.
Officer?
What were you telling her about?
Nothing much.
What's wrong?
You look so serious.
Just doing my job to
keep the streets safe.
You never know what
these Gypsies are scheming.
I could say the same for you
and your friends at the beer hall.
You're scheming about
something every day.
Please, Hughes.
She's a vulnerable girl.
Can't you keep her safe?
It was a betrayal.
Germany still had a real
chance to win the war.
Yet the government just gave
up, stabbing us in the back.
And then the Treaty of
Versailles was a total humiliation.
There are a lot of people who think we should
overthrow the government and take back Germany's pride.
Tell me, Alphonse, do you happen to work
for the people who think those sorts of things?
I just want to build
rockets, nothing more.
So where's Ed?
Did he say something
about going to the university?
Yes.
He's looking for someone.
It's exactly like
Michi's Superman.
Professor Haushofer's
lectures are all canceled.
He's at his villa, I think.
Rumor has it he's too busy
with the Thule Society now.
Thule Society?
Yeah, you haven't heard of it?
Thule's a mystical island in the north
that was written about in ancient mythology.
The Thule Society wants to
harness the power of the gods who
dwell on the island, and reclaim
the destiny of the Aryan race.
Ancient gods?
The occult?
How are they going to save
their country with a myth?
Dammit, there sure are a lot of
guards in the professor's place.
Those rockets?
Don't tell me these are
Alphonse's sponsors?
Looks like some kind
of sorcery diagram.
Probably for sacrificing virgins and
summoning demons from inside the Earth.
These guys are hopeless.
Hold on.
That's no spell.
It's Alchemy.
But why?
Alchemy's not supposed to
work on this side of the gate.
But the circle's not done.
It's worn down.
What am I doing this for?
Finished or not, it
won't make a difference.
Guess I'm just a
sucker for nostalgia.
Still just a puppet,
aren't you, pipsqueak?
Envy!
Shamballa.
What's going on here?
I didn't do any of this!
Go!
What the hell?
Don't move!
Why did the portal reopen now?
We've never been able to do it
twice, no matter what we tried!
They've come back to us.
From Shamballa.
What did you say?
We'll ask the questions.
What have you done?
Check them out.
See if they're okay.
He's been crushed.
This man is dead too, sir.
Any survivors?
My god... Is this
your doing, boy?
In the Hollow Earth lies a
vast underground kingdom.
Far greater than any civilization the
surface has known in modern times.
A utopia without war or
illness, suffering or hate.
The wisdom of its inhabitants
promises absolute peace.
While the mystical power of its army
guarantees victory in mankind's final war.
The road to
Shamballa is difficult.
It seems your hypothesis
was correct, Professor.
A lucky guess, Chairman.
This is the boy I
was telling you about.
Hello, Edward Elric.
Your father was once part of
our society and still helps today.
I don't know where he is
or what he told you, lady.
My name is Delinda
Eckhart, thank you.
Thule Island.
Kingdom of Shamballa.
You people seem to be obsessed
with any world but this one.
Guess we have that in common.
Stop it, Hess.
His plans for
Germany are in motion.
What if this boy tells
our secrets to Berlin?
We might need him!
Brother?
Brother!
Oh, brother, I'm
so glad to see you.
It's been so long.
Are you okay?
I can't breathe!
But you've changed.
You're taller now.
Al
What, you thought I'd still be
a runt when I'm 18 years old?
The Suit's empty.
But how is that possible?
I don't know.
It could be some form
of Alchemy, perhaps.
Don't you see?
It's possessed by a demon!
Fire!
They don't seem too happy.
You haven't changed, brother.
You're still causing trouble.
Save the lecture.
Let's get out of here, right.
Now what?
Just go!
Which way?
Anywhere!
I don't know where I'm going!
Better than getting shot!
I'm sorry, ma'am.
He's escaped, but we
know where to find him.
He's been living with
Alphonse Heiderich.
His knowledge of Alchemy
could be our answer.
But I doubt that he'll
willingly cooperate with us.
He's just like his father.
Then why don't we
use the Gypsy, ma'am?
That girl?
Yes.
We've received a tip from
one of our loyal party members.
The girl's living with Edward and
Alphonse, too, now, as luck would have it.
It's not luck.
The gods of the Aryan race
are lighting a path for us.
You're actually planning
on going through with this?
There's no evidence to confirm it's
Shamballa on the other side of that portal!
You saw what the
trip did to our men!
November 8th is only
ten days away, sir.
The Führer plans to make his move
with or without the Thule Society.
Our role in the
party hinges on this.
Relax, Lieutenant.
The portal will be
opened on that day.
The Thule Society led
the world into a new age.
That's what the future
generations will say.
What's with you, Al?
You finally come back
home and all you do is sleep?
Brother...
I've dreamed of this place.
It's pretty.
Are we really in the gate?
No.
We're on the other side of it.
But forget that.
I want to hear
about your life, Al.
That is really you, right?
How did you get stuck
in that armor again?
Again?
What do you mean?
Oh, right.
You attached my soul to
armor just like this, didn't you?
While my body
was lost in the gate.
Sorry, brother.
I don't remember any of that.
You don't remember?
What?
The last time I saw you was the
day we tried to bring Mom back.
Then I woke up
and I was in Central.
And a girl named Rose
was taking me home.
But as confused as I was, I knew
you were alive out there, somewhere.
And one day, we'd
be together again.
And now?
I wonder how they
opened that portal.
Will they do it again?
Al?
Brother, the transmutation I used to
transfer my soul, it doesn't last for long.
It looks like I've
run out of time.
Al, don't go yet.
It's too soon.
It's okay.
I think I know how to
bring you back now.
That portal they used.
I'll try to open it
from my side, too.
Al!
You're awfully late.
What's with the smirk?
Something good happen?
Yeah, actually.
You're probably not
gonna believe this.
But I saw him tonight.
I saw my brother Al.
And there's a chance I'll be
able to leave this world after all.
Hello?
Mabuse, what's going on?
Mabuse?
I understand you've been sniffing
around General Haushofer's place.
What?
You part of their club?
There's something I'd
like to talk to you about.
Meet me at Ufa, in Berlin.
Hey, Alphonse.
Have you ever heard of Ufa?
Sure.
You'll excuse me for
not keeping in touch.
I'm sorry.
I realize I'm in no
position to call you.
No, it's fine.
But Al isn't here.
Really?
He was for a while.
But he's disappeared.
He and Wrath both.
I see.
They've probably
gone to Central, then.
Huh?
Lior and Central, experiencing the
same phenomenon at the exact same time.
There's one thing they share.
And it's a pretty safe bet Al
arrived at the same conclusion I did.
Does this have anything to do with Ed's
disappearance and Al trying to bring him back?
I've said all I can for now.
Winry, can't you wait here for him
to come back like we always have?
I'm sorry, but not this time.
He's looking for Ed.
And I can't let
him do that alone.
Okay, now it makes sense.
Considering the work it took to rig this, I
can see why you wanted to film the real thing.
Still, I can't complain.
Just seeing it helped me make
the fake one a great deal better.
Dr. Mabuse.
Mabuse the gambler.
I understand that's
a film you made.
Just having a
little fun with you.
Call me Fritz
Lang if you prefer.
I'm toying with the idea of leaving this
country and moving to America for a while.
I've been reading American novels and
publications to sort of get myself in the mood.
They have a great deal of science
fiction or scientific romance, as some call it.
And there's an idea in a recent
book that Wrather caught my eye.
They call it a parallel world, an
entire planet existing side by side
with ours, separate yet
connected by some invisible force.
They might share similarities of history and
people, but with some fundamental difference.
Maybe it's a realm where
magic and dragons do exist.
Or I don't know, maybe where Alchemy triumphed
over physics and paved the whole world in gold.
And maybe, given those
rules, Fritz Lang isn't a director.
Maybe he's a criminal walking
around with the same face as mine.
Or for that matter,
maybe he's a woman.
Imagine, it's fun to
think about it, isn't it?
Any place like that would
just feel like a fantasy.
You think so?
But then how would you know which
world is make-believe and which one is real?
Believe me, you just would.
You'll never know what it's like
spending your whole life in a dream.
So what did you want to discuss?
The Major General
Karl Haushofer's book.
I met him in the Empire
of Japan before the war.
While he was doing his research.
His thesis is that the island has success
because it was made up entirely of a single race.
Germany, meanwhile,
is disjointed.
Its people are spread far
beyond its own borders.
Scattered throughout Poland, Austria,
and many other countries across Europe.
Haushofer believes those nations
should be unified and then distilled.
Creating a homeland
for the true German race.
Sorry, I think I'll pass.
Hold on, Ed.
There's more.
Haushofer also writes
about a utopia, Shamballa.
It's a legend in the Orient, and it's said
that those who rule it can rule the world.
This society of
his believes that.
And what do you believe?
Do you know what
this device is, Ed?
What?
Not long ago, the Thule Society helped form
the National Socialist Workers' Party in Germany.
Which still serves an
active role in their ranks.
Playing in the name of rival
socialists, they're called Nazis for short.
Nazis?
The party is supposedly planning a
large-scale uprising sometime in November.
The consensus in important circles is
that they don't have enough supporters,
and that Berlin's forces
will quickly put them down.
The Thule Society,
however, disagrees.
They have guaranteed victory to
their leader, who they call the Führer.
And as proof of their claim, that
picture is what they showed him.
They say it's a bomb.
A bomb of devastating power.
They also say it relies on a scientific
principle never before conceived in this world.
Haushofer and the others claim that if
they're given enough funding and power,
they'll be able to bring weapons of this magnitude one after
another through the portal, creating an unstoppable force.
They want to use the other
world for their uprising?
What are you planning now?
I can't let them do that!
I have to close
that gate for good!
Let them be.
If they want a war, you can't
do anything to stop them.
I just told you as a warning, so
you'd know to keep your distance.
You should come to
work for me instead.
Hold on, how do you know so
much about these Nazis anyway?
This Führer, Adolf Hitler, is a charismatic
man, and my wife has become a fanatical believer.
Through her, the Nazis have asked me to
work with them many times, but I'm no fool.
I'm one of the Jews they want to get
rid of, and after they exploited my talents,
they cast me aside.
So I cast them off first.
Reality is just a knotted
mess I choose to avoid.
You act like you're too good for the
world, but really you're just afraid of the risk!
Just trying to avoid being
forced out of your dream!
Wait... where are you taking me?
What we're offering isn't
nearly as bad as you think, Noah.
Just hear us out.
The Führer plans to use
the stormtroopers on the 8th.
Goering's men?
You're saying we won't be
involved in the uprising now?
On the day they make their move,
we'll open the path to Shamballa.
That's perfect!
We already have
the Gypsy persuaded.
I'll speed up the plans.
They've set our launch
date for November 8th.
And Hess told me it's crucial
that we're ready on time.
So, let's make Germany proud.
Let's show them
we're not beaten yet.
Isn't that what you said?
If the portal opens,
you can go home, right?
And that's what you want?
Not at that cost.
Those zealots would follow me
and drag my world into their war.
But...
I'm positive now that
Al's alive on the other side.
I never knew that for sure.
I was afraid my
survival meant I failed.
So now, knowing
that, I can bear it.
Alphonse, I need to talk to you.
These people, your
sponsors, they're bad news.
You need to stop
building their rockets.
Our work's in the final stage.
I'll be sleeping
at the factory now.
Wait!
Your sponsors
are plotting a war!
They're gonna start
by invading my world.
And those rockets must
have something to do with it!
Listen to me!
The truth is
I'm running out of time.
You say this world's not yours?
Well, it is mine, and I want
to leave proof that I lived in it!
It's a bit late for you
to start caring now!
Alphonse!
They don't know how to
open the portal anyway.
Right.
So you're not even sure
if Al's in Central or not?
That's why I'm worried.
I only think Wrath is with them because
they disappeared at the same time.
Izumi's death seems to have
been a relief for Al in a way.
Like he's free to
concentrate on finding Ed.
Don't worry, Winry.
I'll show you the underground
city as soon as we're finished here.
Huh.
I guess Elicia and
her mom came by.
So, why did you lead me
all the way here, Wrath?
Guess I'll find out soon enough.
It's just like the one in Lior!
I'm so hungry.
I hope they have some of
those white sausages left.
No beer for you tonight, guys?
That's a first.
I think you better stay
indoors tonight, kid.
By morning, this nation
will be completely reborn.
That's why we're
here celebrating.
Careful, Noah.
That guy's with Thule.
Hold on, Noah.
Noah!
What are you d-Listen, Hughes.
This is no time for a lecture.
You may not realize it, but that man
there is-We're on the Eve of a war, Edward.
That spineless regime in
Berlin will be overthrown.
And the Führer will lead
this nation to greatness.
Noah is helping us get there.
Or didn't you realize?
Every man in here is a member of the
same group fighting for a stronger country.
The National Socialist
Workers' Party.
Let go of me!
Come on, get in!
Hey!
You do want to go to
Haushofer's villa, correct?
Yeah.
Why are you helping me?
Who knows?
Maybe I'm just trying to avoid
being forced out of my dream.
We're ready for test flights.
We'll just need some
kind of transport.
Sorry, Alphonse.
I thought I'd made it clear.
We don't have to move
the rockets to test them.
You mean you're actually intending
to launch from inside this factory?
Noah?
Yes.
She's the Gypsy psychic we've
been looking for all this time.
It's a blessing for us that you
kept her in Munich, Alphonse.
Why is she here?
She's the key that will open
the great door... to Shamballa.
I had no idea you
could create it so quickly.
You're sure that's what you saw... when
you were inside Edward Elbrick's mind?
So everything Ed knows
about Alchemy, you now know?
Yes.
Right.
The magic?
No.
The transmutation circle.
Isn't that their phrase?
Is there some incantation?
No.
There were no
spells in his mind.
The alchemists must circulate energy
between themselves and the circle.
It seems we have a visitor knocking
on the other side of Shamballa's door.
It's been a long time since we've
gone sneaking around like this.
Are you sure this
leads to the old
Führer's office...
It failed.
There's something missing.
What is it?
I did see the gate on that day.
If this one works the same way, then
the equivalent exchange to make it open.
..
It has to be...
Gluttony?
He's one of the seven like me.
A monster!
Tonight, November 8th, in the Beer
Hall, where the able men of Bavaria gather.
The leader of Germany's National Socialist Workers'
Party, our Führer Adolf Hitler, will stand before them.
He will urge the
state militia to rise up.
From there, they will march on
Berlin and take control of the state.
We have to act now and
open the road to Shambhala.
We have to supply the Führer
with the arsenal that we promised.
We're not even sure if
we can survive the trip.
Then it's time to find out.
Elric's knowledge
was not enough.
She can't open the door.
What was that?
Think you can fly this thing?
More or less.
I guess we don't have
to go pick him up now.
And here he is, dropped
from the heavens.
Seems we can't
do this without you.
You mean using Noah
as my stand-in didn't work?
How could you?
But it's your world on the other
side, isn't that right, Edward?
Well, it's not Shambhala.
I can promise you that.
I want to see it!
No, I want to go there
and never come back!
Isn't that the only place
where I can belong?
Another world where
people won't hate
and distrust me!
I thought the Roma
were proud of their ways.
Constant travelers who valued the
tribe and had no need for a homeland.
But I want something more!
I've always dreamt of it!
Trust me, Noah.
What lies ahead for
us now... it's no dream.
Do it...
You'll transmute us both.
Then the gate will open...
...to take us back... Of course.
The gate always opened up when
a Homunculus was brought to life.
Those who came through the gate
can be material to open it, that's right.
That's right... That's
why I came with you.
I know you're planning to offer your
own life as the price for saving your brother.
I don't ever want
to see that happen.
Never again!
But wait!
You don't mean
you want to... Please.
I just want to go home.
Where mommy is.
Now!!!
I wouldn't do that.
Dad...
How did he get here?
What's going on?
We found this was the most effective approach
for keeping the Great Serpent calm and quiet.
Luckily for us, your
father doesn't die so easily.
Hey.
There you are.
About time.
How, dad?
How did they get you?
Easily.
I wanted to create a
portal between our worlds.
By using the science and magic
they study on this side of the gate.
Haushofer made me a proposal.
I'm getting you down!
Son, no!
This is what I wanted.
I'm a sinner, Ed.
I failed to bring
my son back to life.
Instead, I turned him into a
monster and abandoned him.
I took the lives of countless
people to save myself.
And couldn't stop this
beast from hurting you.
So what?
How are those reasons
for helping them?
You're trying to get me home.
I'll offer my life as the price, then
transmute envy to create the portal.
Forget the portal!
I don't need to go back!
Give Al my regards.
Why?!
Prepare the Rockets
We're going through!
Really?
You're the lucky one, Ed.
SHH.
What is this?
I've set everything up
so you can go back home.
You can take this second
rocket while Eckhart isn't looking.
You ready?
Lieutenant, inform the
Führer of our situation.
Professor, is the
portal stabilized now?
Seems to be.
But that's not the point.
I don't believe it's Shamballa.
I think that Ed's right.
Yes, I realize that.
Right in the fake arm.
Good thing she's a bad shot.
Our rockets peak at over
two kilometers a second.
Should be enough speed to punch
through the pressure and get out safe.
That's Haushofer's
theory, anyway.
This one-seater shouldn't
have any problem.
Wait a minute!
I never said I wanted to go!
I'm not giving you a choice, Ed.
Because I'm in the way.
You're trying to get rid of me.
We're real, Edward.
We're not just part of your
dreams like you thought.
I care.
And I make mistakes.
I may not live much
longer, but I'll still be here.
Just don't forget me.
Alphonse!
Alphonse wait!!
Alphonse!!!!!!
Damn it!
What!
Edward!
I'm sorry.
Take me with you, Edward!
Please!
NOOOOOOOOOOOOOOO!!!!!!!
What is that?
Could it be?
This power?
The magic I've learned.
Now it's real.
Where are we?
I'm not really sure.
I'm just glad we're still alive.
So now do you
believe in space aliens?
Don't start that again.
Winry!
Al.
What are they?
I don't know.
All I did was open up the gate.
What?
Huh?
landing still needs some work.
Edward.
I was wondering when you'd show.
Winry.
Welcome home.
Thanks.
Brother!
Shaska.
Al.
I knew I'd see you again.
Yeah.
What is that, brother?
It's a rocket-powered airship.
And it's armed.
They came to conquer this world.
And use any power they can
take from us to fuel their own war.
It's my fault.
So you're the one.
You made the gate on this side.
Al!
Same old Ed.
Home for five minutes and
you're off on another mission.
But you can't go into battle
with that arm and leg, can you?
Huh?
You've been lugging those
around this whole time?
They're great.
But I'm not so
sure they'll fit me.
I've grown, you know.
Who do you think
you're dealing with here?
Who are these bastards?
Dammit!
Behold, my beautiful
artistic Alchemy!
Major!
Major Armstrong.
Who are they?
They look like the same
ones that were in Lior.
But something's changed.
Officers, look!
Behind you!
He's back.
Haha, welcomme
to the party General.
Warrant Officer Fallman.
Take a squad and
defend the assembly hall.
Sir!
Sergeant Fury, inform
the mechanized division.
We need a tank unit in Central.
Now!
Crush their ranks.
Go!
Yes, sir!
You know, he gives a lot of
orders for an enlisted man.
Lieutenants Havok and Breda.
Sir!
The command center's
our last stronghold.
Tell the generals to stop wasting time
and order all their divisions to come defend it.
Right!
Major Armstrong.
You know, if we're
gonna get to that aircraft...
Then we'll need a way to fly.
Got it.
We've been waiting for you, sir.
Okay.
Try standing up.
You know, sometimes I think
you enjoy causing me pain.
Perfect!
Considering all the guesswork, I'd
say I did an okay job, don't you think?
More ships coming through.
Hide somewhere!
It appears we've emerged
in the capital city of this land.
Now I'll destroy it!
More ships.
What!
Elric!
No!
Al!
Hey.
I'm surprised you found
your way to the surface.
It was Wrath.
He showed me all the
ways out beforehand.
Wrath?
That's right.
I made that permanent
gate by transmuting him.
Al..
NO!
You can't bring
back the dead Al.
trying just causes more pain.
Brother...
Is all of this... my fault?
Why is it all turning
out this way?
I just... I wanted... I know.
You were just trying to
bring me back home again, Al.
For whatever reason,
Wrath wanted to help.
That sacrifice was his choice.
The other Al wanted
to get me home, too.
I feel like he did
something meaningful.
And Noah wanted
a place to belong.
We all had our excuses,
and they seemed right to us.
And no one thought it would
lead to suffering like this.
I know that.
None of us were
looking to start a war.
But still... a war is what we got,
and so all of us take the blame.
Do you understand?
That's why... we
have to make it right.
And defend this world...
as long as we're alive.
We can't keep living like our
own dreams are all that matter.
Okay.
How's it coming?
This is the best we could
manage, given what we had.
It's good enough.
Stop! What are you doing?!
Easy now.
Sorry, Lieutenant.
Only room for one.
You liar!
Come back!
Over there!
What is that?
It's Ed.
All this time, you
haven't lost your touch.
Give me a little credit Al.
If you're gonna strike,
do it now, Fullmetal.
General!
Way to bring your trouble
home with you, Fullmetal.
Really nice.
Smart remarks already.
Nice patch, by the way.
Though it should have
covered your mouth, too.
Sorry, sir.
Ignore it.
Now go, Fullmetal.
I'll guard the entrance.
That's why I came.
You don't have to tell me twice.
Hold on, brother.
Wait for me.
I always knew you were alive.
What's wrong?
Why is my magic being blocked?
This land is completely foreign.
Not like my world at all.
You're wrong
about that, Eckhart.
People here laugh and weep, just
like you, live the same, die the same.
There's one thing
I want to know.
What made you start this attack?
I thought the point was to use weapons
of this world to conquer your own.
So why would you wage war here?
I have to.
This entire world must perish.
But why?
Because I fear it.
Opening a door to a new
world was thrilling at first.
A utopia that could
make us greater.
But then I realized how
different it was from our own.
I got scared.
This world is far too
strong to be trusted.
I have to destroy it
now, before it conquer
That's ridiculous, this world doesn't
have any reason to conquer yours
How can you know that?
Because we're
humans just like you.
Liar!
You may wear the same skin
as us, but inside you're different.
You're monsters!
Now i understand
the person you are!
Let's end this.
It's human nature.
We can't accept what
we don't see in ourselves.
We fear it.
Reject it.
And that is the
beginning of war.
When I look at
you, I see a beast.
That is why I
can take your life.
Kill him!
What?
Alchemy can give
us all sorts of abilities.
This is one of mine.
Don't touch me!
What are you doing?
Get away!
Get away!!!!!
I get the feeling
that it's over.
Yeah.
So what now?
Brother?
Brother!
What are you doing?
That should be enough Alchemic
material to get yourselves down.
What about you?
Where will you go?
I'm gonna take what's left of
these soldiers back to their world.
Why?
You don't have to go with them!
I have to break the
gate on their side.
I need you to stay here and destroy it on this
side too, so the portal can never be opened again.
What about Wenry?
Don't you know
she misses you, too?
Tell her thanks.
She always made the best of me.
Wait!
Brother, no!
I just got you back!
You can't go again!
That's Ed.
I know it.
So, I guess it's
goodbye for good.
The uprising failed!
Munich Command
figured out our plan.
And with the help of the
police, they blocked our march.
The other demonstrators were beaten
back along the way, keeping us divided.
And did the Führer get away?
We really were too late.
Open it again.
The doorway!
Do it now!
I must destroy it.
Sham.........balla
Edward.
Noah...
That's right.
After all that
trouble, I'm still here.
Surprised?
But why?
Why would you come
back to our world, Ed?
It's hard to explain.
He came to destroy the gate.
So you transferred
your soul again, huh, Al?
How long till you
fade out this time?
Al!
What are you doing here?
I jumped onto your ship
at the last minute, brother.
Then I hid inside this armor,
so you wouldn't find me.
General Mustang should be breaking
down the gate on the other side right now.
And we're going to
destroy it on this side, right?
But you won't be
able to go home, Al.
I want to be at
your side, brother.
No matter what.
I want to see the same things.
And learn what you learn.
And keep on journeying together.
Like those years we
were looking for the stone.
Despite all the hardships.
Those were the
best times we had.
Al, are you telling me
your memory's back?
Mm-hmm.
When I left our
own world, I think.
Equivalent exchange, huh?
Destroying that gate's gonna
be a challenge without Alchemy.
Between the two of
us, we'll figure it out.
Motion pictures
and weapons of war.
Science has created them both.
So while others point their
guns, I'll have my camera.
Offering fantastic dreams of
other worlds just beyond our reach.
So, where are we
headed now, brother?
First we have to track down that uranium
bomb that was brought over from the other side.
A weapon like that shouldn't
exist, no matter which world it's in.
People are saying another
great war is inevitable here.
And from everything that's
going on, maybe they're right.
Are you sure we should
get involved in their battles?
Like I said, Al, we can't keep thinking we're all
that matter, that the world has nothing to do with us.
That goes for both
sides of the gate.
This is where we live.
It's home now.
And we have to do our part.