Kimbley!!!!!!!!!!!
Hello.
Well, what is this?
This is where you pay for
what you did to my friends.
Kimbley, what are
you doing here?
That's a pretty ridiculous question,
considering I am a State Alchemist again.
You ratted us all out,
you piece of garbage.
Now you have to pay.
Come on, Alphonse.
You're not going to
let her kill me, are you?
Marta, stop killing him
wont solve anything!
Let go!
Tell me, soldier.
Marta: You dont understand!
Are you ready to carry out your patriotic duty?
I have to!
Hey, what are you doing to him?
I'm only doing
what's necessary, kid.
This soldier here knows
it's nothing personal.
Marta!
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Just when I thought I was going to
get to finish my day off with a bang...
You had to go and ruin it.
Leave Marta alone,
or you'll regret it.
By Marta, do you
mean this reptile?
She's a human being!
That's not what I heard.
I heard that she's a chimera.
Hardly considered
a living being.
Kinda like you, kid.
Get away!
Get away from her!
I won't let you hurt her!
Alphonse...
Thanks for giving me the
components I need, genius.
Get out of here!
You devious bastard.
Colonel?
Both of the Elric brothers fall
under my direct command, Kimbley.
Understood?
If you have a complaint against Al,
then I suggest you put it in writing.
I've already filled the form.
Sure Mustang, just keep
that scrap heap away from me.
You're going to the front lines?
I can't very well let Lior
become another Ishbal.
We must end this as quickly
and quietly as possible.
Yes, of course, sir.
You'll have to act as
Lieutenant Führer in my absence.
You're seriously
ready to do that, sir?
Do you accept?
Yes.
Lieutenant Führer!
I finally made it!
This is so gr...
Oh, and send some flowers and nice
chocolates to my wife for me, will you?
She gets lonely when I'm gone.
I'm counting on you.
Sir!
It appears that another city must be
annihilated for the sake of the Philosopher's Stone.
If you've come all this way to find me, then you
must have some knowledge of what I'm planning.
Yeah.
There's a rumor that you're trying to do something
really stupid, like create the Philosopher's Stone.
You shouldn't interfere.
Now this is interesting.
There's something important that
I've been meaning to ask you, Scar.
Four years ago, there
was a Chimera in Central.
Part human, part dog.
I returned their
souls to Ishbala.
You killed a little girl!
Out of mercy.
What else could you
have done for her?
Those are not the kind of decisions
that we're allowed to make, dammit!
Anything else you'd
like to say now?
With that kind of messed up logic, you probably
think it's okay to sacrifice Rose and her people, too!
And how is it that
you know about Rose?
Does that make me a threat?
What is this?
You don't get what's going on?
You're not much of
an Alchemist, are you?
This arm does Alchemy, not me.
Not true!
Alchemy is understanding a composition,
breaking it down, then remaking it as something else.
You've been instinctively figuring out your enemy's
design, then adjusting that arm's Alchemy to destroy them.
But if you don't know what that
substance is, you can't break it down.
So I've been transmuting my automail
into other metals to keep you guessing.
Now I understand.
But I can't keep doing this forever,
because these other metals have some
different physical properties and
it's screwing up the entire design.
So I'm gonna have
to make this quick!
You idiot!
What makes you think you can
sacrifice an entire city for your cause?
You have no right to play God
with these innocent people like that!
Have you forgotten, Edward?
I can destroy
human flesh as well.
Great, the Homunculi.
Please, feel free
to call me Lust.
And I'm Gluttony.
Do you understand why we've
told you our names, Metal Boy?
Yeah, you've told me.
Now you have to kill me, right?
Oh yes, that burned.
You can't get rid
of us that easily, kid.
We're not weaklings like Greed.
Relax, Ishbalan.
We're just trying to help you.
Or shall I call you Scar?
I don't need help
from the likes of you.
If you can make the Philosopher's Stone like you
claim, we're going to help you whether you like it or not.
And Blondie here'd
best accept that too.
Does this locket
mean anything to you?
You gave it to my brother.
Please, I don't know
what you're talking about.
You know more than you think!
What is it, Lust?
What's wrong?
I hate you!
I hate you for hurting my Lust!
What exactly do you know
about that Homunculus?
That is none of your concern.
Wait!
Rose?
Lyra?
Come now, Scar.
Perhaps you should tell Edward
how you know that strange woman.
Yes, I think that's what
Rose is wanting to say.
You mean... you mean
she's a mute now?
I want you to keep this.
So you have something
to remember me by.
When I was a boy, and my home was
still blessed with peace, my beloved older
brother was in love with a young
woman, the most beautiful I had ever seen.
They had plans to marry.
But as fate would have it, she fell ill with a fatal
disease, and was all too soon given to the god of Ishbal.
Brother, you've been
sitting there for days.
What do you keep looking for?
It's called the Grand Arcanum.
It's our people's ancient
method of recreation.
But the Grand Arcanum
is forbidden by Ishbala.
You know that!
It's just another form of alchemy
like those devils practice in Central.
Listen.
According to this, there's a way to
bring someone back from the dead.
Oh, I see.
So that's how it works.
Brother, open this door!
Talk to me!
In his attempt to bring her back, my brother
committed heresy, defying the teachings of Ishbal.
But even after he gave his
own flesh, she did not return.
Afterwards, he was exiled for studying
the forbidden knowledge, the great sin.
But through all of that misery,
did he succeed after all?
That strange woman
who calls herself lust.
All these Homunculi we've been
fighting, do you know how they're created?
They're born when an Alchemist
tries to pull off a human transmutation.
And they take on the likeness of
the person that you tried to bring back.
I remember Dante telling me
the same thing once, actually.
She said she failed a human transmutation years back,
and it made a dangerous creature I should watch out for.
Yeah, that makes a lot of sense.
She must have meant greed.
But their creation alone
doesn't
explain how they're so powerful,
or how they know so much.
Somebody must be gathering them up, and
teaching them, and making them stronger somehow.
Hold on, you're saying
my brother created lust?
Don't get any ideas, Scar.
She's just a monster who
looks like the woman you knew.
She doesn't have a soul.
Lust doesn't hate this
for sentimental reasons.
Homunculi exist as a balancing act,
filling in for the absence of the human,
and so confronting the
real thing makes them weak.
She's a fake.
Remember that.
Soon after my brother was banished,
we were invaded by an unseen force.
The state claimed
innocence, but we knew better.
We retaliated, and the
long, terrible war began.
We had no chance.
In my travels, I have discovered
how to create a Philosopher's Stone.
No, brother.
We can't be afraid of it.
With its power, I could save
Ishbal from her invaders.
Our people were desperate.
No one objected to his
return, blasphemous or not.
But just before completing it,
my brother abandoned his attempt.
His mind apparently shattered.
Knowing what I do
now, I understand why.
I went to Kishua too, Scar.
I talked to the Exile.
He told me about the method.
The Grand Arcanum Stone takes
an even greater human sacrifice.
It's true.
A major city would have to be turned to an open grave, or
an entire race of people wiped from the face of the planet.
All those souls, displaced, angry,
still crying in sorrow at their loss,
are pulled into the Array, and
form the Philosopher's Stone.
In a cruel paradox, the Philosopher's
Stone was the only way to save Ishbal.
And yet, it would take the genocide
of its entire people to create it.
You have to ask yourself, how does one
State Alchemist get all the fun jobs in this war?
Can't you see that
we've given up?
Leave us alone, please!
My wife and children
are murdered!
You've driven us
from our homeland!
Isn't that enough?
Don't blabber to me, old man.
I'm just following my orders.
To take every meaningless life of your
meaningless people with your curious red
eyes and your brown skin.
But why?
Why not?
No!!!!!!!!!
All you people
just need to relax.
You're all going to die someday.
It might as well be at
the hands of a specialist.
Why don't we go piece by piece?
First, your face.
Pretty.
Now what say we lose that arm?
Now what should I take next?
Wow.
Those markings look
like a transmutation circle.
Who would have thought there'd
be a little Alchemist in Ishbal?
Well, too bad you don't have one of
these, darlings, or I might be scared.
Dead, you Colonel.
What?
Brother, what did you do?
The souls of our people who were
in me, I've given them all to you now.
No!
Why would you do that?
Because their lives have power.
That arm is strong.
It heals and sustains you.
Without it, you would have died.
What...what about you?
Like you've said, I've
committed the unforgivable.
Be honest.
You were in love with
her too, weren't you?
Sorry.
You probably deserve her more.
But I'm going to see her first.
Your brother turned his body into a transmutation
circle to make the Philosopher's Stone inside him.
He was taking in the souls of
all the Ishbalans dying in the war.
And that's why your arm
can deconstruct things.
That's correct, because
it's part of the transmutation.
It's looking for ingredients,
souls, for the stone.
And that's why it reacts with the
stone fragments Marcoh made.
It senses the lives
inside and sucks them in.
But it hasn't been enough.
In order to complete
it, I still need more lives.
You think that gives you
the right to use Rose as some
charismatic puppet while you
sacrifice her people for your stone?
Calm down.
You've misunderstood
his tactics.
Scar isn't going to
kill anyone from Lior.
Tell me, Lyra, what the hell
are you doing here anyway?
After Dante was murdered,
I didn't know what to do.
I went searching for a place where
I could do some good with Alchemy.
Here, I learned about Scar
and his plans for justice.
You don't have to worry, Ed.
Right before the attack, the people will escape
through a secret passage below the church.
When the military invades,
Scar will activate the array.
Soldiers have
lives just like us.
I don't care what you
think of the Military.
They're still...
You have no idea what the soldiers
have done to the people of Lior.
Like what?
What'd they do to Rose?
A group of them
carried her to their base.
Whatever they did to her there was traumatic
enough that she couldn't speak when she returned.
My sympathy will not
be spent on Soldiers.
Neither should yours.
Marta, where'd you go?
I'm worried about my brother.
I need to help him.
Havoc!
What's going on?
Are we going to war?
Sorry kid, I'm really not sure.
I've just heard that the
Führer has shown up.
So, the Führer himself
has come to see me.
I'm flattered.
I have an assignment
for you, Kimbley.
A secret one.
I want you to take Dr. Tucker's
chimeras and make your way into Lior.
Don't be spotted.
Oh, I get it.
I caused just enough trouble that
the rebels retaliate against the military,
then we can claim
they started it.
Brilliant.
But I designed these chimeras
to defend us, not attack.
Preemption is a difficult
concept for people to understand.
We'll be able to explain the
matter better if they attack first.
Also, I'm told a State Alchemist has
already gone into Lior and did not return.
Yes, Edward Elric.
I have no doubt those
zealots have killed him.
Make certain you
bring back his corpse.
Of course.
An even better reason for war.
People love a martyr.
Trust me, if he's not
dead yet, he will be soon.
It really is a shame.
So it all starts again, does it?
False wars, murdered soldiers.
Well, I won't let you do
it, and you won't kill Ed.
Call off your orders or else.
Your agile moves won't work
against me, Snake Chimera.
I have the ultimate eye.
The Elrics.
I have to tell them.
Al!
Marta?
Listen carefully.
I don't have much time.
Here, get in.
You've got to tell Ed.
I hope she didn't cause
you harm, Alphonse.
But now the fugitive Chimera has been
executed, and I thank you for your help.
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 41,
Holy Mother.
I can hear it.
That voice.
It should have been lost
to the crimes of the past.
But now, it could save my life.