This group of Ishbalans,
they're just refugees, right?
They haven't done anything.
If Scar is there with them, then
they're guilty of harboring a fugitive.
That's treason.
But still, don't you think we're
going a little overboard here?
You criticizing the orders
of a superior officer?
No, of course not!
I was just...
Our objective is to
locate and capture Scar.
Most likely we should have no
resistance from the Ishbalans.
But sir, what will
happen if they do resist?
I read a report before
we were stationed here.
It said some Ishbalan refugees had been
assaulted by ruffians claiming to be Military.
These people may
not trust us right now.
Those markings on your arm...
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is Alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
You... Zolf J. Kimbley
But you should be dead.
Zolf Kimbley?
The Crimson Alchemist?
He's a State Alchemist?
You were supposed to
be executed years ago.
Charged with disobeying the
Military's direct orders in Ishbal.
Well, that's one
way of putting it.
Another would be that I made
women and children go boom.
And then when my superior
officers tried to stop me... Boom!
I was really looking forward to an
execution, but then for some strange reason.
the powers that be
decided to keep me alive.
But why?
I'm not sure.
Perhaps that gentleman there
behind you has the answer.
How should I know?
Are you just going to stand
there allowing this chaos to go on?
You heard him!
Arrest them!
Arrest every one of them!
Sir!
Teacher, we've...
There's no point
in trying to stop me!
Please, teacher, wait a minute.
Nice work, Al.
Amazing!
Definitely Homunculus.
And that means
he's coming with me.
Think again!
The girl's amazing, too!
An impressive transmutation.
However, those who would
try to harm the Führer...
Shall be defeated in the most
beautiful and graceful way!
You should give me more credit.
I'm used to dealing
with muscles like yours.
Only more beautiful
and graceful.
Brother, we've got to stop them now
before the whole building collapses!
This whole damn
city could collapse!
Brother!
My, my.
Don't you have
an interesting body.
He made an
explosion out of thin air!
I heard of something
like this once.
It's a skill that transmutes materials in
a body into a gunpowder-like substance.
Then it's compressed rapidly
to cause a huge explosion.
Why are you bothering us?
What do you want here?
We've come here for the child.
Our boss has an interest in him.
He'd also like to have a
word with the two of you.
It seems there's some
business to discuss.
Oh, is that so?
Wait a second!
You aren't trying to turn
me into a bomb, are you?
Oh yeah, sure.
Bad idea!
I'll show you what I can do!
Did the Fullmetal One say your
arm and leg belonged to him?
Y-yes.
Well, maybe that explains how you were able to come
through the gate and survive all this time on your own.
Gate?
Gate!
I... Easy.
You don't have to be
alone any longer, little one.
Now, eat up.
Come on.
Yes, savor the taste
as it covers your tongue.
And be gracious.
Hundreds of human lives
went into their making.
Human lives?
What's wrong?
I thought you liked them.
Oh well, I guess you won't be
needing the rest of these, or my help.
Run along now.
Get caught, and give
back that arm and leg.
Look at that.
You can even perform alchemy.
It truly is awe-inspiring what a
couple of human limbs can do.
Listen, I was raised
on these stones of life.
I fancy the taste myself.
The reason is
because I'm not human.
I'm a Homunculus.
And since you're enjoying them as
well... that means you're not human either.
We need Greed's
help to handle this!
We can't do it ourselves!
Greed!
The hell with it.
It'd be easier if I just
blew up this entire building.
Hello, I'm Lieutenant
Colonel Frank Archer.
It's nice to meet the
famous Crimson Alchemist.
Yeah, you too.
Well, as Armstrong pointed
out, you should be dead.
By whose authority
were you kept alive?
Was it the Führer, or did Basque
Grand make that decision on his own?
Beats me.
Do you have any intention of
returning to your service in the Military?
I can make it happen,
if you wanted to.
Teacher!
Where are you?
That stupid Chimera
scratched my face pretty deep.
Major Armstrong!
Oh, the agony, the pain!
That woman is most
definitely your teacher.
Even with my elegant
attack, I was defeated.
Thanks for your help, Major.
I kinda had a feeling things
were gonna turn out like this.
You're holding the wrong place.
Hm.
I've got you my little one.
Huh.
Already not the same.
Go on, boy.
And start doing what
you were meant to do.
Brother, it looks
like Teacher is gone.
Damn it.
She's gonna be too weak now.
You escaped from
here with that kid.
What's she trying to do?
You two, go in from the right.
The rest of you... We're
not supposed to be here.
We'd better go.
I can hear Mustang's
smug remarks already.
That can't be right.
Verify that transmission.
What's our status?
Have we received confirmation
that the Führer is safe?
Well, sir, we contacted
headquarters in Central, and they said
that the Führer had no plans
to come south for an inspection.
Not possible.
I saw him with my own eyes.
Did you apprehend the Elric
brothers and that woman?
No, sir.
With all the personnel here, I felt
securing this crumbling building was a
higher priority, so I came back.
Major.
No.
Wherever they go, they have
nowhere to return to besides the Military.
Search the premises for the
Führer again, just to be sure.
Sir!
You gotta know where she is!
Just tell us!
Is Teacher okay?
Please!
We're really worried about her!
She was hurt!
And that kid she's
with is a Homunculus!
There's no telling
what he could do to her!
The place where the human
transmutation happened.
The same place that Izumi lost her
child, and then transmuted its body in a
desperate attempt
to bring it back to life.
How did you find out?
Oh!
I knew it.
I've got this feeling
that she went there.
She's been gone a while.
Teacher would pick
some place isolated.
Somewhere far away from any
city where no one could get hurt.
Yock Island.
That's it, isn't it?
My boy...
What's wrong?
Hurry and get it over with!
If you don't,
then I'll kill you!
Teacher!
Mrs. Izumi!
Get off her!
Teacher!
You bastard!
Don't touch him!
Leave him alone.
But... but we saw him!
He was trying to kill you!
I brought him out here because
I was planning on killing him.
But I... I am the one
who deserves to die.
What do you mean?
Why?
Because, Ed, I
created this child.
I used the remains of my baby and some other
elements and attempted to perform a human transmutation.
But what came back?
Well, you know what
it was, don't you?
Something not... not human.
Look,
I was once again
in front of that gate.
Edward, what did you see
when you looked into it?
Everything.
Everything there is to
know about alchemy, life.
Everything.
I felt like all the knowledge of
the world was pouring into me.
The truth was in there.
The truth?
It looked like hell to me.
And I gave him to it.
That's where I left the child.
So then, there's no way the child you
had is the same boy that's here now.
When I looked at him, I
knew there wasn't any doubt.
If the child from that time had grown
up, then this is the age he would be.
This Homunculus appeared on Yock
Island, the same place he was born.
It's the only explanation
they're one and the same.
But that still doesn't
make any sense.
A Homunculus is...
created from alchemy alone.
Created?
Is that what you think?
Do you know exactly how a
Homunculus is created, Edward?
Not exactly, but... but they're probably created just
like chimeras, in some place like that Laboratory Five.
No.
You're wrong.
Either because of love or out of foolish
curiosity, human transmutations are atempted.
And when these attempts all
backfire, a different life is created.
A being that has its own
body and mind, but no soul.
That is how the damned are born.
That is a Homunculus!
And how do you
know about all of this?
Who told you?
Envy helped me
remember where I'm from.
And what I am.
Envy?
You've seen that monster?
I have.
Envy was born the
exact same way.
So were the other
Homunculi, all thanks to...
idiots like you, who
decided to play God.
And now all we really want is
to become human ourselves.
Let's get going.
Well, hello, Ultimate Shield.
Hello, yourself, Ultimate... Oh, wait, you
like to be called Abomination, don't you?
You were sealed in a prison
for more than a century.
And you still haven't
learned your lesson, Greed?
Yes, forgive me if my
name-calling's gotten a little stale.
It's been hard to keep
my jokes current in a cell.
What did you do with the skull?
Why, I smashed it into
little pieces, of course.
Ah, I see, so you've taken
and hidden it somewhere.
Don't worry, I'll find it and put
you right back where you were.
Like I'd let you.
From the news I've been getting lately,
we've got a brand-new member around here.
He has nothing to
do with you, Greed.
He doesn't, but I still
want to live and be free.
And to make that happen,
I need a few more allies.
That's too bad.
Hello, Sloth.
This is Sloth?
You mean someone
with that name was born?
There's a new Lust, too, which means that the seven
of us have assembled for the first time in a long time.
It's a pleasure to
meet you, Greed.
I'm so honored to
make your acquaintance.
I may be greedy,
but I'm still not a fool.
I have no intention of fighting
two Homunculi at the same time.
Oh, well.
We'll have to deal with
them at another time.
Where's Wrath?
Oh, I imagine he should be
with the Fullmetal Boy now.
You mean you propelled him
into a confrontation with elric?
The plan was to use Wrath as bait
to put them back on the trail of the
Philosopher's Stone.
That'll have to wait.
So sorry.
I had to see the son of that bastard
trembling on his knees in fear.
I remember.
I can picture it all.
The only thing I could do was sit and
wait in the absolute darkness inside the gate.
I just kept waiting and waiting.
All the while, my body
was slowly growing.
One day, an idiot dropped by.
He had already given his leg, and now
he stuck his arm across the threshold.
He was screaming and crying,
Give me back my little brother!
I took his limbs for myself.
After a long time, I was able to open
the gate with my newfound power.
And I finally came
out of the darkness.
This can't be.
Thank you for the arm and leg.
Thank you for
this incomplete life.
Nothing can match my gratitude.
Not even my hate.
Now, give me your entire body!
Once I have that,
I'll be a real human!
Ow!
That hurt!
Your metal body's
not the one I'm after!
Brother, if you're not
going to do this, then I will.
Al, please, don't do it!
He's... I have to!
His arm and leg
are my brother's.
The things he lost
because of me.
It's all my fault!
No Al.
All this time, we've been trying
to get our normal bodies back.
Nothing's going to stop me now!
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 32, Dante
of the Deep Forest.
Greed, also known
as The Ultimate Shield.
What is the secret
of this Homunculus?