Mr. Hughes?
Hey, it's me again.
That damn Winry!
She needs to be a little more
careful when she does a tune-up.
Peace of...
Now what are we gonna do?
It's still a long way to Ishbal.
We're walking, Al.
It's the only thing we can do.
What?
That's impossible!
I mean, I could do it, but
there's no way you can!
You got a better idea?
There's not a train that goes anywhere near
Ishbal, and the roads have all been shut down.
And it's not like we can
ask the military for anything.
That's true, but there's...
Stop whining and start walking.
We're not getting any closer to Ishbal
standing around in the desert like this.
Let's go.
Brother!
He should really learn
to plan things better.
Humankind can not gain anything,
without first giving something in return.
to obtain something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
See, Al?
Everything turned out fine.
No problem.
What do you mean?
We made it to some
random town, that's all.
Since when did you
become such a pessimist?
We can probably find a
car in this town or something.
And what would we
do if we did find one?
No one would ever sell
a car to a couple of kids.
Well, guess we'll
just have to find out.
Brother, you shouldn't
be so impulsive.
You gotta learn
to plan things out.
Think ahead a little bit.
I am planning things out.
No, you're not!
You're... what you're about
to do is just... it's... What?
It's just what?
Are you sure we're
doing the right thing?
I mean, of course
we have to stop Scar.
I understand that.
And the whole point of all this is to
get our bodies back the way they were.
But what happens after that?
Beats me, Al.
Why don't you tell me?
I don't know.
It's just...
Maybe we should concentrate on
the Homunculi before we go after Scar.
What are you talking about, Al?
If you're worried
about something, say it.
All I mean is, there
might be a better option.
We just need to think it over.
You're not making any sense.
Listen to me!
We need to stop and think
about what we're doing!
Shut up!
You think it over, Al!
What?
What are you doing?
There!
Tell me if you get
any good ideas.
Very funny!
Now you're gonna get it!
That should cool off
that head of yours.
Thanks!
I'm thinking much clearer now!
And I see you
dug yourself a hole.
Brother, stop it!
Take this!
Take that!
Dammit!
Brother, stop it!
Please!
Wait until I get my
real hands on you?
What's wrong with you?
Why do you always
have to be so stubborn?
I am not being stubborn, Al!
Yes, you are!
If you weren't so stubborn,
we wouldn't even be here!
We could have
asked Dad for help!
Are you kidding?
I'll never ask that
bastard for anything!
And that's exactly what
makes you stubborn!
Shut up!
Do whatever you want.
Brother!
Come back!
Nice to see you again.
Miss, uh...
Miss Bookworm.
I'm sorry, I can't
remember your name.
Hey, Sheska.
Yeah, right.
And your name
is Windy, isn't it?
It's Winry.
Right!
Sorry.
I'm sorry, what were
you going to say?
No, please, after you.
Uh, well, um...
There's something important
that I wanted to discuss with you.
What is it?
Hmm...
I've been investigating the
death of Lieutenant Colonel...
I mean, the death of Brigadier General Hughes on
my own, secretly, for a pretty long time now, actually.
The Lieutenant Colonel... I
mean, Brigadier General Hugh...
How about Mr. Hughes?
All right, I guess I
can call him that.
Go on.
It's kind of strange.
Strange?
The deeper I investigate, the
more peculiar things become.
I'm scared.
I don't know what to do.
But why are you
telling me all of this?
Because I can't trust
anybody in the military.
Not even Colonel Mustang, now.
Please!
I can't take it anymore!
If someone doesn't
listen to me, I'll... I'll...
Hey, calm down!
I understand.
It'll be all right.
Thanks.
I knew I could count on you.
What's his problem, anyway?
He complains about everything.
Hey, Al.
Pass the salt.
These are all of the documents that I
arranged and then copied for Mr. Hughes.
And... and this is all of the material that I've gathered
on my own based on what I found in those documents.
Sheska, listen, you don't expect
me to read all of this now, do you?
Yeah, why not?
That's impossible!
Reading all of that
would take me months!
Yeah, I guess you're right.
I'll just summarize it for you.
It all started with the
collapse of Lab Five.
There's no way I can find out what happened
there, because there aren't any records for that facility.
But that lab's definitely where
Mr. Hughes began his investigation.
And then...
And then what did you find out?
What happened after that?
Oh, right.
Mr. Hughes was investigating Lab Five, and
he was researching the Civil War in Ishbal, too.
Ishbal?
Now, it's only speculation,
of course, but I think...
I think that during his investigation, he must have
found out about something that he really shouldn't have.
And he was killed.
Wait!
Okay!
I understand!
Please, don't cry!
Brother, you numbskull.
Hey!
Come on, Al!
If you're worried
about something, say it!
I did!
I was trying to tell you that in
the end, we'll have to face her.
Brother, where did you go?
I've...
Marta!
Long time no see.
After examining these documents, I
noticed that one name kept popping up.
What name?
Who?
Colonel Juliet Douglas.
They say she sparked the uprising in
Ishbal by accidentally shooting a child.
But there's a small problem.
According to buried records, she died in an
accident two years before the war even began.
Oh.
Here.
Take a look at this picture.
What?
What's going on here?
I found all of this in
Mr. Hughes' investigation files.
He got this story from a
newspaper in her hometown.
Okay.
So a woman named Juliet
Douglas died two years before.
But do you think it's a mistake?
Like in the records?
Or maybe someone
with the same name?
The government and the
military records match up.
It's no mistake.
But that's not
the strangest part.
What is?
She's still on active
duty in the military.
Look.
Here.
What is going on?
Just what I've said.
The woman dies two years before the
war, yet the military says she participated in it.
Not only that, they
basically say she caused it.
And yet afterwards she inexplicably landed a huge
promotion as the Führer's secretary where she is today.
That's so weird.
Someone who should be
dead is the Führer's secretary?
But that's not the end of it.
What?
There's more?
If this same woman was alive, she
would at least be in her fifties by now.
But the Juliet Douglas I saw working as the Führer's
secretary is in her thirties no matter how you look at her!
She doesn't die and
she doesn't get any older.
What the hell is she?
None of this information
makes any sense.
But after a lot of thought and
deliberation, I've come up with a hypothesis.
hypothesis?
And when you look at it this way, all of
the discrepancies begin to make sense.
Miss Douglas is actually...
...an alien.
I think that hypothesis
needs some work.
Huh?
What else could she possibly be?
I'm sorry, I really don't know.
But I think if we can keep digging, then we
can find out exactly who murdered Mr. Hughes.
But what can we do?
I work for the military, but all I
really do is take care of records.
And Juliet Douglas is with the Führer, so there's no
way that I can get close enough to her to investigate.
I can't even find
out what she's doing.
If we eavesdropped on her conversations,
I think we could get some more information.
Eavesdropping?
That's the kind of thing that husbands do to their
wives when they want proof for divorce hearings, right?
I couldn't possibly do that.
Oh, yes you can.
I'll help you.
Marta, what are you doing here?
Following you.
I want you to tell me
about your enemy, Al.
Enemy?
You know, the ones
dressed in black clothes.
Why do you want
to know about them?
Why else?
For revenge.
Sorry about my
uniform being too small.
Well, when you're doing a lot of manual
labor, your arms get big, you know?
I never really noticed before.
Anyway, about the case, I really think
that, uh, that's what I should be the one to do.
Hey, what is it?
Nothing.
Did you know those two
officers in the hallway?
Yeah, we've met before.
This is it.
All of the phone lines are
connected and routed in this facility.
Hmm.
As you can see, they've put
quite a few locks on the door.
And the alarm system is
probably connected here as well.
We're going to have
a hard time getting in.
It's open.
Huh?
What?
This is all baby stuff, really.
Oh, okay.
Come on, let's go.
All right, what's the
Führer's room number?
Room 103 in Central Hall.
Room 103, okay.
Here we go.
Right.
And we're hooked in.
Now all we have to do is wait.
That's wrong.
That means that Law and Greed's
efforts to protect you were for nothing.
It doesn't make any sense.
You know what I am, don't you?
I'm a Chimera, and I've gone through
too much to live a normal life now.
Greed and my fellow comrades, they
were the only semblance of a family I had left.
But revenge?
That's no way to... There's
no point in trying to stop me.
I'm half snake.
Vengeance is in my blood.
But... but you
can't... you just...
She's just like Scar.
There's no other reason for
me to live anymore but revenge.
And besides, Al, they're
your enemies too, aren't they?
We'll be helping each other out.
I don't plan to help you with your
revenge, so I'm not going to tell you anything.
I can't.
But why not?
Because I'm sure that Law and your
other comrades would say the same thing.
So...
Goodbye.
Vengeance is raw.
I do have to stop them.
Both Marta and Scar.
Al?
Al!
Looking for him always
gives me a headache.
Edward?
I can't find Alphonse anywhere.
Have you seen him?
Did something happen?
Who cares where he is?
I don't.
You boys fighting?
It's all because of him.
Al keeps nagging me wanting to know
when Dad's coming back like I know.
That can be rough.
Well, I hope nothing happens
to your brother while he's alone.
If only I knew
where to find him.
Why am I always the
one who has to do this?
Come on.
Let's go.
Kay!
Führer's office.
May I help you?
There's a call coming
in from a public line.
The code is... 08.
Put it through.
Showtime!
Hey, guess who?
Envy.
You know the use of insecure lines
is forbidden unless it's an emergency.
Don't be so uptight.
You're the one who
told me to report in.
I'm almost there.
It's too quiet here.
I think if they don't make a move soon,
I'll... You'll complete your mission loyally.
Understood?
What?
Envy?
That's the Homunculus
Ed was talking about.
I've gotta go.
It looks like I have
another job to do here.
Maybe we should
disconnect it now.
Right.
Good idea.
Hmm.
What a weird conversation.
I wonder what it
could have been about.
Who knows?
But it did sound like they were talking
about something big and dangerous.
What do you think?
I think we'll still have to
gather some more evidence.
That was strange,
but not incriminating.
Even if we eavesdrop, this
still isn't going to be easy.
We'll have to check in
at different times, so we...
What's wrong?
We gotta run!
Come on, hurry!
What is that thing?
How should i know?
just keep moving!
Slow down!
What is it?
What's going on?
It was her!
It was that girl!
There.
The door!
Winry!
it's their mom...
Ed and Al's mom.
It's her.
Winry!
I had a feeling that
was you in the hallway.
What are you doing here?
What's going on?
Saved.
I knew it! I knew it!
She is an alien!
Alien?
Come on.
Let's go.
Huh?
Brother?
We're going to Ishbal.
You're right.
We've got to stop Scar.
How did you know
where to find me?
You haven't changed at all.
Huh?
When you were little and we had a
fight, I'd always find you sitting by the river.
Hmm.
Yeah, you're right.
What are we gonna do now?
I guess we'll have to walk.
We don't really
have a lot of options.
Huh?
Hey!
Wanna lift?
Marta!
Who's that?
You know her, Al?
Uh, well, yeah.
Sort of.
All right, then.
What are we waiting for?
Let's go!
No, brother!
Wait!
It's no big deal.
I'm just trying to help
out someone in a bind.
Don't think this
changes anything.
I won't let you do it.
Everybody ready?
Yeah!
Let's go!
What's wrong?
Oh, nothing.
I was just thinking.
Of what?
Remember the first time
we actually got in a fistfight?
Oh, yeah.
You curled your little hand
and punched me in the face.
That was the first time
I went to sit by the river.
Is that so?
Yep.
You always went missing out.
Even after we had a fight.
Even when we were
studying with Teacher.
I had to do the work
for both of us back then.
We fought about who was
gonna marry Winry, too.
We did?
Really?
Yeah.
That's when we
fought the hardest.
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 39,
Secret of Ishbal.
The battleground that Scar has
chosen is a place we'll never forget.
It's a town called... LIOR.