Do you really think we're gonna find the
Philosopher's Stone in a rundown town like this?
Looking around, it's hard to believe
they ever produced much gold at all.
Which is why they're all the more likely
to be developing a Philosopher's Stone.
What do you mean?
Now that their mines are no longer
producing gold, they've got plenty of
reason to want to transmute it.
And they could only do that
with a Philosopher's Stone.
What, with this being a former gold
mining town, it wouldn't look too suspicious.
Is money all that
grown-ups think about?
Elisa!
Hey, get over here.
Give me a hand.
It's no use.
It won't budge.
Daddy?
It's alright.
We'll get you out of this.
I promise.
What's wrong?
My daughter!
She's trapped!
Hold still for just a minute.
OOH, WOW.
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Fullmetal Alchemist, Episode 11:
The Other Brothers Elric, part one.
I mean it.
We sure were lucky to have a real
alchemist like you show up when you did.
I can't begin to
thank you enough.
And don't forget
about his metal father.
No, you've got it all wrong.
Al's not my father.
He's actually my
younger brother.
Younger brother?
But he's so much
bigger than you are.
Anyway, we're both just
glad that you're okay, Elisa.
Elisa!
Elisa, are you alright?
Uncle Belsio!
Daddy?
Get out.
You've got some nerve showing your face
in my house now, after almost getting my poor
daughter killed.
Listen to me, Elisa.
No matter what he says, you are not
to help him with his work ever again.
No, Daddy.
None of that was
Uncle Belsio's idea.
I was the one who begged
him to let me help out.
I'm sorry, sweetie.
Here, drink this.
I am sorry.
Uncle Belsio told me your lemon
pies were always the best, Daddy.
And that it was a shame all
the lemon farms were shut down.
I thought maybe if I helped
him, I could taste your pie.
Don't worry.
Once the Philosopher's Stone is
finished, we'll all be rich, and then we
can afford to buy all the fruit
we want from some other town.
Philosopher's Stone?
Yes.
That's it.
The two of you must have come here
to Xenotime to assist Mr. Mugear with his
research, and finish
the Philosopher's Stone.
Please, do everything
in your power.
Make it as fast as you can.
We want Xenotime to once
again be the town of gold.
We must reclaim
what's rightfully ours.
That's right.
We're counting
on you alchemists.
Our children must
not suffer any longer.
Eh.
Wow, that really puts
a lot of pressure on us.
I guess we'll just have to visit
Mugear now and see what we can do.
Before you go, could you tell
us the names of our saviors?
Certainly.
I'm Edward Elric.
The Full Metal Alchemist.
And I'm his brother Alphonse.
Alphonse Elric.
The, uh, Elric brothers?
State Alchemist, Hero
of the People Elric?
Yep.
What was that about?
Shut up.
The real Elric brothers are already
working to save our town up there with Mugear.
Come back when you're ready
to tell us who you really are.
Now why would somebody go
around using our names?
Brother, are you really
going to sneak in there?
Of course we are.
To confront these imposters.
And get them to tell us all
about the Philosopher's Stone.
Brother was that?
A transmutation.
Look at this.
All these books are about
the Philosopher's Stone.
Then this must be where
they're making it, right?
No doubt about it.
In case the guards weren't
a clue, this place is off limits.
By any chance, are you guys
the ones... Stealing our names?
I take it that means you
are the real Ed, in the suit.
Me?
No you don't!
I'm Ed, not him!
Why does everybody
always think that?
Huh?
So you're the older brother?
Damn right!
Try to tone it down a notch.
Or the gunmen will
realize you're here.
How bizarre.
The real younger brother wears
a suit of armor to protect himself.
It's hard to believe
you're only fourteen.
How do you know
so much about us?
You want to start
something with me?
No, I don't want to
fight with you, Ed.
So why don't you turn
around and go home.
And leave us to take
care of things around here.
That's not the way you beg
someone to do something.
On your knees!
I said get down on the ground!
What?
So we can see eye to eye?
Surely you must be used to
people looking down on you.
An auto-mail arm, huh?
I guess the real Ed's
seen some action too.
And I'm glad to see
you have some skills.
I'd hate for you to be
damaging my name!
You know I've always wanted to find out
what a bonafide state alchemist is capable of.
And I think you're going
to be sorry you asked.
Not bad!
You don't need a circle, huh?
The fakie doesn't
need a circle either!
How did you... you have
a philosopher's stone?
What was all that commotion?
It came from in here.
Damn it.
I feel sore all over.
The fakie was
pretty powerful, huh?
Heh.
He had something
giving him a boost.
Does that mean they've finished
making a philosopher's stone?
I don't know, but
we're going to find out.
You know, I wonder what
those brothers' real names are.
Or if they're even
really brothers at all.
And I wonder if the older brother's
actually much older than you are, or...
Size doesn't mean anything!
Uh...
Brother?
I think we should just
give this ruse up already.
What if the real Elric
brothers turn us in?
Then what?
Don't worry.
Nobody around here is going
to believe anything they say.
So just concentrate on completing
the stone so we can split town.
I just hope it
works out that way.
Well, I'm not going to let Mugear take the credit
for the research Dad devoted his entire life to.
Don't worry.
If it comes down to that, I'll
make sure you get away safely.
No matter what.
You don't get it, brother.
I'm not worried about myself.
There's a lot more
going on here than that.
Are you sure you should
be standing so close to it?
I didn't expect to see you here.
And I didn't expect
you to let those kids in.
But there's no need to worry.
My guards scared
off the Elric brothers.
I think we've seen
the last of them.
Don't bet on it.
Those boys can be frustratingly
resourceful when they want. A desirable trait.
Of course, we always knew it was only
a matter of time before the military took
interest in your research.
You had your shot.
But maybe it's time you
called it quits, Mugear.
A little more time, please.
That's all I need.
Just give me a little more time.
I promise you I'll complete
the Philosopher's Stone.
Make it fast.
You know I hate
being dissatisfied.
It's starting to
swell up pretty good.
Your cold metal feels
just like an ice pack.
Glad I could be of some
comfort to you, brother.
Even in this armor.
Hey, you were the guy
with the lemons before, right?
If you need a place to board
up, you can come with me.
Thank you so
much for taking us in.
Couldn't very well let you
kids sleep outside, could I?
Aren't you gonna ask
us what our names are?
You're the Elric brothers,
that's what you say.
Then you believe us?
Honestly?
Not in the least, but I figure you kids must
have your own reasons for saying that you are.
Makes no difference to me.
To each their own.
So you're not into the Philosopher's
Stone like your neighbors are?
Everyone else is unable or unwilling to
forget the wealth the gold once brought them.
So Mugear's got them
wrapped around his finger.
Good morning, Uncle Belsio.
If your father finds you
here, he won't be happy.
Not to worry.
Daddy's too wrapped up in talk
about the gold mine to even notice.
Good morning.
Hey, it's the make-believe
Elric brothers.
That must hurt.
Did somebody hit you because
you were telling lies again?
I'm telling you, we're not
the impostors here, kid.
But I did get clocked
by one of them.
Wait, you don't mean that you're the
ones who snuck into Mugear's mansion
last night, do you pretend brothers?
Of course we did.
We can't just let those
phonies run off with our names.
Besides, it's a major crime to use
a Philosopher's Stone to make gold.
They're going down.
Brother.
I'm gonna see what
I can find out in town.
Brother.
Hey, big guy.
Yes?
How would you like to run down
to the pharmacy for me today?
What do you need?
Elisa needs her medicine,
and your brother?
He could probably
use a cold compress.
My word, don't look now but one
of those charlatans just walked in.
The gall of him showing
his deceitful face in here.
And you just know they were the ones who
broke into Mugear's mansion last night and
tried to Rob him.
Hey you!
What are you doing here?
I just need to get
some medicine.
Well, we don't have nothing
here to keep you from telling lies.
So go on and get out!
Great.
Now how am I gonna
get that medicine for Elisa?
Uh, excuse me.
You!
I can buy that medicine
for you if you let me.
To make up for me
borrowing your identity.
Here.
Thank you very much.
I guess both of us have older brothers
who let their tempers get the better of them.
Aren't you mad at us?
I figure you have
your own reasons.
I'm sorry.
For us to work with Mugear,
we had to have some credibility.
The only way my brother could pass for a
state alchemist as a teenager was to claim
he was the famous Edward Elric.
You want a philosopher's
stone that badly?
My father... He devoted his
entire life to working on the stone.
So, your father was
an alchemist too?
Mm-hmm.
But then one day, he
was suddenly gone.
So now out of love for my dad, my
brother insists on completing his research.
That's the opposite
of my family.
Our father was also an alchemist,
but my brother hates him for it.
He was obsessed
with the science.
And our mother suffered because
of it, especially when he left her.
And us.
On our journeys, my brother and I have
met a lot more people who've suffered because
of alchemy too.
Listen, if your brother's doing something you
know is wrong, please, just be brave and stop him.
It's tough, I know.
But if someone else has to intervene,
it'll only hurt your brother more.
Hey!
Have you noticed how there are an awful
lot of people with bad coughs in this town?
Uh
Uh, no.
Well, isn't this stuff
cough medicine?
Actually...
Brother!
Sorry, I have to go now.
Wait!
Tell me your real name!
It's Fletcher.
Brother?
Why are you running?
That imposter is
around here somewhere.
Have you seen him?
Um, no.
That unethical jerk.
Did you know he's been fixing people's
tools and transmuting wheels all over town?
That's better than him using
your name to do bad stuff.
That's not the point!
It's the way he works!
He's got no regard for the
law of equivalent exchange!
Al, we're gonna sneak into
the mansion again tonight.
What?
Just one day later?
Right!
They won't expect us.
Brother, there's something
I need to talk to you about.
Tonight we're trying
Operation Molehole.
Molehole?
By my calculations, we should be
under the center of the mansion now.
Are you sure?
No, but we gotta
come out somewhere.
We're in!
What is this?
So that's their plan.
I think this is the chemical
used to produce the redstone.
What redstone?
I remember reading something
about it at the library in Central.
It's a theoretical solid pumped
full of alchemic catalysts.
You put this refined red water under a
few megatons of pressure till it turns to stone.
A philosopher's stone?
No, more like a cheap imitation.
I think there was some alchemist named Nash
or something who was researching the redstone.
But in the end, it
never panned out.
Brother!
I'm having some
trouble breathing!
Brother!
This way!
Who's there?
It's me, come on!
Hurry!
Fletcher.
Brother, are you alright?
Where am I, Al?
And what the hell
is he doing here?
I... I'm sorry.
What are you sorry about?
What'd you do?
No, Fletcher.
It's what you
didn't do, isn't it?
If you know something, tell us.
I get the feeling you don't
like what's going on here.
That red water you saw?
It's a toxic substance that's
been polluting the whole town.
But it's... it's the vital ingredient
for creating a redstone.
Is that why the people in Xenotime
have been coughing so badly?
I'm... so sorry.
Okay, this is ridiculous.
First things first,
let's demolish this lab.
I can't let you do that.
After all the work we put into
it, we finally created a redstone.
My father gave everything he had in
pursuit of this breakthrough, Mr. Elric.
If you think I'm going to give
up now, you're quite mistaken.
So you care that much about a
lame piece of costume jewelry?
Yeah, a fake sword
from a fake stone, huh?
I think I can top that.
Mine's the genuine article.
What the...
Red water straight from the tap.
If you're doused
with it, you're a goner.
You'll lose a lot more
than your consciousness.
Fine, let it rain.
Ed, this is crazy.
Your brother's right.
Just go and you can live.
Never.
I'm not giving up to some
naive kid who's desperate to be.
Just like Daddy.
Ah!
Fletcher!
Fletcher, hang in there.
Brother, the reason Dad wanted to create
a redstone was to bring happiness to people
and make their lives better.
But what we've been doing here, it's
actually been making people suffer, hasn't it?
Don't you see the cost
of forging that stone?
It doesn't matter who
gets the credit anymore.
Because this isn't... Because Dad would
be ashamed if he could see what we've done.
Full metal alchemist!
The Other Brothers Elric Part 2.
There's more to being me
than just using my name.
Can you handle the consequences?