Brother...
EDWARD!!!
was too easy.
Humans are so pathetic.
Brother no, you can't die.
It's supposed to be me.
He's dead?
That's right.
He's setting the pace for every human to
follow.
Now we'll kill off each one of them until
only Homunculi are left.
[Laughs in douchebag]
Brother can't die.
That's ridiculous.
He wouldn't let that happen.
He couldn't.
That's reality for you.
All the effort he gave got him nothing in
return.
You can pay all you want.
It's never enough.
Hey, you all right?
Colonel Archer?
Give me your car.
Where are you headed to, sir?
The Führer's mansion.
The rebels are there, right?
That was a false alarm, Colonel.
We've just come back from there.
It was Lieutenant Hawkeye.
Hawkeye?
And you let her live?
Hold your fire, Colonel!
The Führer wants her interrogated at
Headquarters, sir!
Have you seen Headquarters?
We're in a war zone!
Rebels are everywhere!
We don't have time for questioning!
Let me kill her!
Is my species of consequence to you now?
I haven't had the chance to test my
Homunculus traits much.
I wanted to see what would happen if I let
my whole body explode.
You really wanted my position badly,
didn't you, Mustang?
I can appreciate the vanity of ambition, but
you should have been more patient about it.
Even if this had somehow worked,
the Council would have found you out and
they'd never let an assassin back into
their fold.
I didn't do this for politics.
I couldn't forgive myself for being blind
this long.
This was the only way I could
atone for the friends I didn't save.
Well, then by all means, let me help you
with that.
Give my best regards to General Hughes.
What's going on?
Hello, son.
Good news, I've caught the rat.
I'm sorry that I disobeyed you,
Father, but I just had to come back.
I forgot something and I wanted to make
sure that you were okay.
So what now?
You said people are foolish, so how do you
explain loving him?
Father, what's the matter?
You look like you're hurt.
What's wrong?
What have you done, you idiot?
I just... I got it from your safe.
You said your life depended on it and I
didn't want it to get hurt in the fire.
Father.
Stop!
You are foolish.
All of you.
Even my own son.
I don't know how you've lived Führer.
Or how many times you've
cheated death, but not anymore.
It's the end of the line.
Don't do this!
That sound, what did he just do?
Gluttony.
He used alchemy, with a stone.
You petulant boy, look at the damage
you've inflicted on yourself!
Sit down before you're wasted completely!
Stay back!
You can't make me do anything!
And what do you think you can pull off?
Brother hasn't been dead for long.
Look, there's still some color in his
face.
His soul is probably still at the gate.
I just have to pull it back.
The same way he did for me.
Don't be a fool, you know what would
happen to you.
Yeah, I do!
A lot of people died to make this stone.
And I would have died too, if not for
them.
And it's time I gave my share,
and made my own choice.
Alphonse.
Goodbye, Rose.
This is for you, brother.
I'll miss you.
General!
Dammit, Roy Mustang, talk to me!
Al.
What.... What's going on?
Where am I, you worm?
The gate.
So what's on the other side of it?
I don't know.
For me, it was a place called London,
if I remember right.
That's what my old man said.
Old man?
You mean Hohenheim of Light?
Yes.
You're telling me he's still alive?
I wouldn't do that.
There's no way to know where it will lead
for you.
Like hell there isn't!
I'll tell it exactly where to take me!
I've come to kill him!
Take me to Hohenheim of Light!
Stop messing with me!
You'll do as I tell you!
You're taking me to see Hohenheim!
To that bastard!
To my father!
Al.
Edward?
Can you hear me?
Yeah.
But what am I crying for?
Al?
He used alchemy to bring you back,
Ed.
After you died.
The Philosopher's Stone.
He used it to fix my body and pull my soul
from the gate.
But then what happened to him?
Don't tell me...
Don't tell me he's gone, Rose.
Al!
Al!!!
Damn that child.
How could he squander the stone like that
with my body in such terrible condition?
I'll have to send Pride down there to
teach those boys a lesson.
Dammit, gluttony!
What are you doing here?
I don't have time for this!
You don't understand me, do you?
Just hold on.
We'll find you something to eat soon,
okay?
You'd better get moving.
I hate to ask this, but could you take him
to the surface too?
What about you?
I'll destroy this place down to the last
plank.
So no one ever gets the idea to create a
Philosopher's Stone this way again.
Very well.
I'm sure whatever happens, you'll find
your way out.
You've got strong legs.
You'll get up and use them, won't you,
Edward?
If what my dad said about the Gate is true,
Al's old body and mine should still be there.
And now his soul is there too.
Maybe life has no equal trade.
Maybe you can give up all you've got and
get nothing back.
But still...
Even if I can't prove it's true,
I have to try.
For your sake, Al.
Dear Winry.
It was nice to hear from you again.
Central is finally settling down to some
normalcy.
After the fall of Führer King Bradley,
the new government didn't waste any time
taking over, and the military surrendered
control of the state back to the old assembly.
But that doesn't mean the end of war,
with several neighboring states still
vying for power and reacting to old
wounds.
There is good news, though.
The assembly has voted to completely
reverse the Ishbalan policy.
They're going to help them rebuild on
their old land.
It's going to be a hard road, but I
believe there's reason for hope.
It's still going to be a while before General
Mustang is ready to come back to work.
But I think his influence will help a lot.
What's the frown for?
The plan was perfect.
You did your part.
But I should have gotten there sooner to
protect you.
Nothing's perfect.
The world's not perfect.
But it's there for us, trying the best it
can.
That's what makes it so damn beautiful.
Just shut up and eat.
Needless to say, I was shocked to hear
about Al.
So when they found him, he was a
ten-year-old boy again?
With no memories of anything that took
place in
these last four years? As if all he'd done since
their mother back had never happened at all.
Have any of those memories returned to him
since you wrote me last?
And what about Ed?
Any news?
I know that must be hard for you.
Teacher!
I still can't get my head around all this.
Do you think Edward's really gone for
good?
There's no way to know what Ed paid to
make this happen.
A life for a life has never been enough.
It's possible he traded with experience.
That the value of the memories they shared together these
four years became payment for getting Al back as he is.
Lately, he can't last an hour without
sticking his nose in an alchemy book.
It's like the old days.
It comforts him, I think.
Reminds him of Ed.
Meanwhile, that boy named Wrath got some
help.
Winry and I fitted him with a brand new
automail arm and leg.
Our latest model she'd been designing for
Ed.
And where is he today?
He wandered off days ago.
That sounds like him.
You really want to train again?
Mm-hmm.
At your place, if I could.
May I, teacher?
Please.
We learned so much from you the first
time.
I want to know more alchemy.
And more on equivalent exchange.
So that one day soon, I can be with
Brother again.
I've no idea how to make that work.
But if... if I study hard enough,
I will find a way to bring him back.
I can't explain it.
I just know.
Al...
Will you let me?
Can't say no to that face.
Now, Al, I want you to promise me
something.
I'll study, too.
To be the best mechanic I can be,
however that may help down the road.
So in exchange, you have to promise me,
okay?
Promise you'll come home safely,
so I can help you.
You got a deal.
I'll find a way to bring Brother back,
and then we'll all be a perfect team.
Exitus acta probat.
Tau se stes ca vestman rhein.
Bei Tag und auch bei Munterscheid.
Blick doch gleich durch das Firmament.
Elig Finns es doch fundament.
Brothers, let's adjourn for the day.
I want to thank you for sharing your time
with us, Professor Hohenheim.
You really believe that knowledge can come
from this sorcery?
The Thule Society knows certain truths
about the Aryan race.
We come from an island long forgotten by
the modern world.
Communicating with the ancients will teach
us what we've lost, and help us fulfill our destiny.
We are counting on your continued help,
Professor.
Not to worry.
As you know, I'm a hunter of lost
knowledge myself, Professor Haushofer.
Excuse me, where are you going?
Very expensive.
Monty!
Fourteen marks for a piece of fruit?
It's absurd.
And absolutely ridiculous.
How long is this inflation going to last?
Have a wonderful day.
I want to show you something.
Show me what?
Planning a trip, Edward?
Look.
The liquid fuel rocket, Robert Hutchings Goddard.
He's an American.
But there's another guy studying the same
thing in Transylvania right now.
Wouldn't happen to be named Dracula,
would he?
Nah, it's Hermann Oberth.
He's been a student here in Munich.
I'm gonna see him.
You mind telling me why?
He thinks he can get to outer space in a
rocket.
No one knows exactly what's up there
beyond the atmosphere.
Maybe it's like the gate.
A portal between different worlds.
Haven't you studied Einstein's theories?
No one believes him.
If you can't use alchemy, you'll go buy
machines.
Is that the plan, son?
I know that my alchemy did something.
I saw Al put back together at the gate,
and I thought it was for me.
But then I woke up here, and until I
understand why, I have to keep working.
You knew the only way to keep your body and mind
was to come to this side, so you did it without thinking.
Subconsciously, as Freud would say.
Still.
But Al returned to me, I lost again.
I should have found a better method.
But nothing's ever perfect.
Haven't you realized that yet?
Earth turns on a tilted axis, just doing
the best it can.
It's wrong.
I thought I made an equal exchange.
My body, mind, and soul for his.
Yet here I am, still alive.
So does that mean Dante was right,
except to the opposite extreme,
and I got something for nothing?
Or does it mean that in reality, Al wasn't...
You boys had a long journey together.
All the people you helped along the way.
All the hardships.
The pain of losing friends you loved.
The determination.
Sweat and blood.
Don't you think that may have been the
price you paid?
I don't know how to get back to you.
This world's a strange place.
But one thing's for sure.
I will find a way.
We'll be together soon, Al.
Humankind cannot gain anything without
first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of equal value must
be lost.
That is alchemy's first law of equivalent
exchange.
In those days, we really believed that to
be the world's one and only truth.
But the world isn't perfect.
And the law is incomplete.
Equivalent exchange doesn't encompass
everything that goes on here.
But I still choose to believe in its
principle.
That all things do come at a price.
That there's an ebb and a flow.
A cycle.
That the pain we went
through, did have a reward.
That anyone who determined and perseveres.
Will get something of value in return.
Even if it's not what they expected.
I don't think of equivalent exchange
as a law of the world anymore.
I think of it as a promise.
Between my brother and me.
A promise that someday, we'll see each
other again.