Hey, find anything good yet?
No, nothing but garbage.
Well, keep trying, man.
We all gotta pull
our weight, huh?
Thank you for such
a warm welcome.
But you're sure? You realize
who we are and where we're from?
Judging by your complexion and
eye color, I'm guessing Ishbalan, right?
Well, don't worry.
This is a place of refuge for those who have been
banished from their homeland for whatever reasons.
No questions asked.
We accept criminals and
Military deserters alike.
An eclectic mix.
Here, you must be thirsty.
I found the man from Ishbal
with the scar on his face!
It's the opportunity you've
been waiting for, Yoki!
Hey, kid!
Wait up!
Hey, hold on a sec!
Listen, I'm sorry!
I didn't mean to attack
you like that back there!
He just slipped through a
solid brick wall, but how?
You're a real pain!
If you can't tell, I'm
a little busy right now.
They say you're a genuine State Alchemist who's
looking to get his hands on the Philosopher's Stone.
Is that correct?
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Half a pound of ham, 128 Cens.
I need to speak with Izumi.
Can you tell me
where to find her?
Chicken breast, 160 Cens.
All right, maybe you can tell me if the Elric
brothers, Edward or Alphonse, have been here.
Any clue who this Joker is?
- Cubed Steak
- 215 cens a pound. Or what
he might want with Ed and Al?
Not the small guy.
The big guy's usually friendly,
but he doesn't look happy now.
- Smoked Sausage 27 cens per link. And I'm
guessing if he's looking for the boys, it can't be too good.
Top-grade boneless
Chuck roast, 200 per pound.
We're here on official
Military business.
You have no need
to protect them.
Ground beef, pork or
Turkey, 98 cens a pound.
I'll take care of this one, sir.
Stop, Major!
Ed and Al are... What the...?
Guess they've earned
each other's respect.
The muscles did
the talking for them.
That's just odd.
What's that you were saying,
miss, about Edward and Alphonse?
I don't know what you mean.
Oh, I think you do.
Rumor has it you used your brother's body
as a sacrifice and had to transmute his soul.
Though why you used his and
not your own, they don't say.
Ungrateful bastard, I'm
trying to take you to safety.
And that means you and
that freak you call a brother.
Who are you calling a freak?
It's true you really are
as hollow as a tin can.
Tucker was right.
Tucker?
Now you're dead.
Don't get upset.
It's not like it hurt
when I decapitated you.
It won't get away that easy.
Your powers are uncanny.
Then again...
I'm uncanny, too.
What the hell was that thing?
A chimera.
Interesting.
It must have escaped from Laboratory
Five during all the commotion.
The Major!
We haven't seen you in a while.
Yes.
This man here is Lieutenant
Colonel Frank Archer.
He's the ranking officer in
charge of the Military Court.
Then what are you
doing this far south?
The Military Court?
You must work pretty closely with
Lieutenant Colonel Hughes, then.
How's he doing?
We'd like to ask you some questions regarding
that chimera and a few more unexplained events.
I'd love to stick around and chat,
but we don't have time right now.
Let's go, Al.
Right behind you.
This is certainly
getting interesting.
A perfectly functioning chimera.
It will be mine.
What happened?
We just saved your dumb ass!
How come my arms and legs
look so different from both of yours?
That's because this arm
and one of my legs aren't real.
That's dumb.
What'd you do with the real
ones you were born with?
It's hard... to explain.
Well, where are they now?
What about you?
Are you sure you don't
remember how you got this scar?
No.
You know, it could
just be a coincidence.
I don't think so, Al.
But your arm and leg were both
taken in the equivalent exchange, right?
So what would they
be doing back here?
You have to admit,
that's a little weird.
Oh yeah, it's more
than just a little weird.
But as long as we're
stretching the limits of possibility,
let's just say he was able to
salvage my limbs from the gate.
And possibly, we
could get your body, too.
Here, take a look at the
bottom of the kid's right foot.
He may be the key to
the mystery of Lab Five.
I want him detained.
But what should we do
about the Elric brothers?
Forget them.
Now we've found a
much more valuable target.
Your move.
Hey, is everything okay?
Or did I do something wrong?
Brother!
Major, what the
hell are you doing?
Brother, no!
What do you want to do with him?
He's an innocent kid!
He's totally lost his memory!
This kid may be a material witness to
everything that happened in Lab Five.
He's coming to South
Headquarters for questions.
But he doesn't
even know who he is!
Perhaps, but we've managed to
get a solid clue as to his identity.
That Mark... it's what
the homunculi had.
Give me a few good hours with him, and
he'll lead us to the ones who destroyed Lab Five.
Major!
Go to your teacher's
house, Edward.
Wait there so we can
find you when we're done.
I'm afraid we're going to need
to take your testimony again.
I thought this whole investigation had been
officially suspended by the Führer himself.
A long time ago, a fox
took a bite out of my arm.
Right here.
That kid has the same
wound in the same spot.
Then there's his left leg, which
doesn't look like it belongs with his body.
You honestly believe that
his arm and leg are yours?
That's preposterous, Ed.
I'm not sure!
That's why I need a
chance to confirm it!
Don't pursue this.
How can we stop?
This is the kind of break
we've been hoping for!
Say we do investigate.
And say we find some way to prove
that those are indeed your limbs.
Then what?
What would you do, Ed?
Would you tear them from his
body and sew them on yourself?
Of course not.
Then you're better off
never knowing the truth.
Yoki, you say?
I know I've heard
that name before.
He claims he once oversaw the Military's
mining operation at Youswell in the East.
Yes, I remember now.
Yes, I'm positive.
I saw him with my own two eyes.
Yes, yes, that's correct.
That's wonderful news.
I'll be sure to let Führer Bradley
know, and if it does turn out to be true,
maybe he'll reinstate
you into the Military.
Thank you!
And the Military man slung him over his back and carried
him all the way to South Headquarters for questioning.
What a shame, but good
for you for finding him.
He sounds special.
I want you to forget about tracking the Smelric
brothers for now, and keep your eye on the little imp.
You got it?
Turns out those Elric boys are
exactly as you described them.
Yes, I'm sure they'll
be of great use to you.
When I first heard that Envy, Pride, and the rest
were after these twerps, I didn't give a damn anyway.
I just wanted to grab the boys
myself to piss off the others.
But now the boys have led us to
someone actually worth chasing.
To think there's a homunculus like
me who can honestly use alchemy.
We need to have him on our side,
or things may get complicated later.
Let me break him out, sir.
Have you gone insane?
You can't just go
charging into that place.
It's a bloody fortress.
You're a former
Military lab rat.
I shouldn't have
to tell you that.
Not that anyone asked, but I used to be
stationed at South Headquarters back in the day.
You're right.
We didn't ask, so
keep your trap shut.
State Alchemist.
No.
Since you've so passive-aggressively
volunteered, perhaps you can guide these two there.
But if I learn you've betrayed our
cause, I won't be feeling too friendly.
You can rest easy, boss man.
All I'm really wanting... is a chance
to make some fireworks again.
What did you boys do to him?
We didn't do anything.
Why are you making such a big
fuss over him anyway, teacher?
Maybe it's the
best thing for him.
They might be able to
track down his identity.
And besides, he's not human.
You may not believe they exist.
We didn't.
But we've seen more than
our share of homunculi recently.
They're real, and
they're terrifying.
They have powers that
ordinary humans don't.
A mouth that can
chew through metal.
Fingers that can stretch
and Pierce anything.
There's even a homunculus
that can morph into anyone.
That child may have
special abilities, teacher.
But that's because
he's a monster.
Do you have the slightest idea how a
homunculus is brought into this world, Alphonse?
Take it easy.
Do you take me for a fool?
That I'd be so blind as to not
realize exactly what this child is.
Teacher!
Izumi!
So she's been
sick all this time?
Yeah.
But since she always acts so
strong, sometimes we forget.
But what's her illness?
Maybe if we transport her to a
hospital in Central, they can find a cure.
Young lady, I'm afraid that
won't do her much good.
No offense, doctor, but I think a big
city hospital would be better equipped.
He means what?
She's cut, can't be cured.
All of her internal organs,
from here to here, are missing.
Missing?
How?
It looks as though somehow
they were just taken away.
Amazingly, the remaining organs have all
adapted, intertwining to pick up the anatomical slack.
Still, I don't know how
she survived this long.
Brother, do you think she...
You heard what he said.
Like they were just taken away.
So, she must have tried to
do the same thing that we did.
Doctor?
Thank you, honey.
But I'm okay now.
I'm doing this alone.
I have to.
You wouldn't let me help last time, and I
know there's nothing I could have done.
But now...
Please.
I don't want you to see
what I'm going to have to do.
Mr. Sig!
Please tell me Miss
Izumi's not inside!
How come you're
just ignoring me?
I asked you a question!
They're all in harm's
way, Miss Izumi, Ed and Al.
Why did they do this?
I didn't know....
couldn'ta.
She felt guilty, as
though it were her fault.
But it was me who made the decision to
save her life at the expense of our unborn child.
Still, she apologized to me repeatedly
for not being strong enough to give birth.
A baby, I see.
Afterwards, I didn't realize the depths
of the depression she suffered from.
Or how heavily the loss
weighed on her heart.
I certainly never imagined she
would resort to such drastic measures.
What do you mean?
The same taken by
your friends, Ed and Al.
Human transmutation?
She tried to revive the baby?
She went off, all by herself.
And wouldn't tell me what
happened when she did it.
But when she came back to
me, all of her insides were torn out.
She said she'd never be
able to get pregnant again.
And again, she told
me she was sorry.
Would you like to kick
this party off with a bang?
It seems I'm gonna
need a little more sulfur.
That'll do.
Oh, come on.
What now?
Major, we have to keep moving
or else that woman could...
Major!
My, my.
Things sure are hopping
around this place today.
Teacher!
I have to ask you to put him down
and get out of here as fast as you can.
Listen.
Like it or not, I'm part
of the Military now.
What the hell?
What's the Führer doing here?
Perfect.
You're here too.
So sorry to intrude.
We just came for the kid.
Teacher.
The Military.
And these bastards.
Damn.
Looks like a four-way fight.
Well, then I guess I make five.
That man who just passed,
do you know who he is?
Is he another Ishbalan refugee?
Keep your distance
from that one.
Didn't you see the tattoo
branded across his face?
The shameful Mark of a sinner.
He betrayed God's ways, and for
that, he was exiled from Ishbal forever.
It's a camp in the south, in
Kishua, full of the disenfranchised.
What of it, sir?
We have reason to
believe Scar is hiding there.
Take care of it, Colonel.
Sir!
We're moving out.
To the city of
Kishua's western slum.
That's where Scar is hiding.
If he surrenders, great.
We'll do everything we
can to keep the peace.
But if he resists, let's be
ready to take him down.
And anyone else
who gets in the way.
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 31, Sin.
Those limbs, they belong to brother.
He lost them because of me.
We've come too far
to lose them again.