So, boys, you're really
convinced you're ready for this?
That's right.
Just tell me what to
wear to graduation.
Hmm.
Careful, Ed.
I'd hate for you to get cocky.
As you know, you
find your own training.
I suggest him.
Sewing life alchemist, huh?
Shau Tucker.
Practically wrote the book
on bringing things to life.
That's how it started.
We spent the months before the
exam living at the Tucker estate.
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Two years ago, Mr. Tucker used alchemy to create
a chimera that could actually speak our language.
Quite a feat.
How the heck did he do that?
Beats me.
I guess it was some kind of composite
using several animals with different genes.
Had the brass in an uproar.
Needless to say,
he's passed the exam.
Sounds awesome.
Yeah.
Now, it's not just
the two of you.
Mr. Tucker has a
four-year-old, so be polite.
What about his wife?
Isn't he married?
Let's go in.
That's his house?
It's so... Yeah.
It's pretty big.
Come on, boys.
The door's over here.
Right.
Sorry.
Coming.
Ah!
Guess everything's big here.
Oh, yeah.
You know that's bad, Alexander.
Oh, my.
I'm sorry.
No, Prob.
Just don't... say roll over.
Sorry about the mess.
We just lack a
woman's touch here.
Oh, that was sexist, wasn't it?
I've been so out
of sorts lately.
Oh!
Hey Daddy, bigger
brothers clothes are funny.
They're like a button pin.
Aren't they heavy?
That's okay.
Bigger Brother is very strong.
Oh.
Uh... Er...
Mr. Tucker, I'm sure you'll have a chance to
talk to these boys about their unusual traits.
Until then, please, just
take them as they are.
Nina, why don't you play
in the courtyard for a while.
Aww...
I bet Alexandra's lonely.
We'll play later, okay.
Sometimes I wonder if I
have the vigor to raise her right.
You're so young to
be taking the exam.
I'm happy to help.
And we thank you
for it, Mr. Tucker.
To start, we'd love to see
that chimera you created.
The talking one!
I'm sorry you've come too late.
It died shortly
after it was made.
Besides, studying for
the exam comes first.
It's a monster.
You'll need much more than an
overnight cram session to pass.
Wow!
This is the reference room.
You're welcome to it.
I've never seen so many books.
And they're all about alchemy?
This collection
is nothing, really.
You should see the alchemy floor they
have in the National Library in Central.
Books are the
best tools we have.
Pass your exam and you'll have access to
dozens, no, hundreds of times more knowledge.
Really?
Brother, we should get started.
He already has.
Edward, making
progress in your studies?
Yes, sir.
Some.
But I've got to speed up.
There's so much I don't know.
Yes, the more steps we take forward,
the longer we see the path is ahead.
But you're so young.
You needn't worry about
taking the exam this year.
No.
I don't care what the odds are.
I don't care how
long the path is.
I'm going to take this test.
I don't make excuses.
Waah!
Big brother isn't
eating his dinner.
That won't do.
You have to eat to get grown up.
I think I'm plenty...
Thanks.
Wow, it sure looks delicious.
Make sure you chew.
Mmm.
Yeah.
It sure tastes great.
Good.
Now eat the steak.
You still up?
My head is too full with
all the stuff I learned.
Yeah.
Ed?
Hmm?
Get some sleep.
You shouldn't worry.
You're smart and determined.
You'll pass.
Maybe.
It's nice here though, isn't it?
Kind of like before.
In those days, the two of us wanted
nothing more than to become state alchemists.
We felt like once we did, this
great big door would just open up.
Oh no.
Is it that late already?
Yo, Alphonse.
Where are you?
Let's hope the dog didn't
think he was a hydrant.
Al!
Hey, brother.
We made angels
brother, come look.
I wish you could stay.
I mean, after you pass the
test, it gets lonely with just Dad.
Huh?
What are you drawing,
little big brother?
A transmutation circle.
See if I have a wish,
it helps it come true.
Okay.
Now watch this.
You made me magic flowers!
Decent work.
Major Hughes.
Hey.
I came for you, Ed.
Gotta keep you from studying
through your birthday, you know.
He's right.
That's today.
How did you know that?
I haven't told anyone yet.
I'm in the investigations
department.
Wouldn't make much of a
major if I couldn't manage that.
Don't look sad.
You're all coming.
I can't throw a birthday dinner
and not invite his friends, right?
Welcome, kids.
I've heard lots about you.
This is my lovely wife, Gracie.
Your stomach's a melon!
Yes, yes.
You're having a baby?
Soon?
Any day.
There's a big fuss inside my belly saying
she wants to come out and see the world.
Really?
Wanna feel?
Eww, no.
I do, Mrs. Hughes.
Well, go ahead, Nina.
I felt it.
It moved.
It felt funny.
Who wants refills
on their birthday tea?
Sounds wonderful.
Gracia!
Honey, it's here.
The tea?
The baby!
But the doctor said next week.
Well, the baby just said now.
And I'm pretty sure
she gets to choose.
Okay.
I'll get your bags.
But the snow.
It's a blizzard outside.
Right.
You can't leave.
I'll bring the doctor here.
You kids help her.
How do we do that?
I guess this counts
as party games.
Okay.
I've got the hot water bowl.
Thanks, Edward.
Set it on the floor next to me.
Okay.
What else?
Well, let's see.
I guess I'll need a
lot of fresh towels.
Okay.
I'm just glad your
pain's passed.
OOOWW!
He's been gone for so long.
Yeah.
He probably had to walk.
I can't do this!
I'm dying!
AHHH!
What are we supposed to do?
She said she's gonna die!
But, that's just an expression!
OOOOOOWWWWWWWW!
AAAAAAAAAAHHHHHHH!
But since she's not
dead, she just fell asleep!
I don't know.
If you think of it like alchemy,
making a life's expensive.
You don't have to
give something up.
Childbirth is not
alchemy, you dope!
Look!
She's alive!
Can I do anything, Mrs. Hughes?
You could all stop yelling.
Damn it all.
Alchemy's the ultimate science.
There has to be some
way it can help her.
Little Big Brother,
the water's very cold.
Ed, what did you do?
I have no clue!
You heated the water.
Alchemy.
How did you use alchemy
without a transmutation circle?
I don't know.
I just used my head.
AHHHH! I can feel it's head now!
You can feel it's head‽
What's that mean‽
I'm not touching baby stuff!
I can't believe she's
so beautiful, Gracia!
It's all thanks to you kids.
I couldn't have done it without the
other birthday boy and his friends.
We didn't do anything.
You were right by my side.
This alchemy stuff really
didn't help her out at all.
Nothing a hot water
heater couldn't do.
Yeah.
Now mom's on the other hand.
There's your miracle.
Gracia did something tonight
alchemists couldn't do in a thousand years.
No strings attached.
Our mom did it too.
Al, you...
You think I was that
soft when I was born?
And warm?
Of course you were.
You were still soft
when you were five.
Yeah.
After the birth, we dove into the
alchemy books with new determination.
We were going to pass our exams and
get our bodies back the way they were.
I've been thinking, brother.
That night at the Hughes, you
changed the water without a circle.
Most people can't do that.
But it was just a fluke.
I haven't been able
to do it since then.
Still, you showed
it was possible.
I need to learn how too.
Okay.
How about I quiz
you twice as much?
Okay.
E-Day, as we called it,
was fast approaching.
It's always the same.
Written test, then an
interview, then practical skills.
There's no way to know
how many people will apply.
But the state only accepts
one or two each year.
One or two people?
You're kidding me!
It's rough.
Uh, what kind of stuff do
they do in the interview?
That varies, I think.
With me, they just ask questions, but I've
heard physical exams are pretty common too.
Uh, let's say.
After that, if you pass the first two,
you move on to the hardest challenge,
the practical skills.
Half bring results of their research,
like I did, and half perform on the spot.
You boys have a plan, right?
Uh...
Dammit.
What am I gonna do?
I didn't think I'd need
a demonstration.
And what about a physical?
They could open up my armor
and find out there's nothing inside.
Hey, maybe you could stuff Alexander
in there and pretend you're a talking dog.
I don't think that's very funny.
With our anxiety piling
high, E-Day finally came.
We hoped if we could pass the written
part, Colonel Mustang would help with the rest.
We'll now commence
with the preliminary exam.
Good luck.
Begin.
Big brothers.
How'd it go?
I didn't finish, and my
wrist feels like spaghetti.
I got through it, but
next comes the interview.
I never imagined that the
younger one would pass it too.
Is that a problem, sir?
There's gotta be a way.
No, you can't say that.
I've worked so hard for months.
I'm not dropping out now.
If you want to go on without
revealing your past, you have no choice.
That's not good enough.
I'm not getting split
from my brother.
Easy, Al.
You remember what
Aunt Pinaka said, right?
State alchemists are military, and get
thrown into service whenever war breaks out.
You have to do what they say, even hurt
people for some good you don't understand.
It means you're a dog of the
state with a leash around your neck.
But, Ed... One of us has
to join to get what we need.
But we both don't have to.
Let me go alone, and
I promise I'll fix things.
Get us back the way we were.
Brother...
A chair with three legs.
It shouldn't keep its balance.
Take a seat.
Alchemy is the
science of balance.
If you have the gift,
it will not refuse you.
Go on, Edward.
State alchemists
cannot be afraid.
Very good.
Now tell me why you want to
be an alchemist for our military.
Because...
I'm waiting.
Because I made a promise.
To the only family I've got.
I told him I'd become an
alchemist in service to the state.
And take all the good
and bad that comes with it.
Al,
Do you think we decided right?
Chose the right path?
I don't know, Brother.
But I do know this.
I don't want to be
in this suit anymore.
I want to feel things again.
It's strange.
We've been right beside
each other all this time.
But I can't remember what your
skin feels like or how you smell.
And then, the day
of the practicals.
I'm off.
Not yet!
Go on, Nina.
I made something for you.
It's a circle to help your wish.
It's great.
Thanks, Nina.
Welcome to the
practical skills exam.
We've provided you with some
nice raw materials for your alchemy.
You may use them to
create whatever you see fit.
Gee, nice guidelines.
What the heck am I supposed
to create to impress them?
Impressive detail.
But he used so much
energy, he can't even stand up.
You can't get tired?
Out of the way.
I'm next.
What's he cooking?
I hope that little big brother's ok.
Don't worry.
You gave him your
circle, remember?
AWWW!
Nicely done.
Trees and water into a
hydrogen paper blimp.
That's not good.
Look out!
Alchemy without circles.
I think we've found
our alchemist.
Youngest we've had.
Magic flowers.
Al.
Hmm?
Today marks a big turning
point for us, you know.
It's full speed ahead now.
And if dead ends come,
then we'll find another way.
Someday, I swear, I'll get
you back the way you were.
Uh-huh.
And when that day comes, your
full body will be there too.
Full Metal Alchemist Episode 7.
Night of the Chimaera's Cry.
Nina...