So that's it.
You girls really aren't
going to tell us anything.
I already told you, the alien...
Let me handle this, Sheska.
Saying that you were lost is hardly an excuse
for crawling around in the generator tunnel.
What in the world were you
doing down there in the first place?
Sergeant.
Can you at least tell us what
you're planning to do now?
Lieutenant Ross?
Something really bad's
happening inside the Military.
You need to be careful.
Thanks.
I'll do that.
So what now?
We can't do too much.
Well, it's back home
to Resembool for now.
I'd like to speak to Ed and Al about
this, but I've got no idea where they are.
Well, what am I
supposed to do now?
What are you talking about?
You're coming with me, Sheska.
But what about all
my books at home?
They'll stay home.
Oh!
So, can I take this off now?
Go ahead.
Thanks, Strength.
Much better.
Kimbley!
Hello, Major Flame.
Haven't seen your
pretty face in a while.
Oh, I'm sorry.
It's Colonel now.
Is there a problem, Roy?
You damn well know there is.
What's he doing
on this train, Archer?
Who?
You mean the Crimson Alchemist?
Lieutenant Colonel Zolf J.
Kimbley.
Lieutenant Colonel?
This man was wrongfully imprisoned
for crimes he did not commit.
And just before he was subjected to
illegal experiments at Laboratory Five,
he heroically escaped.
And now, thanks to his fearless work, all
the loose ends from the lab have been tied up.
This is ridiculous.
Crimes he didn't commit, Archer?
I'll remind you.
The Führer gave me the rank of Colonel
for this operation, and I don't need to listen
to any lectures from
an equal-ranking officer.
Hm.
What about this
report you received, sir?
What did it say?
Oh.
Do you know anything about
a desert town called Lior?
What's that?
Look!
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
So, you're the one.
Yeah, I killed Greed,
and I'm not sorry either.
Brother, please,
this isn't the time.
Marta, I'm not really sure where you stand on all
this, but I want to make sure you know where I'm at.
I regard you and Greed as
criminals, especially Greed.
He murdered Dante, an old
woman, and he deserved what he got.
Marta, stop!
Look out!
A snake!
Great.
If we were enemies,
you'd already be dead.
Greed knew he'd be sealed
again, and he couldn't take that.
What is worse for the greedy
than having nothing at all?
I think he wanted
you to end his life.
And the pain.
My enemies in all of this are
the Military elite who made us.
Those freaks
dressed up in black.
And the rat who
betrayed us most of all.
Kimbley!
You should eat that.
They're good for you.
Really?
Then why don't you eat it?
Come on, you want to turn
me into a cannibal now, Ed?
We're close to
Lior now, aren't we?
What?
Yeah.
I wonder how Rose is.
I hope she's all right.
And who might that be?
Nice try, brother.
I know you've been
thinking about her, too.
Hey, Marta.
How long till we get to Ishbal?
You're looking at?
Hm?
At least what's left
of Ishbal, anyway.
It's worse than I imagined.
There's really
nothing left at all.
Scar wouldn't be here.
We're back to square one.
What exactly are you
looking for, anyway?
The Philosopher's Stone.
Someone told us it was created here a
long time ago, before Ishbal was destroyed.
But that's impossible.
If the Ishbalans were capable of something like
that, they would have put up some kind of resistance.
Resistance?
What do you mean?
There was armed tension between the Military
and Ishbal for years before the war broke out.
And when it did, it was because of an
Ishbalan revolt, in reaction to a Soldier
accidentally shooting a child.
So, that's the way they told it.
Always wondered
what they would say.
Hm?
But I never got to know.
I was locked up in
Lab Five for 14 years.
But that was when
the tension first started.
You would have just been a kid.
I may look young because of the experiments,
but I'm actually old enough to be your mom.
That old-I mean, wow.
We were special ops.
The soldiers who
don't officially exist.
They didn't brief us on our assignment
until moments before we had to move out.
That's the way it always was.
What was that?
Big trouble!
We were ordered to infiltrate Ishbal and
perform disruptive activities on a large scale.
We were told they were planning an
attack on Central, and we had to prevent it.
Covertly.
Anyone who saw us
could not be left alive.
But why would the Military
provoke a war without provocation.
And how come no one ever stepped up
to tell our people what really happened?
No one ever knew about it.
You did.
Well, let me finish my story.
No!
Ew.
Weird.
I think I'm missing your point.
Wait, it's a visual.
Right after the war in Ishbal started, we
were all taken into custody without explanation.
It wasn't smart to resist.
What's going on?
We're soldiers like you, dammit!
We were following orders!
Those of us who lived
became the rats of Lab Five.
No!
Dorochet!
Is that you?
Marta!
What the.....
B..Behind you!
Behind you!
They turned you into chimeras.
They could further their research
and silence all of us at the same time.
But why?
They didn't want the real
reason for the war to get out.
It's part of some greater truth.
But what the hell for?
How could they
profit from Ishbal?
Someone's here!
Yeah, our next lead!
Stop!
Alright, fess up!
What in the hell are you guys
doing out here following us?
This area's off
limits to civilians!
We're here under orders.
We're supposed to check the
security of the old Ishbal region.
Then why didn't you just come ask us
about it instead of hiding like a couple of spies?
My brother may not look it,
but he's a State Alchemist.
And a tough one.
What are these guys?
Moles?
No.
I think I recognize
those voices.
Hey.
It's you guys?
That means the
Colonel's here too.
Hmm.
Can't say I was expecting
to see you here, Ed.
Yeah, I get it.
Wouldn't see me since I'm so short you
couldn't distinguish me from all the grains of sand.
Very funny!
I understand you've been
making quite a mess of things.
Southern Headquarters?
And an escort train
full of Ishbalans?
No more.
From now on, you'll be
working under my command.
But Colonel... You were lucky
Havoc's patrol picked you up.
It's dangerous out here.
But you know how we work.
We should be able to
conduct our own investigation.
It's the rules, Al.
I'm their dog.
And when war starts, they
put me back on their leash.
War?
Just look around you.
They've come on a full
Military train, armed to the teeth.
But, who are we at war with?
Calm down.
We're just suppressing
a little regional uprising.
Our objective is a city about
two kilometers to the Southeast.
And that's it.
Big guns for a
peacekeeping mission.
You think so?
Why don't you
come out and say it?
Scar's your real target.
The truth is, we're
looking for him too.
Why Scar?
What's your need to catch him?
He is a wanted man, isn't he?
If we don't, there'll
be trouble later.
Don't be silly, Al.
You don't have to go through
the trouble of pretending to eat.
Uh... alright.
Sorry.
Okay, Al.
You're dead.
What's that?
Pictures of our target city.
From our new
surveillance balloon.
I don't believe it.
Is this right?
A Grand Arcanum
Transmutation Circle.
Around the entire city.
Beat that.
But who would do such a thing?
I got closer to it. I win.
Scar...
And why would you say that?
You wouldn't happen to know the
motives behind that, would you, Ed?
No.
This city.
What's it called?
It's Lior, sir.
Last year, the so-called prophet in
control of the city stepped down...
and the Military was hoping it
could go in and restore the peace.
That'll do, Fury.
He's familiar with its past.
I don't get it.
An armed uprising in Lior?
That doesn't make sense.
They were committed to
peace after we exposed Cornello.
Not for long.
The priest came back, and Lior was divided
between those who supported and opposed him.
The only thing you really
accomplished was stirring up the debate.
Now both sides are against us.
Why didn't anyone
tell me all this?
As far as I knew, we helped.
I got the report from Hughes, and
I made the decision not to tell you.
But why?
Because it was too big for you.
They really don't know, huh?
About what happened to
Brigadier General Hughes?
Apparently not.
If the colonel told the boys all that happened,
they'd no doubt run back to Central in tears.
Fullmetal's work is
too important here.
He can't.
The Elric brothers have entangled
themselves in a very dangerous web.
The colonel wants them to
be under his supervision now.
That's the real reason
he's keeping them close.
Uh, do you guys know
where my brother went?
I want your reporting
directly back to me.
It's very important.
But as long as you agree to all of the conditions
I've laid out, I think we have ourselves a deal.
Edward, what are
you doingin here?
Hmph.
Always overreacting, Mustang.
Mr. Elric here has requested to
do some scouting for us in Lior.
You're going to let one of our most
prized State Alchemists go sightseeing?
It's his talents that make me
confident he'll come back in one piece.
Right, Ed?
He also knows the city's
layout better than any of us do.
And don't worry about
him going AWOL.
He's leaving his
brother here as collateral.
As devoted as he is, I'm sure
that Edward won't run away.
And leave his
little brother behind.
Why the hell didn't
you come to me?
Well, because you
wouldn't have said yes.
You're not thinking straight.
You're upset because you
just learned the truth about Lior.
And I wonder who I
have to blame for that.
Oh, it's hot in there.
You should be careful.
The way the state sees
it, you're a wanted criminal.
Do you really want
to do this, brother?
Go into Lior on your own?
Archer doesn't trust us.
Leaving you behind
was part of the deal.
And someone has
to confront Scar.
You think that transmutation
circle is for the Philosopher's Stone?
If it is, I'll break it apart.
Marta, stay out of sight, okay?
Don't you sweat it.
That's my specialty.
I held myself back from
that Archer jerk, didn't I?
I have to kill Kimbley and
those people in black first.
My revenge against
the Military comes later.
I won't let you do any of that.
Be careful, brother, okay?
Yeah.
Oh, Major.
I didn't realize you were here.
Colonel Archer's orders.
You're to leave your silver
pocket watch at the station with us.
Oh, right.
Guess that'd be a
dead giveaway, huh?
It's foolish, Edward Elric.
Why did you come here?
I guess it's fate.
Don't lie to me.
You've never been
one to believe in that.
I've got another
one for you, Doctor.
Make sure that you give it the full
amplification treatment, if you don't mind.
Heh, heh, heh, heh.
So, Cornello's
followers drove you out.
True for a lot of folks.
That priest turned
out to be a real villain.
A wolf in sheep's clothing.
I guess it makes sense.
I swear I've seen you before.
Hm?
Oh you think so?
I get that a lot.
Look!
She's here!
Lucky timing, mister.
You get to see the Holy Mother.
Holy Mother?
Who's...
You can't come out, sir.
I'm sorry.
The Colonel's
giving clear orders.
You're not to be seen.
Why?
Because I'm supposed to be dead?
At least let me play at night.
I can't.
Really?
Sir?
Heh, heh, heh.
No!
Kimbley!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
Hello.
Who would have thought we'd
meet the boy in this town again?
What should we do now?
Gluttony.
Pride told us something
lust... something important.
It was, uh... He told us to kill anyone
who learned the secret of Ishbal.
It's too bad.
Yes.
He's here!
I can smell the Beast of Ishbal!
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 40,
The Scar.
Someone once told me that the scars
on your body will eventually fade away.
But there are some
wounds that can never heal.