Dante, I want you to stop using my
sons as pawns in your malicious game.
In exchange for that promise, I will tell
you the reason your new body is rotting too.
Perhaps, but it's been centuries
since our last meeting, Hohenheim.
We'll have plenty
of time to talk later.
Right now, why don't you
help me enjoy this new body?
Sorry, but I have a wife.
So, I was married
as well, wasn't I?
Again and again
and again and again.
After all, if I stayed with one of them, he'd have
noticed my slowly aging body and our secret would be out.
That's where we're different.
Tricia was my first and my last.
The only woman
I ever really loved.
How odd.
Four hundred years ago, when we first
met, back when I was still an innocent,
you whispered
words of love to me.
Or do my memories deceive me?
No, they don't.
On that day, four hundred years
ago, we had finally achieved our goal.
By using the lives of those sentenced to
hang during the witch hunts, and those who
were dying of the plague, by repeating our experiments
relentlessly, despite countless failures, we finally grasped it.
The Philosopher's Stone.
But the demands of the
transmutation took its toll on you.
You were dying.
In sheer impulse, I attached your
soul to the body of another man.
And it was then that we
discovered eternal life.
So, by using the Philosopher's Stone...
You transplanted your souls again and again.
Yes, that's right.
Why did you have us find someone to
make the stone if you already had one?
After Hohenheim of Light left
my side, I needed a new stone.
And I didn't know how
to make one on my own.
That's why.
Tell me, why did you leave?
Wasn't eternal life
enough for you?
Dante, there's no such
thing as eternal life.
The Philosopher's Stone.
Those who possess it, no longer bound
by the laws of equivalent exchange and
alchemy, may gain without sacrifice,
create without equal exchange.
We searched for it.
And we found it.
Woah, you shouldn't
put that much salt in!
You're ruining it!
Stop!
Huh?
Oh.
Cooking is an exact science.
Just like building Automail.
To do it right, you just
follow the simple calculations.
Then, with this oven I invented, if
you did everything right, it'll be perfect!
With the easy-to-use temperature setting
mechanism, the built-in automatic cooking
timer, and a window in the front to keep
an eye on whatever dish you have cooking..
..inside it! Every
chef will want one!
Cooking is an
art, like literature.
It's an adventure in creative self-expression that is
limited only by the boundaries of your own imagination.
Cooking is a science!
No, it isn't!
It's an art!
Why don't you answer it?
Oh, I couldn't possibly.
I'm only a guest.
No, no!
You're like family, really!
Get the damn phone!
Okay.
Hello... I'm uh... looking
for the Elric Brothers.
Shou?
Yep.
Some guy with a
really weird voice.
He said his name was Shou.
Shou...
Anyway, he said he wanted to meet
with you and that it was really important.
He said it didn't matter when you
got in, you could call him any time.
Alphonse, he was crying
while he talked to me.
Shou...
Is it someone you know?
Uh, no!
This looks really good!
Ed'll be so happy!
Oh!
Brother's back!
Hey!
Brother!
How come you're covered in dirt?
Brother?
Oh, don't worry.
I was just leaving false tracks to make
everyone believe we were headed North, that's all.
I wasn't watching where
I was going and I fell.
I'm fine.
You should have told me.
I would have come with you.
Think about it, Al.
What would we do if
the Homunculi found you?
Right.
Sorry.
That's okay.
Everything cool here?
Al, did you tell him about
the strange call you got?
Oh, that!
It wasn't anybody we know.
Maybe it was the Military
spy on us or something.
That's weird.
I'm starving!
I was the one who nominated Edward Elric to
take the State Alchemy exam, despite his age!
And now look at the
shame he's bringing me!
Are we absolutely certain that this boy
is connected with the insurrection in Lior?
Well, according to his report, he
was in Lior a year ago, where he
exposed the Leto priest as a fraud who was
using alchemy to control his loyal congregants.
He stated that the people there had
renounced this charlatan, but in reality,
the man went on to lead a revolt against our
troops, and we were forced into armed combat.
I heard the Military suppression was
excessively violent, and that's what started the war.
Are you criticizing my
operations, Mustang?
What the hell, Terry?
Who does he think he is?
Please, gentlemen, calm down.
If you consider the impressive record
Colonel Mustang has compiled, it's clear
that he's an excellent soldier who's
been loyal and faithful to the Military.
However, I would be interested to know the reason
why you called off the search for the Elric brothers.
The Elrics were on their way to their
hometown in the east, but changed
direction before making
contact with our squadron.
Now it seems that they have
redirected and are headed straight north.
North.
To Drachma.
I see.
So, they have connections
with that tribe of barbarians.
Major Armstrong's tactical unit is searching
for the brothers up north as we speak.
And now... I've heard some other interesting
information that I'd like to take up with the council.
Interesting information?
Perhaps you gentlemen
should excuse us for a moment.
Not yet.
You see, the information concerns
your secretary, Miss Douglas.
Just what are you
implying exactly?
It's Miss Douglas'
day off today.
I hope she's all right.
There are serious doubts about her Military record, and
it has now been suggested that she was an accomplice.
In the recent murder of
Brigadier General Hughes.
Oh my goodness, that's
quite an accusation.
You were really in
love with her, huh?
By the way, Colonel, sir, I heard
you made a Wrather important enemy.
Why'd you have to go and
stick your neck out like that, sir?
I don't know whether the
Führer is a Homunculus or not.
But for a long time, these people who call themselves
Homunculi have sacrificed innocent human lives
for one reason, developing the
Philosopher's Stone.
And it's possible the entire uprising and
war in Ishbal were orchestrated by them in
order to gain the lives
needed for the Stone's creation.
You really think
they'd go that far?
Tell me, why would any sane person
go after the Philosopher's Stone?
For wealth.
Glory.
Power.
To gain eternal life.
Despair.
We've all heard the stories of what
happens to anyone who gets near it.
Losing the lives of
everyone you care about.
Or your entire civilization
disappearing in a single night.
It should drive anyone away.
Except someone
who's already lost it all.
Someone pushed to the brink
by the tragedies around them.
Like in a war.
It is odd.
Since Führer Bradley took over,
our country's been at war constantly.
Just one campaign after another.
You're right.
I never realized that.
I'm a soldier.
I don't mind war.
But what if all the
reasons have been lies?
And the sole motive was to cause
death on a large enough scale.
To create both the
motivation and the ingredients
for a stone.
Ed! Al!
Are you planning
on sleeping all...
Sorry.
That's okay.
Don't look so surprised.
A trick like that's
pretty basic alchemy.
Done.
What is that thing?
Don't be scared.
It's just me, Winry.
Al?
I used a few materials I
found to make Al a disguise.
There are no seams, either.
No one will know he's in
there unless they break it open.
So you guys are leaving again?
Sorry, Winry.
There's something I need to do.
Wait, I know!
You're going off to find some
way to get Al's body back, right?
Why don't you just
do your research here?
You're going to avenge
Hughes, aren't you, Edward?
If I give my whole life to revenge now...
Everything Scar said... his life would be meaningless.
Then?
Still, there is something
that I have to take care of.
Something more important than
what you've been searching for?
Or revenge?
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
What do you want?
I'll braid your hair for you.
That's okay.
I'll do it myself later.
I'll do it.
Okay.
Something dangerous, isn't it?
Brother, where do you think Dad went?
Keep quiet back here, okay?
How can my soul be rotting?
Not even souls are invincible.
Each time we leap to another
body, we leave a little strength behind.
Now our souls no longer have
the energy to maintain a body.
You have to face
the truth, Dante.
That's how we're going to die.
I won't die.
As long as I still
have the stone.
I'll transfer to another body.
And pretty soon that
body will rot as well.
And the next one
will go even quicker.
And then I'll transfer
to another body.
And what about the
Philosopher's Stone?
How will you keep
transferring your soul?
You must have already used
up the small fragment I left you.
I forgot you haven't
been keeping up.
Thanks to a clever Ishbalan alchemist
and a decade's worth of labor, one of your
sons has been turned into
a new Philosopher's Stone.
You tricked me.
So you were supporting
Scar this entire time?
You really don't understand.
They should've told me.
Our sons.
They should have told me what
they attempted when I came back.
No.
No, I think I knew.
I just... didn't
want to believe.
Trisha.
I love you.
I always will.
Why, thank you.
You're just too kind to me.
Hohenheim of Light.
I've been doing some research
since you've been gone.
Trying to learn more about the gate
that is the source of all our alchemic power.
I've discovered some
fascinating things, Hohenheim.
Would you like to know
what lies beyond the gate?
You can't tell me you haven't
been just a little bit curious.
Did you know a part of the
gate is actually within all of us?
As our consciousness matures and we grow more
attached to this world, we lose our awareness of it.
But by using someone whose link is still
strong, like a baby, the gate can be summoned.
I'm going to show
you, my darling.
See for yourself just
what is beyond the gate.
Trisha..
Our boys will be fine.
They're yours, after all.
And mine.
No!
Shut it! Shut it! Shut it!
It's all right, Wrath.
I promise that you're not going
to go beyond that gate anymore.
Bring me the Philosopher's
Stone now, Sloth.
Go.
Take him.
And her.
Why should we?
Just so you can be
reincarnated again?
Once I have the Philosopher's Stone
and transfer my soul to another body,
I'll finally be able to turn
all of you into human beings.
Of course, that will depend
on your performance, won't it?
Here we are.
You need to eat more, dear.
If you don't gain some weight,
my dresses won't fit very well.
Now search carefully.
We have to assume they're
in some sort of disguise.
There's a tall one and a dwarf.
The dwarf could easily be
overlooked, so take extra precautions.
That can't be him.
The guy we're looking
for is the size of an ant.
Commander!
We found some weird
bronze statue in the back.
How big is it?
I think it looks bigger
than a suit of armor.
But I don't know.
Let's crack it
open, just in case.
Open it.
Here goes!
Hey, weren't you
tall a second ago?
You're the dwarf!
Al, let's go!
Okay, brother!
Soldiers!
Al, run ahead!
Brother, I bet with the stone's
powers we can... Just run!
Now!
Thanks, brother.
But I could have... Al, you
can't use alchemy anymore.
But why not?
I remember the
gate now, brother.
And I'm a philosopher's stone, so I've been
thinking I could probably do it without a circle.
Just don't, Al!
If you use the stone's power, we
don't know what will happen to you.
We'll take our time, okay?
We'll study more.
And do it right.
Don't worry.
It'll be fine.
Brother, where are you going?
Good old dad told us, didn't he?
Someone out there has been
manipulating all the Homunculi.
There's something here I'm gonna
need, if we're going to stop them.
I'll come with you.
It won't take long.
Why don't you just stay here?
But...
Don't worry.
You just rest for a while.
They've officially ordered us to regroup
and conduct an offensive in the north.
It's a very dangerous region.
Right.
After my little performance at the
council, whoever's pulling the strings in.
all this must have
realized I'm a threat.
And before I could cause any more
trouble, they send us straight to the front line.
If they wanted to silence us so badly,
couldn't they have just done it here in Central?
Not after Hughes they couldn't.
It would be way too suspicious
if they tried that again.
Out on the battlefield, they can
have us killed whenever they want to.
There's nothing like the chaos
of war to mask an assassination.
Even now I'm having
trouble believing it's true.
The Führer is a...
No matter how many times I read the material Sheska
gave to me, I just couldn't put the whole thing together.
I needed to confront
the Führer to test him.
And he's responded
in classic form.
Innocent men don't
cover their tracks.
I didn't think you'd come up
here again, after all that happened.
I could say the same to you.
But I came to look around, and
try to understand some things.
Did you find anything?
I'll tell you later.
Why did you come?
Because I have a
question I need to ask you.
A question about what, Edward?
There's something I need,
and you're not gonna like it.
I'll just say it.
Edward, did you happen to keep any
of the remains of your baby's corpse?
You're going after them?
Yes.
Hello.
It's me.
Thank you for coming Alphonse.
We're happy to see you again.
Teach me.
Teach me how to use
the Philosopher's Stone.
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 46,
Human Transmutation.
You all say you want to be human, but why would
you want to become something that's so flawed?