I knew you would come.
You must feel, as I do, the connection
between us.
A lot has happened between you brothers
and me.
But really, we are very much alike,
don't you agree?
Yes, very much alike indeed.
In fact, Al, I guess that's why Edward
felt uneasy about seeing me today, right?
My brother's not sure we should use the
Philosopher's Stone.
How peculiar that he would hesitate now,
after all the trouble you've gone to, to find it.
We've worked hard to gain back what we
lost.
That's still the only thing that matters
to us.
Does it hurt, Nina?
Everything will be alright.
The preparations are complete,
my dear.
Constructed bodies, and the sacrificed
lives of many different animals.
Now I only need to complete my creation.
Using your Philosopher's Stone.
How did you know we had it?
Or that it was made?
Actually, it was quite simple.
By looking at Archer's wounds, I could
tell exactly what had happened in Lior.
Especially since Scar was there.
Then there's the Führer.
I heard how badly he wanted to find you
and your brother.
And Homunculi like Bradley only chases one
thing.
The Philosopher's Stone.
What?
You knew the Führer was a Homunculus?
Alphonse, my boy, do you have any idea how much time
I spent working in the Fifth Laboratory with all of them?
He felt no need to hide himself from me.
Neither did the other one.
The other one?
The one who gathered the Homunculi,
raised them, and led them all.
Wait a minute!
Then you can tell me who it is
that... We'll talk about that later.
You have something they want quite badly.
Something we've all been searching for.
Now please, let me see it at last,
after all these years.
Where's the real Philosopher's Stone?
Please, don't touch me!
I am the Philosopher's Stone.
I hadn't realized it.
But I suppose this does explain your
brother's reluctance.
Yes.
If we use the stone, there's no telling
what could happen to me.
He wants to study it more.
But he said he has some business to finish
with the Homunculi before we can do anything.
I understand he's worried about me.
I do.
But I don't want to wait anymore.
I want his body to be whole again.
So please, if you know how... Of course,
Alphonse, I can teach you how to use the stone.
But in return, I'd like you to let me use
its powers as well.
That is equivalent exchange, after all.
The Philosopher's Stone.
Those who possess it, no longer bound by
the laws of equivalent exchange and
alchemy, may gain without sacrifice,
create without equal exchange.
We searched for it.
And we found it.
Most of her books have disappeared.
Those left are useless.
Tell me about Dante.
I mean, what kind of person was she?
A great Alchemist from a long line of
them, who inherited this crest.
Or so I thought.
What do you mean?
She was extremely thorough at hiding her
knowledge of Alchemy.
I'm sure she knew more than she told me.
There's nothing wrong with that,
is there?
We encrypt our alchemic secrets,
too, when we record them, don't we?
Yes, well, she was certainly a master at
doing that.
If alchemy is truly meant for the
well-being of people, why do we hide it?
She chose a life of isolation,
living in these woods, seeing no one.
But for what purpose?
I was hoping you'd be happy for me.
Do not expect me to coddle you,
Izumi.
I haven't the talent for it.
I'm leaving you and this forest.
I'm going to live in the city among the
people who need me.
If approval is what you're looking for, then you
might as well enlist and become a State Alchemist.
I've heard they praise their dogs well in
the Military.
Tell me something.
I think you should go now.
Did you ever... did you ever love anyone
other than yourself, Dante?
Why should I love any human being?
They are all ignorant, egotistical things
beyond any redemption.
Once they learned how to use gunpowder,
they thought only about waging war.
If they ever understood the secrets of
Alchemy, what a horrible tragedy that would be.
Don't forget that I am a human being,
Dante!
And that you are too!
There was one name that was never to be
spoken in front of her.
That name was Hohenheim of Light.
My father?
Yes.
This is the only useful thing I've found.
It's a love letter.
From Hohenheim to Dante, years ago.
Wait a minute!
You can't tell me that!
I met Dante!
She was an old hag!
She was at least 20 years older than my
dad!
There's no way!
That's not the only problem with this.
The year is indicated there based on the
birth of Christ.
The birth of Christ?
The dating system isn't used anymore.
It's derived from an ancient religion.
One that hasn't been practiced for
centuries.
That date was 400 years ago.
So what do you make of all this?
I don't know.
Maybe the names are only a coincidence.
Maybe so.
Or maybe she's the one who's been
controlling all the Homunculi.
That's quite a leap.
But if that is the case, are you prepared?
I wasn't much of a help.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
I'd Wrather finish on my own anyway.
Teacher?
I'm sorry.
Go on, you fool.
What are you going to do now?
Start a war up north, apparently.
The Führer won't stop until we're all
dead.
I just wish I could be there to help,
you know?
It's almost time, sir.
Well, at least you won't be lonely now.
Your companion is here.
Master Sergeant Fury.
During your last physical examination,
we discovered Athlete's Foot.
And we now believe that it is affecting
your brain.
Sorry about this, Sergeant.
Guess we just can't mobilize you.
Hmm.
Not bad at all.
That's very funny, sir.
Drachma has been taking part in subversive
plots against our government.
This is a border dispute that was solved
long ago.
But they have chosen to disregard our
treaties.
The Führer has considered all possible
strategies and made a wise decision.
We will gather our Military forces in the mountain
range at the border and expel the rebel invaders.
Those we send to represent us in this
crucial show of force are the greatest among us.
Soldiers.
Champions.
Heroes.
I apologize for forcing so many difficult
missions on you.
It's been an honor to serve you,
sir.
I want you to know that I consider the doubts
about you completely unfounded, Mustang.
I believe that this is proof.
I won't let you down, sir.
You can depend on me.
Good luck to you.
I will await your safe return.
As for you, Lieutenant Colonel Armstrong,
please do your best to look after him.
Of course.
But, sir, I must say I'm concerned about our defenses
in Central if we concentrate our troops in the North.
Don't worry about that.
Frank Archer will be heading our defense.
Archer?
He's still alive?
But how?
Thank you for your hard work, Führer.
You know there are no legends about the
Philosopher's Stone in the North.
Even if we provoke them, no one there will
know how to create a Philosopher's Stone.
It doesn't matter.
Our only objective this time is to cover
up our tracks.
Those who have been close to the
Philosopher's Stone will die.
There will be no exceptions for your
soldiers.
So Mustang's not the only one you're
after?
Of course.
Anyone who had any kind of connection with
Maes Hughes will be killed in action.
Envy's going to see to it.
Are you talking about me?
Envy, didn't I tell you to head North?
I heard he'd be here.
Don't be rude, Envy.
Get out of my way, you puppet!
Don't insult my work, Envy.
A Homunculus who can age like a human is
hardly a puppet.
He's my greatest masterpiece.
Where is he?
Who precisely is he?
Don't play dumb!
You know who I mean!
The bastard who made me the way you made
Greed and Pride!
The one who's been jerking me around!
Oh, yes.
You mean Hohenheim.
He came here!
I know he did!
So where is he?
Missing your father?
I'm touched.
Tell me where he is now!
He's dead.
He's not!
He can't be dead yet!
I'm going to kill him myself!
I broke the union of his soul,
his mind, and his body.
He's as good as dead.
No, it can't be!
Why didn't you tell me?
It was for me to do!
Me!
Of course, his sons are still alive,
you know.
It was for me!
They have the Philosopher's Stone with
them, but then I'm sure you knew that.
They have the Stone?
Are you sure about that?
Positive.
And if things continue the way they are,
they will regain everything they lost.
No.
Such a shame, isn't it?
Those two boys he loved are going to
regain everything, and you alone,
who should have been his most treasured
child, you will gain nothing.
They won't.
I want to witness their faces as I take
the Philosopher's Stone away from them.
I want to witness them lose everything.
This note says that he went to see Tucker.
That's Shou Tucker.
I thought we'd seen the last of him in
Lior.
Interesting.
So why do you think old Tucker got in
contact with him all of a sudden?
Isn't it obvious?
He wants to complete that useless Chimera
he's obsessed with.
His daughter, Nina.
Tucker learned a lot about the Stone while
working in Laboratory Five.
He knows what it's capable of.
If he learned that much about the way the Stone works,
then he must know enough to teach the boy how to use it.
Why don't you tell me what you're thinking
about, Lust?
WWrath, dear.
Take care of things while I'm gone.
You're leaving?
For a little while.
You know, you're
brother really is a genius.
He's the one who thought of that
seven-point array.
Made it up on the spot by himself.
And you just imitated it?
I would like to claim that I made some
improvements.
But in all honesty, Edward's first attempt
was as close to perfect as mine will ever be.
Somehow he must have known that this complex
array is the only way to activate the Philosopher's Stone.
So he does know.
He's just trying to protect me.
You know, despite the fact that getting
your body back has been his highest
priority for all these years, I don't
believe that your brother has any
intention of using the Stone now that
you've finally obtained it.
Why not?
Perhaps it's because...
Nothing.
Will you come over here, please?
Tucker!
I'm afraid I have to insist that my
payment come first, Al.
You understand.
But such a large Philosopher's Stone as you should be more
than enough to resurrect my little Nina, don't you agree?
No, wait!
I'm not ready yet!
Oh, Nina.
Nina.
It's time, my dear.
Tucker!
Al?
Al!
Don't even try it.
You're looking well for a fugitive of the
Military.
My brother told me who you are.
What you really are.
I'm nothing but myself.
Catchy.
Oh, I'm sorry, boy.
Did you want something in here?
I told you I know what you really are!
Today's the day.
I'll take this.
Sorry, my arm's not for sale.
Let go!
Okay, Wrath.
Don't bother begging for your life,
Elric.
I wasn't about to.
I was just going to say go ahead.
Take my arms and my legs, too.
I don't even care.
I've got the best Automail Mechanic in
the world.
What are you talking about?
Ask yourself this, Wrath.
If you take my arm and my leg and attach
them to your body, do you really think
that'll make you a human being?
I have artificial limbs and Al's a suit of
armor.
But our souls make us human beings,
not our bodies.
And that's something you'll never have!
Just shut up!
Why are you just standing there?
Kill him!
You know what'll happen if we have to go
back there and tell her we failed again!
Kill him now, Lust!
I guess you want to become a human,
too, now don't you?
If there is a Philosopher's Stone
then Shou Tucker is teaching your brother
to use it as we speak.
Let's say, that you did know how to use it.
Stop, Lust!
We can't talk to him!
Then would you?
Would you make me a human being?
Traitor!
What the hell are you trying here?
I already told you.
Oh, come on.
If you really think I would turn you guys into
humans, you're even crazier than I thought you were.
Why wouldn't you?
If you transformed all of us Homunculi into
humans, then we wouldn't be chasing you anymore.
You'd have no more enemies, would you?
Traitor!
You just couldn't be patient, could you?
Didn't she already say she'd make us into
humans if we found the Philosopher's Stone for her?
I don't believe her.
I can't.
I know she just wants the philosopher's
stone to prolong her own life.
For that reason, countless wars have been
fought.
You know our master has no intention of
ever making us all human.
Well, I've never really cared if she helps
me or not.
I've got my own strategy for becoming a
human, Lust.
I guess it's just like our master said.
You really can't be trusted, can you?
I'll do all of us a favor.
Let's go.
We have to hurry.
Sloth went after your brother a while ago.
Do you know where Al was going to meet
Tucker?
The factory where he worked before he
became a State Alchemist is nearby.
I assume they went there.
Wait!
Wait a minute!
I didn't promise you anything,
you know.
Why?
I'm the one who should be asking why.
Why do you want to be human?
You guys are immortal, aren't you?
And you don't even age at all,
from what I can tell.
You can't be hurt, and you have powers no
human being can ever top.
So why should I believe you when you say
you want to give all that up?
You don't know how cruel you're being,
do you?
All right.
Why do you want your brother to return to
the flesh?
He's practically immortal too now.
It's the same thing, Edward.
Hold it!
The person you were talking about!
The one you call master!
Just tell me one thing.
Is it somebody that I know?
You know something?
If you make me human, I just might answer
that question.
Hey!
Don't forget!
I still have your weakness, you know.
No, Edward.
I won't forget about that.
Nina, sweetheart.
What happened?
It's really you.
Oh, Alphonse, you're awake.
Look who it is.
Nina.
Darling, do you understand what I'm
saying?
Do you, Nina?
Listen carefully, darling.
I want you to see Daddy.
There's no soul.
Congratulations, Mr. Tucker.
A perfect human transmutation.
It's all right.
I didn't come all this way to take that
soulless doll away from you.
It takes a very strong will to attach a
soul.
So I'm sure you are aware that it wasn't
possible for you.
Come, Alphonse Elric.
It's time for us to go.
We can't let that long-awaited
Philosopher's Stone erode anymore.
Erode?
What do you mean?
No!
Brother!
What's happening to me?
Is this really the Philosopher's Stone?
Fullmetal Alchemist.
Episode 47,
Sealing the Homunculus.
Look, Sloth.
Your weakness is here.