Well, we're here.
Yeah.
What's the matter?
What do you think is the matter?
Once again I'll have to listen to
Colonel's sarcasm.
Tell me how I screwed up.
Struck out on the Philosopher's Stone
again, huh?
How am I supposed to keep funding this
goose chase?
Money doesn't grow on trees there,
Chief.
Ed, where'd you run off to?
Oh, wait, there you are.
I couldn't see you there beyond my
paperwork.
Seeing as how you're so short and all.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
I know.
We're already here, so I might as well get
the verbal abuse over with.
Let's go, Al.
Hey, Al?
Al!
Coming, brother.
What are you up to?
AHHHHHHHH!
Huh?
What was that?
Humankind cannot gain anything without
first giving something in return.
To obtain something of equal value must be
lost.
That is alchemy's first law of equivalent
exchange.
In those days, we really believed that to
be the world's one and only truth.
Fullmetal VS Flame.
AHHHHHHHH!
What's the problem, Breda?
Havoc!
Be careful!
It's on the loose!
There's nothing protecting us!
Over there!
Care to explain this one, Falman?
It is a dog, Lieutenant.
Carnivorous canine mammal.
I believe the scientific name is...
That's not what I'm asking, Falman.
You need to loosen up.
Yes, sir, Lieutenant Hawkeye.
I will continue to work on that.
Sorry, sirs.
I found him this morning.
He was all on his own.
MSG fury.
So, you gonna keep him?
I wish I could, Lieutenant
Havoc, but as I'm sure you're
aware, there's no pets allowed
in the NCO living quarters.
Well, that certainly doesn't mean you can
keep him in the office, Kane.
I know it.
I just... he was shivering out in the rain
and I felt sorry for him.
Your higher-ups, you could keep him.
Not me.
I'm in the dorms, too.
No way!
I hate those beasts!
Don't worry.
I'll take him off your hands.
I like dogs.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
He's really sweet.
Sure.
I hear they're good when stir-fried.
A few spices...
Yes, sir.
Here in the East, they raise them as a
delicacy.
Especially these plumpets.
Let's try to find him a better owner,
okay?
Good plan.
Please.
It was a joke.
So, uh, should I come back later?
Hey, Edward, Alphonse, I guess this means
you're back.
Meow
Strange.
Excuse me.
Al and I need to talk.
Edward, I believe you have a report to
make.
Thanks for the reminder, sir.
I'll speak to the Colonel now.
Al, be rational.
We don't have the means to care for it.
You can't just go picking up any stray you
see.
It's not any stray.
He called to me.
He's wet and hungry.
Can't we keep him?
No, Al.
Now go put it back where you found it.
I hate you, brother.
You're not even human.
Come on, Al.
Don't run.
Think of the kitten.
I know.
I am.
I'm the only one who is.
Wow, Ed.
You really have made some bang for our
buck.
Don't start with me, okay?
You're the one who told me to go to Lior
for a stone that turned out to be a fake.
That's true, but I didn't ask you to
unseat their favorite prophet.
Yeah, and now a town ripe for uprising is
under the rule of the military again.
Wait a minute.
Is that what you were planning all along?
You know, I've heard an odd rumor about
Xenotime and its land baron, Mugear.
Apparently, he's missing and his mansion
collapsed.
Yeah, Xenotime.
Now where is that again?
That's a city, right?
Maybe I should have you file a report on
the Red Water, too.
I almost forgot.
We had a little inquiry from a detective
in Aquroya.
So tell me.
Is it true Psiren's a real ten under the
mask?
So you know everything I do.
Is that what you're trying to tell me?
Great.
I'm glad we had this talk.
Settle down, Edward.
You could at least look like you're
following orders.
Why?
So I can turn into another one of your
toadies?
We've got other objectives, you know.
Like the Philosopher's Stone.
It's been three years and you haven't
gotten any closer.
I'm going to find it, no matter what.
Colonel
Tell me if the name Marco rings
any bells for you.
He's a doctor and
alchemist who showed up in
Xenotime with no
background five years ago.
Apparently, he cured the
poisoning caused by the Red Water,
which no one else could do,
using some kind of alchemy.
You always seem to know a
little about everything, and the
military's bound to have a
file on someone that skilled.
The name isn't familiar, no.
But I'll check on it.
Company, sir.
What brings me this pleasant surprise,
Brigadier General?
As of today, we'll be taking over this
East HQ as our temporary central command.
May I ask what's wrong with the one in
Central, sir?
HA HA HA HA HA HA
I know, Mustang.
I asked the same thing.
Sorry for the hassle.
Everybody at ease now.
Fuhrer Bradley, welcome, sir.
Your job is not to ask questions,
Colonel.
The Fuhrer and his staff
will run this place, both to
operate as Central Command
and to observe the region.
I trust you'll make us comfortable.
Look at all those chains.
Those are for the Silver Pocket Watches.
They only give out to state alchemists,
aren't they?
Yeah.
Means every one of these guys is a full
-fledged alchemist.
Look, can you believe how big Alicia's
gotten?
She can even ride a tricycle now.
She follows me everywhere on that thing,
like my own escort of cuteness.
Yep, you're the same as ever, Major.
Nice and insane.
I've got more pictures.
Wanna see?
Maybe later, okay?
Anyway, if you knew this transfer was gonna
happen, you could have warned Mustang.
Not a chance!
I had to see the look on Roy's face.
Oh, by the way, I'm a Lieutenant Colonel
now.
Got me in charge of court martial
investigations.
Sounds fun-filled beyond belief.
Shouldn't you be in Central, then?
Why?
So I can work in a bunch of empty offices?
All the major bigwigs are fleeing
Central as fast as they... Never mind.
How's the search going for the,
uh... you know what stone?
Well, we're closer to where I'd like to
think we are.
Right now I'm looking for a guy named
Marco who might have answers for me.
But I can't get Mustang to tell me what
he's got on him.
Well, have you considered that he might
not have anything?
No.
Roy Mustang's hiding stuff from me.
I can definitely tell.
Did I hear you say the name Marco
Fullmetal?
Brigadier General Grand.
The Iron Blood Alchemist.
What do you want?
What do you want with Marco?
He's a filthy deserter.
Six years ago, a brigade
of State Alchemists
were called on to
neutralize the Eastern
Rebellion and Marco was in
their ranks.
But he went AWOL before the battle was
done.
The coward's been missing ever since.
A deserter?
Don't know him.
Sorry.
Dr. Marcoh?
Nope.
Not here.
Damn it.
Wouldn't you know it?
He's been erased from all the record
books.
Clearly Mustang knows, but he's not
talking.
I'll have to beat it out of him.
A fight?
You can get away with that.
Meow
Is your stomach purring?
Yes.
I mean, no.
I mean, you know it's still raining
outside.
Ed, I forgot to mention something earlier.
What with the pictures...
Get to the point!
Fine.
I will.
Rude little...
As I was saying, due to conditions,
your assessments will be held here,
Ed.
Assessments?
You mean to renew a State Alchemy
certification?
I'll tell you later about all your
options.
I've got it, Major!
Lieutenant Colonel!
Seriously, I know the perfect way to show
off my skills.
Right?
Oh, no.
Battle assessment?
Sounds weird.
Does the Army really do that?
Yeah, sometimes.
The alchemists go up
against each other in a mock
battle, and they're graded
on how they use their skills.
I just think it's weird Ed actually
requested it.
Yeah, and picking the Colonel.
That's a heck of an opponent to take by
choice.
Seriously, though.
Who do you think would win, if they were
both really giving their all?
Are you kidding?
It's gotta be the Flame!
I don't know.
You can't count out FullMetal,
either.
The Kid's a hero in this region.
Then again, when you think about all the
stories of Mustang during the Rebellion...
But why would Ed propose this to begin
with?
It's so risky.
I heard it was for a cat.
The conditions are that if Ed wins,
Mustang has to take care of it.
A cat?
I guess that's bad news for this guy.
I was hoping the Colonel would take him.
Sir?
Dog, huh?
I love dogs!
Really?
You mean it?
Of course!
Dogs embody loyalty.
They follow their master's commands above
all else.
Be a jerk to them and they don't complain,
and they never once beg for a paycheck.
Trust me, Fury, they're the great servants
of man!
Loyal canine Howie, salute thee!
Well, you're awfully manic today,
sir.
I figured that challenge would worry you
some.
Come on, the Fuhrer knows it wouldn't be
fair with me against the kid.
I'd love to show off my valor,
but there's no way he's going to allow it.
That sounds like a very interesting fight.
I'm going to allow the battle assessment.
But, Fuhrer... Fuhrer's
spoken, Colonel.
You can use the parade grounds.
That way you won't have to worry about all
the collateral damage.
What's wrong, Mustang?
You're sure of your own skills,
aren't you?
Go on.
Fight Fullmetal.
I think it's going to be a lot of fun.
You can't say I didn't try to protect the
kid.
But I'll dutifully obey
my orders, at least until I
become Fuhrer and every
one of them is obeying me.
Be more discreet about those declarations,
sir.
Some would call them treason.
She's right, Chief.
It's a presumptuous thing to say.
You got a death wish or something?
That's a stupid question, Havok.
I say it because it's true.
And when I'm Fuhrer, there will be
changes.
That day... All female officers will
be required to wear tiny miniskirts!
You're a miracle, Mustang.
I'll follow you for the rest of my life.
Yes.
Ladies and Gentlemen!
Welcome To the Easter
Command Center Festival!
A guaranteed break from that soldier
grind.
Incidentally, take a look.
My daughter, who turned three this year!
Isn't she adorable?
Oh, no!
Don't fall on Daddy!
Elicia!
Ow.
And now without further distraction,
we move directly to the day's main event.
In the red corner, the flame alchemist and
hero of the Eastern Rebellion...
Colonel Roy Mustang!
Give it up!
You just won a promotion.
Give me back, my girlfriend!
In the blue corner, the full metal
alchemist and living legend of the people.
Let's hear it for Edward Elric!
What?
Where?
I can't see him.
Walking gravestone is more like it.
Good luck, beansprout.
Don't call me small!
I'll break down your feet
and stick them on your head!
Okay, Al, you're right.
Today's a great day.
The day I beat Mustang's
pompous mug in front
of the whole army and
get some damn respect.
But we're indebted to him, brother.
He's asked for it.
Saying he knows all we do.
Acting like he let our secret out.
Then not telling me what I need to know.
So what's your strategy?
I told you, a fist in his face!
This assessment means nothing to me.
If I win, you tell me all you know about
Marcoh.
And let's not forget you'll have a new
cat.
Alchemist, get set...
Ready to fight!
What?
Too slow.
Damn it!
That was a cheap shot!
A soldier favors haste over cleverness.
Means there are no cheap shots,
Edward.
Strike quickly and you'll end it quickly,
too.
Those flames are coming out of nowhere.
How does he do that?
Oh, this is the first time you've seen the
Colonel fight?
His right glove's made of special material
called ignition cloth.
When he snaps, it makes a spark.
After that, he uses alchemy to change the
oxygen density in the air.
And, boom, bombs on command.
Just relax!
Stop running!
Sorry!
Well, I guess I can't torch you all.
This is hard.
He's such a small target.
Who are you calling small?
If your opponent is of
choleric temper, seek to
irritate and never fall
for an enemy's taunts.
You've gotta be kidding me!
Okay, maybe I overdid it.
Need more?
Damn.
Without that glove, you can't
make flames anymore, can you?
Advantage, Elric!
All war is deception.
Think your enemy has a weakness and it
becomes his strength.
Remember that.
Just end it.
You don't have to ask.
All right, that's far enough.
An excellent fight by two skilled
alchemists.
We are honored by your compliment,
Fuhrer.
Don't stop us now!
We're not done yet!
Hmph.
That may be true, but if
I let you go on, it would
be much harder for just
the two of you to clean up.
They don't have a choice but to spend time
together now.
The Fuhrer ordered them both to fix the
mess.
This is the reason I tried to avoid the
fight, Ed.
What happened?
Why did you hesitate at the end?
Huh?
I don't need anyone to cover for me.
If you had time to beat me, you should
have done it.
This goes back more years
than I care to admit, but
there was something
called the Ishbal Rebellion.
Part of the Eastern Rebellion,
right?
When the people of Ishbal  clashed with the
military.
I saw my share... of really terrible
things.
Dr. Marcoh, the deserter.
He was the smartest one among us.
I still think so, even now.
Is that why you kept quiet about him?
Out of respect?
But maybe I was wrong not to tell you.
You should pay him a visit, so you'll know
for yourself.
You mean he's alive?
You still haven't told me yet.
Why you hesitated and didn't finish me
when you could.
Never mind.
You don't have to say.
Well, if you've got no other candidates,
I guess I can handle him, Kane.
Really?
That's awesome!
Sorry,
guess he's just relieved to have an owner.
Now you won't be doing that again,
will you, Pup?
See, you've got a strict mommy now.
The bathroom's out here.
Got it, Black Hayate?
What's wrong with all you people?
About Lior, that desert town in Ed's
report.
Are you aware that General Hakuro's
detachment has been dispatched over there?
I hear it's turning into a pretty ugly
civil war.
Ed said their prophet,
Cornelo, had been removed
as a sham, and the people
would open their eyes.
But a priest is still there and going
strong.
And now he's calling his followers to this
uprising.
I can't say for sure if it's the same guy
who Ed fought, though.
You think you should send Ed in to
investigate?
Ed believes he saved that town.
It's one of the first successes he's had.
I'll let him keep thinking that for a
while.
He'll learn the truth soon enough.
We always do.
After all the info the
Colonel gave us on Marco,
we can't ask him to
keep this little guy, too.
Equivalent exchange, we'd end up owing too
much.
Yeah, I know.
I'm sorry, Al.
It's just the best we can do.
So, isn't it about time you told me?
I know you didn't all come here to observe
us.
The bigwigs.
They kept wearing the Fuhrer down until he
agreed to move us.
It's the alchemist killer, Roy.
There have already been five officer
slayings in Central.
You wont win!
They'll find you!
You're a barbarian!
Nothing more!
Time to head east.
Full Metal Alchemist Episode 14,
Destruction's Right Hand.
I don't care about your cause, even if
it's vengeance on all state alchemists.
I won't let you kill my brother.