Alright, how did it come to this?
How long are we going to stand around
doing nothing?
I thought we had a war to fight.
Hell if I know, man.
Of course there are bound to be a few stubborn
holdouts and Bradley loyalists who refuse to cooperate.
It'll no doubt be an arduous battle, but I will try
my hardest to keep the death toll to a minimum.
We're reversing course and moving back
towards Central immediately.
You can't be serious.
Together we'll boldly lead our divisions
in storming Central headquarters.
You mean staging a coup?
You think we'll betray our Führer just
like that?
The Führer has betrayed us by making immoral decisions
while allowing those around him to manipulate his judgment.
We are acting for the good of the state.
But, sir, is there proof to these charges?
Proof?
Your proof is right here!
See this body, flawlessly sculpted in
service of our state?
Feel how they pulse with loyalty,
how solid and serious they are?
Feel how?
If you don't believe me, they'll make
you believe!
Feel!
The Philosopher's Stone.
Those who possess it, no longer bound by
the laws of equivalent exchange and
alchemy, may gain without sacrifice,
create without equal exchange.
We searched for it.
And we found it.
Mommy?
I've started a chain reaction that's
transforming your liquid body into ethanol.
Nicely done, sweetheart.
Clean up after yourselves and take care of
each other.
Edward!
Alphonse!
Winry, is that you?
What are you doing here?
Did something bad happen?
I came cause I was worried about you,
but I see that you finally beat her.
You are not Winry Rockbell.
Alphonse, you're the one I've always
loved!
Well, that was easy.
You're too late!
I am the Philosopher's Stone!
Yeah, that's what I've heard.
Why don't I give the new you a test drive?
Now that you've become the stone, let's
see how much your cute little seal job can take.
Leave my brother alone, you bastard!
I know how you love being protective.
But you don't have to blow a gasket,
I'm just taking him back to my master.
Your master?
That must be the one Lust talked about.
She said this master's only using you to
get the Philosopher's Stone and achieve
immortality without concern for you
Homunculi.
Who cares?
And you shouldn't speak so impersonally.
You and my master go way back.
Your master knew about our mom's
Homunculus from the start.
Sought her out and fed her red stones so
she'd live.
Who else would do that
except... Don't say it, Ed!
Dad would never do that!
Never!
We've talked enough.
Hey, I'm on your side, remember?
You're supposed to be tackling that
half-pine over there!
But he can do anything now, can't he?
Sorry, kid, but this toy isn't for you to
play with.
He could bring Mommy back!
You have to let me try!
You have to!
Give it a rest, mama's boy!
This is all because of you.
It's your fault that Mommy's gone!
Easy!
Mommy!
She was your mommy, too, and you killed
her!
Stop it!
This has nothing to do with you!
If there's anyone you should want to kill,
it should be me, my child.
No, you're not my mom!
You're absolutely nothing to me!
Teacher!
Are you okay?
He was... crying.
While I can't even squeeze out a single
tear.
That poor kid's crying like a baby.
Like he... he was crying because I
couldn't.
Enough.
Let's find Al.
I can't do much in this shape,
but I could sure as hell be a crutch.
Now, where to?
Brother, can we go?
Okay, but aren't these central bookstores
great?
I've never even heard of some of these
books.
Whoa.
I've been looking for this forever.
I hope we get to see Ed and Al.
Either pay or get out.
Crap.
If I spend all our money here,
we won't have anything left for a hotel.
But if I don't buy these books now,
I may never have another chance.
Start a tab.
No can do.
We're a specialty store that caters to State Alchemists,
and only they can establish lines of credit with us.
They're the only ones who can understand
these anyway.
Uh...
Then it's a good thing I am, in fact,
a State Alchemist.
Huh?
Guess you don't recognize me.
Brother!
So this is the infamous Edward Elric?
Yeah, the little traitor told me himself.
He's the Fullmetal Alchemist.
Wait a minute!
You've got the wrong guy!
I was just borrowing his identity to get
some books!
Yeah, tell it to the people at
headquarters.
Our orders are to bring you and your
brother there for detainment.
Brother, what's happening?
Just get out of here!
It's the younger brother!
Grab him before he runs!
Get back here!
Hold him!
Stay still!
Stop it!
Was the younger brother always this small?
Yeah, I'm pretty sure.
What'd you do this time, brother?
I don't think I like Central very much.
Lust.
Did you seal one of the Homunculi in that
circle?
I didn't do this one.
It must have been...
Regardless, this means there are four of
them left.
The child.
The one who eats everything.
The one who can morph into anyone.
And the Führer.
And one more.
The one who controls them all.
Who's there?
Look, Nina.
That's your friend Ed there.
Edward, your friend.
Say hello, dear.
Don't be shy.
Even with the stone, he couldn't make her
soul.
Why don't you play in the courtyard?
I bet Alexander's lonely.
Which reminds me.
Where is that dog?
Where's Alexander gone?
Some watchdog, huh?
And you're fine with this?
That soulless doll is the embodiment of
his sins.
Just like Sloth represented my sin.
And Wrath yours.
Don't worry, Nina.
Daddy will keep you safe.
You've really grown up, Edward.
Crap, grown up?
I thought I'd grown up when I was
certified as a State Alchemist.
But obviously, I still had a long way to
go from there.
So what do we do now?
Well, as I see it, there's only one of the
Homunculi left that we can account for.
And we know where to find.
I take it you're talking about the big
one, Führer Bradley.
What's taking so long?
Quit dragging your feet!
We're completely surrounded.
And there are fewer soldiers cooperating
with us than we hoped.
Well, don't tell me you're surprised.
The Führer's rule has made the army
powerful.
There aren't many officers who will want
to betray him.
Looks like the newly appointed Brigadier
General finally made a wrong move.
Not at all.
Mustang's real plan is for us to create a standoff,
forcing them to come to us, leaving Central undefended.
We're going to have to dig in.
But I can't do this!
How am I supposed to lead our troops in
fending off a major siege?
I'm just a freaking Lieutenant!
You have nothing to worry about.
I'll be with you every step of the way.
Though I must say, the two of you have
never looked better.
Lieutenant Havok, you're supposed to be in
bed.
You good at keeping secrets, sweetheart?
General Mustang, what's this about?
Some kind of secret mission?
Yes, in fact, it is.
So keep your mouth shut, okay?
Can you do that?
Of course.
What are you so angry about now?
I'm not angry.
Just leave it alone.
It looks like Havok and company are
holding up their end of the plan.
Yeah.
Hurry up, men!
Let's look alive!
We have to catch up to Mustang's mutinous
brigade by nightfall, so step two!
I'm impressed you could assemble such a
fine expeditionary force on such short notice.
Why, thank you, but I couldn't have done
it without your advice.
How were you able to anticipate this
treasonous insurrection, sir?
That Mustang and Armstrong
would turn on you as soon as they
were given new stars for their
lapels and troops to command?
At least now we know their true character and that
they were up to no good all along, just like Basque Grand.
Well, you see, I had to make it seem as
though I trusted Mustang.
That's why I promoted him to Brigadier
General.
I'm sure you weren't pleased with that
promotion at the time.
I trusted your judgment.
And believe me, sir, I'll have this
mission done in no time.
So, can I punch out for the day?
Oh?
You arrested a couple of kids calling
themselves the Elric brothers this morning?
Well, let's see.
Yes, I think you'd better execute them.
Why did you have to pretend to be Ed
again?
What else could I have done?
We're broke.
But we have to get out and go see them and
give them the page from Dad's journal.
Quick, hide it!
Thanks a lot.
You've outdone yourself.
No problem.
And since this job is for the Führer himself,
I made sure to finish it as fast as possible.
So everything's exactly like this
blueprint?
Oh yeah, I followed every detail,
just like you told me.
There's just one thing that struck me as a
little odd.
Usually you'd want a wine cellar to be...
Yeah, I don't get it either.
I just gave you the instructions that I
got from the Führer's secretary.
I'm filling in for her while she's on
vacation.
Since I asked you to do such a quick job, I
threw in a special thank you for your hard work.
Oh, is that so?
These thank yous are putting my kid
through college.
The construction is all finished, and if I
have my dates right, he's going home today.
Something wrong?
It says here the Elric brothers were
arrested this morning.
Shouldn't you have checked if Bradley was
here before we invaded?
Oh sure, it's my fault!
How was I supposed to know he'd go home
early for his kid's birthday?
There they are!
Quit making excuses!
Let it go!
I know they came around the corner.
Where'd they go?
I hope you're not injured, Fullmetal.
It's you guys, the impostors!
I have a name, Russell Tringham!
They were arrested because the MPs thought
they were you and your brother.
I honestly don't know how they get
confused.
You're only about half as tall as I am.
What did you say?!
Is it me or did you shrink since we last
met?
But brother, none of this would have happened
if you didn't keep pretending to be Ed.
Without even hesitating, the Führer
ordered them to be Executed.
We thought that was too extreme a
sentence, so we went to talk to them ourselves.
And then you helped them escape when we
burst in and caused all this noise.
They're here somewhere!
We'll hurry up and find them!
In all seriousness, it was good seeing you
again, but we have to get going now.
Where to?
We're going to pay the Führer a little
house call.
We have no other choice.
Oh yeah, I almost forgot!
Take this.
It's an excerpt from our father's old
journal.
There's some information about Central
that you might want.
Teacher!
This means...
But you can't be....
Lieutenant Colonel Archer
Edward Elric and the woman who escaped
from South Headquarters.
I've been looking for you.
Leave the tank head to me.
You go to the place mentioned in that
journal.
Teacher... If you're going to keep
calling me that, then do what I say.
Now go!
You boys get out of here too!
It looks like the Elric brothers won't be
needing us to bail them out today after all.
I knew they wouldn't let themselves get
caught without a reason.
Those boys are smarter than that.
We'd better move.
Hey!
I need your car!
Well, I'll be damned.
Mustang...
Did you come here to capture us too?
Then where were you headed when you ran
into me, General?
The Wog District.
That's where the Führer has his private
estate.
Going to wish his kid a happy birthday?
I gotcha it's top secret.
But you should know they'll be ready for
you.
Armstrong staged a coup for me on the
Northern Front.
The Führer would never imagine that I'd be
right back here under his nose in Central.
I thought you were all about following orders and
kissing ass so you could become Führer one day.
Wait a minute.
That's not fair.
You became a military dog too so you could
chase your own goals.
So don't go... Take it easy.
The end justifies the means when it comes
to achieving my ultimate goal.
Back then, that just seemed like the right
stance for me to take.
You realize there'll be no justification in the
eyes of the public if you go against the Führer.
Even if you pull this off, you'll never be
allowed to succeed him with your reputation.
The masses won't hear of it.
That may be, but even so... I can't
let him get away with what he's done.
So you're doing all this to avenge Hughes?
You got it.
He must have known what was going on in
the military and that's why he was killed.
And for that, you're willing to throw away
everything you've worked for your entire career?
Without a second thought.
Not so different from you, is it?
Selflessly giving up your status as State
Alchemist for your brother's sake.
Like adults, we swallowed the crap they
fed us and now we're throwing it all aside.
Funny.
Us both trying to live out our dreams.
Like children.
I can't let you come with me.
Even after I became a soldier,
war still seemed like something that
happened in a far-off land where I
couldn't see it.
Where someone else fought and died.
It didn't seem real.
I thought war had nothing to do with me.
But now that I've learned there's someone
who's willing to start war, who's going to.
start war just for the stone... I know that as long as
there are people who seek the
stones forbidden power that bloodshed
will keep happening.
And I know the desire for that power lurks
somewhere in all of us.
The Homunculi may throw fuel on the fire of war, but didn't
the desire to bring back people that we love create them?
And if they're nothing more than products
of our hearts and minds, no matter how
pure our intentions, then there will never be a war
that isn't at least in some part caused by all of us.
Never.
But you're thinking on too large a scale
there, kid.
If we don't want to drive ourselves crazy, each of
us can only deal with what's directly in front of us.
But what's in front of me is to defeat the
one the Homunculi call their master.
After that, I'll destroy the Philosopher's
Stone once and for all, so its whole
existence will be permanently erased from
mankind's memory.
And no one will ever hunger for its power
again.
Wait, destroy?
So I take it that means the Philosopher's
Stone has been completed.
I'm guessing it's the one Scar was working
on.
In the end, it wasn't just Scar who forged
the Philosopher's Stone.
It was in our own hearts, all of us.
But wasn't that your dream all along?
To one day use the stone to get back what
you and your brother lost?
All of that would mean nothing if it came
at the expense of so much pain.
Then there's something more important than
that?
Even when our eyes are closed,
there's a whole world out there that lives
outside ourselves and our dreams.
Goodbye, Fullmetal.
Goodbye, General.
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 49,
The Other Side of the Gate.
On the night of September 2nd,
1916 AD, 16 demons clouded the skies over London.