Now, come with me, my Alphonse.
I know it must have hurt, the doctor using
you like that, but you're going to be fine.
See?
It's just like when
you were little.
Mom..
Yes.
Mommy...
Mommy.
The Philosopher's Stone.
Those who possess it, no longer bound by
the laws of equivalent exchange and alchemy.
They gain without sacrifice,
create without equal exchange.
We searched for
it, and we found it.
Please, let me try it again.
I know I can fix her.
Please, Al.
You've already gotten what
you wished for, Dr. Tucker.
Brother...
I should have known.
Step away right now.
Brother, you don't understand.
Yeah, she got to me too, Al.
But it's lies.
She's not our mother.
I know what she is, alright, but still...
She's using our memories to manipulate us.
Period.
That thing doesn't have a soul.
You weren't always
so cruel, Edward, dear.
Please, Al.
Once more.
Tucker.
You could have killed Al
by bringing him here alone.
The stone has
equivalency, after all.
He used it, Ed.
And this is what it took.
So he tricked you into
coming here and then did this?
Damn it, there's so many
idiots whose asses I have to kick!
I'll have to start carrying a list
just to keep track of them all!
Come on, Al.
Let's get moving.
You don't need to worry, Edward.
Why?
You planning to bring my brother
back to his real body for me?
Or are you just gonna bring him back to
your master and use him till there's nothing left?
Al, step away!
Don't be stupid, Al!
Edward, you're hurting me.
Nice try, but I know it takes
more than that to kill you!
Your mother was talking to you.
What is this?
It's the same array that was at
Dante's house when I killed Greed.
It's designed to
seal a Homunculus!
Isn't it!
That's very clever of you, but
you're going to need more than that.
Oh, don't worry, I know.
The remains of
the human that died.
The one the transmutation that
created you was supposed to bring back.
It can cripple you.
Brother, what is that?
She's our fake mom, Al.
This is her weakness.
The real thing.
What?
You dug up her grave
without even telling me?
What's wrong with you?
In case you didn't notice,
we're fighting for our lives!
Give it up, sloth.
You're not going to be able to
dissolve this transmutation circle.
I made sure to carve it
out especially deep for you.
Thanks.
I owe you one.
I hope you don't believe I did
all this for the locket Fullmetal.
Lust, how could you betray our master?
Betray?
That's an interesting
word for you to use, Sloth.
What are you two talking about?
Memories.
Of the people we were.
They're subtle,
but they're real.
It took me a long time
to understand what I saw.
Books say we shouldn't
have memories.
Or if we do, it's only the emotions of
the alchemist who made us that we see.
But they're wrong.
Those memories are mine.
I was... I was an Ishbalan
woman deep in love.
No, you weren't.
Sloth remembers.
But she's let our master fool
her into not caring about her sons.
She's not our mom!
Or maybe she really is,
but she's not yet complete.
What the hell are you doing?
Just stay down, Ed!
I'm not gonna let
you do this to her!
Don't you understand?
If we don't get rid of them, they're
just gonna keep hunting you down!
Mom's remains
paralyzed this Homunculus.
That proves what she is
absolutely, and where she came from.
We created her that day.
Right.
She's a Homunculus.
We know.
Homunculi are born when an
Alchemist goes against the laws of nature.
Whether she has a soul or
not, it's our fault she exists!
Exactly my point!
She's our responsibility!
Which is why we're the
ones who have to kill her!
No!
Damn it, Al!
Don't worry.
I'll do the work.
No.
You can't do this.
You had better go fetch
those remains, Fullmetal.
We're running out of time.
You were using this to
hurt Mom, weren't you?
Your mom?
WWrath, you've got a serious
case of confusion, you know?
I'm not confused at all, Edward.
I'm just taking away
everything that was yours.
That creature in there
isn't my mother, either.
I think you're the
one that's confused.
Hand it over.
What are you doing to Mom?
Mom?
Funny, that's what I said.
But it turns out that he wants a mother
so bad, he's picked himself out a new one!
Get away from her!
You were good to stick
up for your mother, Al.
Hey!
Al!
Go.
I've got WWrath.
Now, don't you think you're
too old to be crying for Mommy?
You can't win.
I'll just keep
coming back to life.
Oh, that's only as long
as the stones are in you.
Didn't you know?
And I can soon change that.
I'll just rip them out of her
belly, one death at a time.
I'll get my way!
I'm going to become him!
And what exactly
is the point in that?
What do you mean?
It's the whole
point of everything!
Why should I exist if
I'm a creature like you?
Using you was a
mistake from the start.
And why is that lust?
Because I can use Alchemy?
Or did you forget that detail?
Al!
NO!
Hey!
I'm sorry!
It's not me!
We can't do this, Al.
Even brushing against
you could cause a reaction!
Yes, that seems to be true.
You'll have to leave us alone.
Please Mom, stop!
Stop!
When are you going to accept it?
She's not Mom!
Mom wouldn't talk this way!
She wouldn't use
you as a shield!
And she wouldn't
hurt her own son.
Ed, what are you doing?
Since your brother can't touch you,
he's trying to use a transmutation circle.
But I won't give him
time to finish one.
Are you okay?
I need you to fight
against her, Al!
Now!
This is what you
wanted, isn't it?
To be a human so
you could die with them.
Maybe you are right.
Where did I come from?
And where will I go when I die?
Maybe all this time...
That is what I wanted.
The freedom to find out.
Is that all being human means?
That you can die?
Then why do I want
to become one so bad?
Well, can't you answer me?
You are human, right?
Mommy.
That's right, that's a reason to live.
Protecting her.
Al, I'm sorry for all this.
No, I'm the one who's sorry.
Listen, I better go
make sure Lust is okay.
No!
Stop!
Help me, Alphonse.
It's your responsibility.
Edward, I saw you that night.
There there, my dear.
Eat.
Yes.
When I heard she died, I
knew it would come to this.
After all, they are the
sons of Hohenheim.
There.
Our monster is starting
to look presentable.
Now, Envy, when you were
first born, you were no better off.
I saw... children.
There was a country house.
And a man.
Laundry on the line.
We were happy there.
But also very sad.
What does it mean?
When you're
human, you will know.
Human?
That's why we need to find
the Philosopher's Stone, dear.
So you can start your life.
I think I'll entrust
her to you, Pride.
There's a deceased woman from the military
whose records I've already altered to explain Ishbal.
Perhaps we could
use her identity again.
Good point.
Your beautiful wife would be jealous
if you brought this little angel home.
Right, Sloth?
Yes, that will be her role.
Our Sloth.
She's accelerating
the cells in her body.
She's generating
her own heat source.
Please, Edward.
Stop trying to play
this dumb mom card!
You don't even have memories!
Yes, I do.
What Lust said was true.
Maybe it's just your own feelings and
wants that were etched into my being.
But either way, I do have them.
You're lying!
Then why would you attack us?
To be free.
These memories are the driving force in
everything I do because they feel like chains.
I remember being a mother
with endless devotion.
Now I have none.
It's a fraudulent persona
that's been forced on me.
And I don't have the
energy to assume it.
That's why I have to kill you.
So I can prove this identity is false, because
no real mother would kill her own sons.
As long as you children are alive, these memories
will torment me, trying to make me into this human.
They are at war
with my real self.
And they could win.
In time, I might even
come to love you two.
And how can I allow that?
I should always hate
you for creating me.
Brother, what are we
supposed to do with her?
It's like we both said,
she's our responsibility!
Mom!
The final proof is coming soon.
When you see how little I care.
Brother, what happened?
Mom!
I transmuted my automail into
sodium just as it punctured her.
The chemical reaction with
her body made her explode.
Mom, no!
Cut it out.
She's nobody's mother.
Face it, Wrath.
It's over.
Mommy!!!!
You actually think
I'd die so easily?
You don't understand me at all.
Mom!
I want you to
wait outside, Wrath.
I won't!
I never want to lose you again!
He fused himself with her.
And bind Homunculi.
Wrath...
You fool.
You shouldn't be
so impulsive, Wrath.
Did you already forget about
taking those remains into your body?
And now that you're part
of her, she can't even move.
And I can just take my time to
recompose her into a different element.
What do you mean?
Alchemy on a living structure?
You don't know how to do that.
It's something I
learned fighting greed.
I reworked his body's
chemistry to create a weakness.
And this wasn't like Kimbley's technique where
he'd just manipulate a few components in the blood.
I altered the makeup
of Greed's entire body.
Homunculi are more
malleable than humans.
It's their strength
and their demise.
Mommy?
What did you do?
I'll kill you if you hurt her!
Step away.
That's my advice, Wrath.
Mommy?
I've started a chain reaction that's
transforming her liquid body into ethanol.
She's going to evaporate.
Disappear into the air.
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 48,
Goodbye.
To all my friends and those I love, I'm
sorry, but this is the path I've chosen.