I'm sorry to have to bother
you with this, Colonel, but here.
This comes directly
from Ed Elric.
An invoice?
He wants Eastern Headquarters
to reimburse him for everything.
Hospitalization, medication,
travel, and other assorted expenses.
Junk food.
Literature.
And an awful lot of unexplained
receipts from toy stores.
And now where are they?
A trip.
They're searching for a different
method to restore their bodies.
They'll contact us when
they're ready, Colonel, sir.
Sorry.
I'm asking where they went!
Colonel, look here.
Take me to the Elrics right now!
They're gone.
Where are they?
Just who... Who are you?
Hey.
Huh.
Good job, honey.
Let's go.
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
I can't believe it!
Rush Valley!
Perfect!
It's the latest design
for Roomie Studios!
I didn't think it'd be here!
Look at the size of that rock!
Will you buy it for me, please?
Oh, you bet, baby!
It's perfect!
The latest design
from God's Auto Mail!
And will you look at the
precision of those lines?
I have to have it!
Oh, that is so cool!
Oh, that's so cool!
Let me try it on.
You can't.
And why not?
A high-powered culverin's a
weapon that's meant for a fighter's arm.
A young girl like
you has no use for it.
Oh, am I stooping low.
This place is a real dump.
Pops, give me the
strongest piece you've got.
I just inherited a fortune from my
dead grandma, so money's no object.
Don't ignore a paying customer.
Hey, what you got there?
That looks pretty awesome.
Wrap it up.
It's sold.
Not to you.
I only make Automail as a necessity,
not as a rich kid's toy.
Isn't my money as
good as some cripple's?
You don't need this weapon,
kid, and you never will.
You're right, I don't need this.
Not from a washed-up
chump like you.
I don't know what I was thinking coming
into this second-rate junk shop to begin with.
Your stuff's all crap.
Step right up!
Rush Valley's famous Automail
arm wrestling competition returns!
The entry fees are measly 10,000 cens,
and if you can beat the reigning champ,
you win the jackpot!
Come on up!
Don't miss your chance!
Excuse me.
I want a piece of that.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have a challenger!
This should be good.
Ready... fight!
Brother, was that...?
Yeah.
Ready... fight!
Guess it's to be expected.
Hey, little girl.
You sure you want to do
this with that piece of junk?
If it was made by that old man, she'd probably
have a better chance just using her real arm.
I want to see a
good, clean fight!
Ready... fight!
Very Close.
If you want, I'll give you the
name of a good mechanic.
Is there no one else who
dares to challenge the champ?
What about you, sir?
Sure, you look big and strong,
but how'd you like to prove it?
You mean me?
No.
No, thank you.
That's too bad.
What about...
No, I couldn't possibly ask this
shrimp to take on the champ.
I'm not a shrimp!
Whoa, you're a pretty
feisty shrimp, aren't you?
But it looks like you salvaged that
Automail from the bottom of a scrap heap.
Alphonse, let go
of your brother.
Yes, ma'am.
Edward if you lose, I'll kick your ass!
Wrestlers, take your stances.
Ready... fight!
I forget.
Now whose Automail
belongs in a scrap heap?
Take that!
510,000 cens!
I can hardly believe it!
It's perfect!
Now you can buy me all those new
Automail parts I've been looking at!
You know, it made
me really happy.
Yeah?
What did?
Never mind.
You guys again.
Yeah, thanks a lot
for humiliating us.
Now give us back the money, unless
you want Jumbo here to get angry.
No way!
This is ours!
We won it fair and square!
Yeah, right!
I know for a fact that little
shrimp cheated us to win!
Huh?
Ha!
You've used alchemy to
cheat people out of their money!
And you used it to cheat back!
Alchemy, Ed?
Is that true?
Yeah.
Did you know about this?
What?
Yeah.
Oh.
Edward?
Yeah.
Winry!
That hurt.
Hey!
What do you think you're doing?
Brother!
You're such a jerk!
Colonel, I've brought
you Major Armstrong.
Let's keep this low-key.
We've investigated
around the clock.
We believe we know the identities
of Brigadier General Hughes' killers.
Then why haven't
you arrested them?
We're not sure
where they're hiding.
Though we have our suspicions.
I want the names.
I can't.
This is a direct command from
an officer who outranks you.
I'm sorry, sir.
Forget it.
Just leave.
Yes, sir.
Some help?
Actually, he was.
He specifically said the
identities of Hughes' killers.
Meaning there's more
than one responsible.
I ordered him to speak.
The fact he couldn't is a clear
sign that someone who outranks
me must have told him to keep
his mouth shut about this case.
You combine that with what Lieutenant
Ross reported about Ed claiming to have given
up on the Stone and not wanting the
military to know where he was going.
I think someone high up has a dangerous
interest in the Philosopher's Stone.
Does that mean...
For now, Lieutenant,
we'll stay in the dark.
I can't believe
Winry's not back yet.
You know, it was wrong to
use alchemy in that contest.
Well, I only did it because
those con men were cheating.
Yeah, but...
Did you hurt your arm?
I saw you there.
In the wrestling match.
Yeah...
Can I sit down?
Sure.
Your legs.
So they're Automail as well?
Yeah, they are.
How'd you know?
Lucky for you, I'm a Mechanic.
You really banged
your arm up, huh?
Yeah.
Let me see it.
Impressive.
The structure's so
simple, yet effective.
It's very efficient.
The suspension feels
a bit out of whack here.
And the cylinder
must have gotten bent.
You really know your stuff.
Whoever made this is obviously
talented and more familiar with it than I am.
You should have them take a
look at it as soon as possible.
You're right.
I know I should, but...
So, how did it happen?
What?
Oh.
There was a train wreck.
That was the mechanic?
Yeah.
Dominic took me into his home and
custom made this Automail for me.
That's all the more reason
to get him to fix your arm.
He cares about you.
I guess you got a good point.
I don't get it.
Why are you so
reluctant to ask him?
Because then I'll have to tell
him I lost in that big contest.
I can't do that.
The only reason I entered that stupid
thing was to prove his Automail was the best.
Well, I've got it.
All you need is some other way to show
everyone what your Automail is capable of.
Yeah.
Easier said than done.
What if you could show up a State Alchemist
who also happens to be the reigning champ now?
Wouldn't that prove beyond a doubt
how awesome your equipment is?
And how can I pull that one off?
Don't worry.
You have me.
Paninya, what are
you doing here?
Hello, Dominic.
Hi.
It's a real pleasure
to meet you, sir.
I'm Winry Rockbell,
visiting from Risembool.
I'm an Automail Mechanic, too.
Did you say you're a
Rockbell out of Risembool?
Are you related to Pinako,
the leopardess of Risembool?
I can still hear that
bone-chilling laugh!
You knew my grandmother?
What happened to your arm?
Nothing.
Do what you want.
Where the hell'd she go?
I'm not sure we'll
ever see her again.
She must have spent
the night outside.
Hey!
Good.
I found you.
You found us?
We looked for you everywhere.
Sorry.
Guess I did lose
my temper yesterday.
Hi there, fellas.
You're the girl
from that contest.
Her name's Paninya, and she
was nice enough to let me
stay at
her place last night.
Really?
So, uh, Edward.
Yeah?
Can I see your pocket
watch for a second?
And why should I do that?
Please?
Okay.
But you can only look this time.
Thanks a lot!
What are you doing?
It's you against her.
If you can snap your precious watch back from her
before she makes it to the pawn shop, then you win.
Hehehe.
Come and get it, little man,
if you think you can take me.
What the hell?
Winry!
Better run if you don't want
that watch to get hawked.
And no cheating this time.
Brother!
Winry!
Why would you do that?
It's simple.
I want Ed to gain some
appreciation for good Automail.
Get back here!
Give me back my watch!
Having trouble keeping
up with me, are ya?
Keep on dreamin'!
Dammit, she's
like a freakin' cat!
You know, when you can't win using
your legs, there's always alchemy!
Screw you!
Whoops.
All right, I played
your stupid game.
Now give me my watch!
Nah.
I got somethin' else for ya.
Maybe she went
a little overboard.
What?
I sure hope I
didn't... kill him.
Let's see... where am I?
Damn you!
You okay?
I'd feel better if I won.
I've got no idea what you
were tryin' to prove by that.
But you weren't gonna beat me.
I've got the best
Automail in the world!
I wanted to show how incredible Dominic's
Automail is so he can get the respect he deserves.
It looks pretty
incredible to me.
You misguided child.
Hello, sir.
You don't have to prove
anything to anyone.
You understand?
Yeah, but...
Take note.
Automail is more than
nuts and bolts and machinery.
It's your arm and your legs.
It doesn't matter what
anyone else thinks about it.
I honestly thought I raised you to
know that fact for yourself, Paninya.
I get it.
You build Automail as an extension of the person's
soul, and in time, it becomes a part of who they are.
It's really true.
When I could finally stand up again, I felt
complete for the first time in a long while.
I'm begging you,
Colonel, please.
You have to find the monster that did this to
Lieutenant Cur-I mean Brigadier General Hughes.
I'll do anything I can to help.
The military's investigation into the death of
Maes Hughes has been officially suspended.
But that's why you should
use your power to reopen it!
I see that you're working as
tirelessly as always, Colonel Mustang.
It's good to see
you, General Hakuro.
If the rumors are true, we'll be
seeing a lot more of each other.
Of course, rumors alone
won't get you back into Central.
If you support my transfer, General, I
pledge to serve you with all my heart
and soul, and I'd be honored
to work under your leadership.
I must say I'm liking
your attitude, Mustang.
Excuse me!
I'm on my way to the top.
You coming with me?
You know the answer to that.
Well, it was nice meeting you.
Say hi to Winry for me!
Hey, Ed.
You asleep yet?
No.
You know, I think you may have grown
an inch or two since the last time I saw you.
People do that.
At this rate, you'll probably
outgrow your arm and leg soon.
Want to go back to Risembool
so I can make new ones?
Let me think about it.
Nah, I think I'll pass for now.
But why?
Haven't you been satisfied
with my Automail, Ed?
I promise to make
the next even better.
I've been studying hard, so it'll be just as
top of the line as any of the big city dealers.
So...
What do you say?
Oh, Winry.
Your Automail's the best.
Really.
It's just that we're still trying to
get our bodies back to normal.
We have to.
Brother!
You're not gonna
believe who's here!
Full Metal Alchemist
Episode 27, Teacher.
I'm sorry, Teacher.
She was our mother.
What could we do?