Will you drop this
stupid routine?
I've told you
everything we know!
Sorry, sir.
The orders from Lieutenant
Colonel Archer were very clear.
This isn't a time for protocol!
They've got my brother, dammit!
The Crimson Alchemist, Zolf J.
Kimbley, and the Sewing
Life Alchemist, Shou Tucker.
A pair of infamous ghosts.
I've held my end of the bargain.
How about you?
You don't have to worry.
Neither do you, Doctor.
I'll guarantee
safety for you both.
See, you're under the
protection of Frank Archer now.
Protection?
That's right.
I'm reinstating you into the
military to continue research.
But this time, you'll be
working directly under me.
You'll let me finish my work?
Yes.
I'll be changing my orders.
Tell the troops not
to take prisoners.
Kill anyone who
looks suspicious.
I want this place cleaned.
But, sir, they're civilians.
Are you sure that's okay?
It is now.
Now that Tucker's on our side, those creatures
can be replaced and not even Greed can stop me.
As long as I have this.
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Be smart.
Like hell!
Greed, move!
Right.
My name is Alex Louis
Armstrong. Air to the family trade.
But you can call me
the Strongarm Alchemist.
Major!
My demands are simple.
You give Alphonse Elric to me.
Sloth is quite the slave driver.
Ruthless to the bone.
Oh well.
It is her fault that Greed
slipped away in the first place.
Guess she has no choice.
Okay.
It's your move, Greed.
What next?
Damn!
Behold!
A little sample of the artistic alchemy that's been
passed down the Armstrong line for generations.
Well, obviously I'll need more
than this to stand a chance.
Maybe some real muscle instead.
I'm not sure what to say.
It's been too long since
I've had this good of a battle.
I'd expect nothing less
from you, Armstrong.
Your strength hasn't
changed at all from back then.
I served as a soldier on assignment
in Ishbal during the campaign.
I know your talents well.
A former comrade?
Well then I certainly
don't want to kill you.
Surrender now and live.
An impossible request.
It's us, Major.
Step aside.
We'll take him.
Come on now, don't
waste your lives.
All right.
I'll gladly take that advice.
But pass a message to
Kimbley and Tucker, will you?
Tell them both they've
just wasted theirs.
They finally quieted down.
He was being a real
noisy pain in the ass earlier.
Yeah, well I guess he
finally got tired of whining.
That's better for us.
You can say that again.
So we're the only
ones who got away.
What the hell am I gonna do now?
How long did you
think you could last?
It's been a thrill,
but time's up.
And who might you be?
From what I've been told,
you've already met Gluttony.
As for me... well, can't
you tell I'm the new Lust?
You don't say.
I don't usually like to be so quick about
things, but you have two options, Greed.
You can either be sealed
again... or you can die right here.
Who's gonna pull that one off?
Don't tell me it's you.
Here's a story.
A lowly Homunculus actually tries to
defy the person who pulls all the strings...
and is locked in a
cell for 140 years.
When he escapes,
that person gets angry...
and gives us everything
we need... to end it.
End it!
There's no time to talk, kid.
Just cooperate.
Make sure Marta's safe.
But what are you guys gonna do?
Wait, Law!
Dorochet, what's happening?
Get out of here, Greed.
Now.
We'll take care of this.
It's my problem.
Well, it's ours now.
We're not going
to lose you here.
Just see that we're all avenged.
That's all I'm asking for.
My, you sure have some
loyal pawns, don't you?
You can blame it on the
Alchemists who engineered me.
I was combined with a dog.
Loyalty just runs in the blood.
Greed gave us hope for nothing.
Now we'll return the deed.
Greed, now!
Come on!
Okay.
And what did they
combine you with?
You may run for it if
you wish, Dorochet.
You know that.
Sure I could.
And I'd get away, too.
But after all that talking,
I'd sure look like a fool.
Then you're at peace with this?
You're asking me now?
Hold on.
That's right over Dante's house.
Just us now.
You're such a good
little hostage, Alphonse.
You could have
just fled, you know.
I've been a little distracted.
That's not what I'm
worried about now.
Yeah, right.
Hey, listen, Marta.
Yeah?
Stay in this can till morning.
If I'm not back by then,
you're on your own.
Just make sure
you have some fun.
Okay?
Greed, what are you gonna do?
Can't get into it, doll.
The talking's done.
Wait!
Let me out, kid!
No!
I gotta go with him!
Stop!
He told me to stay in
this thing where it's safe!
I don't care!
After all of this time, I'm back
at the beginning of the tale.
Not even sure
what I came here for.
Maybe I'm gonna
beg that hag for my life.
Maybe not.
That's a good boy, Greed.
It all happened
exactly as we were told.
Are we done?
Yes.
I'd say we performed perfectly.
I'm still hungry!
Where's the old lady?
The reason you
came here is simple.
Because these are the grounds
that witnessed your creation.
Smart girl.
Those are... Your bones, yes.
Hey, where the hell
did you get those?
And what did Dante tell you?
Lady Dante is over there.
What's going on here?
Who are you?
How could you know?
How could you make that array?
You're just a damn kid.
Could it be...
That's alchemy.
My life...
That's my life!
You...
Dammit.
I found you, Greed.
What the hell?
Explain this, Greed.
What happened here?
Beats me.
I was going to
ask you that, kid.
You did this to her, didn't you?
Are you gonna answer me?
Blame me if you want.
I really don't care.
How could you?
She was helpless.
Tell me, Edward Elric, how could you
go so far to protect your little brother?
And what does that
have to do with anything?
Feelings can be hard to explain.
What are you talking about?
What have you done with Al?
If you want him back, come on.
You know what it takes.
Let me go! I need a help!
No!
You still don't understand
what you're dealing with, do you?
Didn't you say that I was a mistake
that you were going to correct?
This is the last
time I'll say it.
If you really want to stop
me... I'd best be ready to kill.
I know.
And you think you're
ready for that, kid?
Remind me to thank
my mechanic, would you?
Even though it's busted to
hell, it still functions just fine.
Let's go!
Your alchemy's worth nothing
when you're fighting me!
Now it's my turn for fun.
What.
What the hell is this?
What have you done to
my shield, you little bastard?
It's easy when you
realize one thing.
There are no
unexplainable events.
Everything results from scientifically
measurable actions, even your precious shield.
It's been said that Homunculi have the same
body structure as Humans, on an elemental level.
And there's a key element in humans that serves to
increase the body's hardness and resistance to abrasion.
Carbon.
It makes up a third
of every person.
And carbon's degree of hardness can be
changed depending on the strength of its atomic bond.
It can mean the difference
between a diamond and pencil lead.
Now that I know how to use
it, this shouldn't be too tough.
Now take me to Al.
Why would I do
that if I haven't lost?
Don't delude yourself.
This is over.
I'm sure your
brother could tell you.
I don't die so easily.
Well, then I'll just have
to keep beating you down.
Till you wish you did.
What a relief.
I was worried this
wouldn't be fun.
I feel better for
gambling so much on you.
Let's start.
Let's finish!
Damn kid, that was good.
What about Al?
Where is he?
He's back in the woods.
I let him go.
But I thought...
We Homunculi were born when
an Alchemist tries to recreate life.
We are weakened when we're close to the remains
of whomever it was the Alchemist tried to resurrect.
That's the
Homunculi's weak point.
That's how we can
be killed, understand?
And not come back.
But why?
Why are you telling me this?
So you can beat them, Ed.
They sealed me for so long.
You can't let them
stay in control.
But they're... like you.
I'm greedy as hell.
Only out for myself.
She always said it
would be the death of me.
Greed!
They pull the strings.
Now cut them.
I'm counting... on you, kid.
Hey now...
Greed, cut it out.
This is a joke, right?
Stop!
Hey!
I thought nothing
could kill you!
You're the Ultimate Shield!
You're indestructible, right?
I can't kill you!
Something's happened.
Marta, don't!
What did she tell you?
Nothing.
It was over when I got there.
Lyra's gone too.
I don't know where she went.
I'm not sure what
to say, teacher.
Except I'm sorry for all this.
We'll look for the
Ishbalans now.
If we stayed here, we'd
only bring more trouble.
There's a chance the military will come
looking for you, after all that's happened.
You should stay
hidden for a while.
Spare me, Ed.
If you guys start worrying about
me, it really is the end of the world.
Your goal is still
the same, then?
Yes.
We've gone through way too much
not to make it worth something now.
We'll keep on moving
until we get our bodies back.
We'll meet again.
I hope.
You wish?
Let's just talk over-the-top.
Like tomorrow, we'll
meet up in this city again.
Yes.
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 35,
Reunion of the Fallen.
Where did we come
from, and where will we go?
Maybe those are just
questions for fools.