Mr. Edward, is everything
all right in there?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I told them not to
bother me in here.
Maybe they don't
really trust you.
Though I can't see why, except for,
you know, you lying about who you are.
What the... Fletcher?
Run for it!
Hurry!
Brother...
If they catch you,
we'll all be in trouble.
So please get
out of here quickly.
I promise I'll explain
everything later.
All right, let's go.
You can blame me, Brother.
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Fullmetal Alchemist, episode
12. The Other Brothers Elric part 2.
You promised you would never
experiment with alchemy, Fletcher.
You know that Dad
didn't like you doing it.
My lab!
What have they done to my lab?
Mr. Mugear.
Oh, I'm glad to
see you're all right.
The Stone, has it been damaged?
No need to worry.
It's intact.
It's a decent size.
I commend you
for getting this far.
But I'm afraid that our
timetable's been pushed up.
I need you to move directly
into our contingency plan.
But sir, we've
made real progress.
We don't need to resort to that.
Are you questioning the only
person who's given you a chance?
No.
There was once another alchemist
who couldn't do what I asked him.
He left here with his tail between his
legs and he was never heard from again.
What is that?
With this machine, even a
non-alchemist such as myself has options.
Why are you doing this?
Because I can.
You honestly think
I'm a fool, don't you?
That I don't realize the true
Edward Elric has an automail arm.
Or that you're the
sons of Nash Tringham.
A lot of excitement up at the
mansion tonight, huh boys?
You don't say.
The second night in a row.
There's not much
hope for you, is there?
Cough, cough, cough.
Is Elisa still here?
Her father's gonna be furious,
but she wanted to stay here.
And like you two, she
won't listen to reason.
I had no choice though with her
coughing like that, so I put her to bed.
Red water.
They want to crystallize it into a
red stone, an alchemic amplifier.
Stupid.
Compared to the Philosopher's
Stone, it's a cheap imitation.
They're wasting their time.
He said his father put his
whole life into that research.
Yeah, yeah.
Probably another lie.
Unless... maybe they're
the sons of Nash Tringham.
Nash Tringham?
You mean that
theorist I read about?
The guy who came
up with the idea?
He grew up in
Xenotime, just like me.
He only moved to Central to put his
research together on the Red Water.
He was gone for years.
And then one night, he just
showed up again, out of the blue.
It was raining.
Nash Tringham.
You really are back.
Guess I lost that bet.
How are you?
The town's worse off
now than when you left.
You keep saying we need to give up on
gold, but that's a pill no one wants to swallow.
So how's research on the
Red Water going, Brains?
Any luck yet?
Abandoned.
I'll never mess with it again.
And I'm not going
back to Central.
Ever.
But Nash, what
about your family?
I've been a failure.
Both as a good
husband, and a father.
No, Nash.
He'd left behind everything
that mattered to him.
But he wouldn't tell me a word
about what had happened in Central.
He was a wet, wounded
animal, ready to be pounced on.
And the town's biggest land-bearer and
Mugear had made his fortune smell like blood.
Beg me all you want,
the answer's the same.
You're going to turn your
back on this town, too?
The mines have dried up and people are suffering,
but your Red Water could make us produce again.
Once we have the gold, the town
will bounce back twice as strong.
We need you, Nash.
You could be our hero.
You can still make
something out of your life.
Ultimately, he gave in, secluding himself
in Mugear's mine to resume research.
And as the land-bearer promised,
the town was once again lit by gold.
Furnaces were aflame, vendors
filled the streets with their wares.
Life returned to the people.
But at the same time, a
mysterious plague began to spread.
We had all the money we
wanted, but we couldn't buy a cure.
Many, many babies succumbed
to the disease soon after birth.
Elisa was born then.
When she was a baby, an alchemic doctor named
Marcoh passed through town and took a look at her.
Somehow, she's come
into contact with Red Water.
I'll do whatever I can.
It glowed?
Yes.
The doctor's tool.
Could it have
been the real thing?
Whatever it was, we have that
treatment to thank for Elisa's survival.
I hounded Nash all
about the Red Water.
Answer me, Nash.
Before this whole town
becomes a graveyard.
What the hell have
you done here?
It's all my fault.
I've brought it out... again.
Sorry, Belsio.
I'm going to stop it.
Once and for all.
But Nash...
That was the last time
anyone ever saw him.
Soon after, the gold dried up and the
town was once again on the decline.
If those are indeed Nash's boys, they
must have come here in search of their father.
Or his work.
Brother?
What is it?
Is it wrong?
They wanted something to
bring them closer to their dad.
Oh, please, Al.
They're just using their father
to justify their own selfish causes.
Maybe.
But is it really all that
different from what we're doing?
All I'm saying is, I
know how they must feel.
You're useless.
You just had to put the
Contingency Phase Two into effect.
Brother?
What is Phase Two?
Simple, really.
You introduce the red water into the
drinking supply of pregnant women.
It permeates their placenta, a
factory of biological condensing.
No!
You shut up!
When the process is done, you
extract it and transmute it into a stone.
It's foolproof.
Let's Mother Nature do the work.
It's a shame.
You have obviously inherited
your father's cowardice.
Wait!
Just tell me one thing, Mugear.
Did my father ever use
that method on someone?
No.
At the last minute, he had a
crisis of morality and backed out.
If only he had gone through with it,
he would have saved his wretched life.
You liar.
You said that
he left here alive.
Wait!
Mugear!
Get back here!
I've taken care of everything.
Now all we have to do is convince the
real Elric brothers to put our plan into motion.
You make it sound so easy, but those
boys are more complex than you think.
I can handle a
couple of children.
Please, just put
a little trust in me.
We're close to
the milk and honey.
I can feel it.
It's your gamble.
Go ahead.
One way or the other,
things will work out.
I'm so sorry those
impostors stole your identities.
I was completely fooled by them.
We all were, I'm ashamed to say.
The last thing I want to
do is add insult to injury.
I'm sure you have work to do.
But since you two really are such
accomplished alchemists, there's a matter
I'd like some help with.
Something with red
water, by chance?
Oh!
So you have heard about it.
That'll spare me
having to explain.
The truth of the matter is,
I've done my research as well.
And I happen to hear some rumors that
you're very interested in the Philosopher's Stone.
Uh-huh.
What do you think, Edward?
It's the product of
crystallized red water.
A prototype for the
prize that you're after.
And so what do I do with that?
First of all, together
we can save Xenotime.
Once we revitalize the gold mine,
this town can get back on its feet again.
Sounds like a good cause.
So, where are the fakes?
Taken care of.
They're in the cellar.
Oh!
What did you do that for?
We'll talk about the
unfinished work later.
First, we execute
those prisoners.
We state alchemists aren't
the type to forgive liars.
Oh!
Then you mean you're accepting
my request for assistance?
I told you let's take care
of those pathetic kids first.
It's been a good while
since I killed anyone.
I kinda miss it.
You wanna watch?
Uh, no thanks.
I'll let you take care of it.
Hmm...
Brother.
Hi.
Al, what are you doing here?
I know who you guys are now, and I know
that your father was actually Nash Tringham.
What I don't know is why you'd
so foolishly continue his work.
Because... it was his dream.
And as his son, it was
my duty to see it through.
So you honestly think
this is what he wanted?
You do realize the suffering that toxic water
is causing the people of this town, don't you?
Well, your father realized it.
That's why he chose
to abandon his research.
And I can tell you right now you're not gonna find
happiness by chasing your father's failed dream.
Live your own life.
And stop with all the acting.
Trying to be someone
you're clearly not.
Come on, Al.
Not to worry.
That was nothing compared to
what these boys will fashion for me.
Which boys?
You mean us?
There's one more thing
I've been wondering.
Whatever happened
to Nash Tringham?
Just in case we have
any questions to ask him.
Nash Tringham?
Oh, his research wasn't making
progress anymore, so I had to let him go.
Huh.
You don't strike me as the type of guy who
lets someone who knows all of his secrets
just walk away clean.
I'm afraid I missed
the implication.
I'm saying I don't answer
to murderers, Mugear.
You got that?
Really?
In that case, you're not
getting out of here alive.
There are plenty of
other alchemists I can use.
Another stone?
So he's got more than
one of those things?
It may not be as
potent as that other one.
But it'll do!
Is that all you've got?
Bad question.
Didn't think I had the stones?
Ah, crap!
You can't hide for long.
Yeah.
I hate to say
it, but he's right.
We need an out.
Fast!
Not done yet.
Uh...
Now's our chance, Al!
Push!
Well Ed, I do hate to interrupt, but
it looked like you needed the help.
Nah.
We're not going to be chasing
our dad's dream anymore.
You're right.
It's time we live our own lives.
Uh...Russell...
Brother!
A secret passage?
Come on, guys.
Time for a chase.
Russell!
Not much farther!
The spring where the red
water comes out is just up ahead.
We're almost there.
Mugear blocked our path.
He forgot who he's dealing with.
I'll never surrender the spring!
As long as I have the red
water, nothing can stop me!
Least of all the diminutive state
alchemist and his copycat friends!
Ed!
Brother!
Diminutive state alchemist!
Points for the big word,
but you're still going down!
Oh yeah!
You see now?
Even with your stones,
I'm on a whole other level!
What's going on?
Ed, that's enough!
Let's get out of here!
Brother!
I'll never surrender...
the spring!
Rushing water.
The red water's overflowing.
That should hold it for now.
Eh, won't it just come
out somewhere else?
That shock probably
weakened those support beams.
We should leave.
Now then. if we
could just find a drain...
The trees... they're
absorbing all the red water.
I saw something like
this back in the lab.
That's right.
They were detoxifying
the red water with plants.
See?
It works.
They pulled through.
Well done.
Thank you, trees.
Sorry for this.
Take these!
They're from my uncle!
Great!
Thank you very much!
Stay out of trouble, you guys!
Yeah, and come back to see us.
Sure, of course we will.
So, are you sure you'll be
able to make it in this town?
Belsio wants us
to go work for him.
Our agricultural alchemy should
be pretty useful around his farm.
So, Ed, you'll still hunt for the
Philosopher's Stone after this?
Yeah.
If you want, I can tell you exactly
how we crystallized the red stone.
But why?
It's not so much out of atonement,
but just because you deserve to know.
Thanks a lot, Russell.
But no thanks.
We'll find the real
article on our own.
You can count on that.
You'll see, Ed.
When you come to visit,
this town will be even better.
That's right.
And by that time, I'll
probably be taller than you.
Come on!
Show a little respect
for your elders, huh?
I'm serious.
Hey, why is that funny?
So long, guys!
Goodbye!
Bye!
Don't forget to visit!
Goodbye!
Hey, a letter.
It's for us?
Yeah.
Let me read.
What?
What's it say?
Drop it!
It's nothing, okay?
Oh?
Let me see!
Stay away from me!
I'm serious!
Show it to me!
Hey!
Come on give it back!
Ed, thank you for all the help
and words of wisdom you gave us.
I'm sorry I was such a smartass to
you at first, but I am trying to be a better
older brother to Fletcher, and I'll
try hard to follow your example, Ed.
I guess you being a year older
than me makes a big difference.
Well, have a good trip, Russell.
Damn!
I can't believe he's a year younger
than me and already so much taller!
Life's so unfair!
You think those two
are gonna be all right?
Yeah, they'll be fine.
Maybe we will, too.
Fullmetal Alchemist.
Episode 13: Fullmetal vs. Flame.
Colonel Roy Mustang,
the Flame Alchemist.
I'm afraid he's more
powerful than my brother.
Like hell he is!