Nice of you to come.
Graciously, do I welcome you here.
You don't look too welcoming with that
sword.
I have been entrusted with guarding these
grounds.
For now, you may call me number Forty-eight.
Forty-eight?
Catchy.
It's been silent for too long.
I'm pleased to face someone capable again.
But your luck has run out running into me.
Do not think ill of me, child.
And you don't think ill of me for being
the child who defeated you.
How about a little blade on blade?
Nice.
You move well for a big thing.
Good.
Who are you?
Ooh, so demanding.
I guess I should answer.
I'm number Sixty-six.
Oh, that's just what they call me at work.
Number Sixty-six?
Yes.
I have a proper name, too.
But if I told you, you'd be so shocked
you'd wet yourself.
I'll tell you when I'm peeling your skin.
Those reflexes!
Why, you!
Curious child.
An anchoring seal.
Bodyless armor.
He's just like Al.
Humankind cannot gain anything without
first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of equal value must
be lost.
That is alchemy's first law of equivalent
exchange.
In those days, we really believed that to
be the world's one and only truth.
Fascinating.
This deserves a better introduction.
Number Forty-eight was my
label as a condemned prisoner.
According to the official records,
I was executed two years ago.
Prisoner?
So that proves it.
There is a link between Laboratory 5 and
the prison next door.
When my body was flesh and blood,
the papers called me the Slicer.
I was a mass murderer and I made a real
splash.
Here my skills have been put to a
different use.
I'm its immortal guard.
No, you're hardly immortal.
What?
That seal of blood.
It's alchemy.
Someone took the iron in that blood and
attuned it to the metal in your armor.
That's what keeps your soul bound to this
world.
If someone breaks the seal it's made,
then you're a dead man.
Ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Finally, someone with a backbone.
Someone who thinks they can live.
This should be a good fight.
I've told you I know your weakness.
This is your final warning before I use
it.
I don't care!
See, I'm the type of person who likes a
little struggle in the kill.
So try to make it last.
Aaaaah!
What was that?
My shoulder nearly caved.
A lighter weight should make you faster.
But that means it's easier to break too,
so don't be reckless.
I'm in trouble.
Better make this quick.
[Fighting Sounds]
Just like a Monkey aren't you?
You better watch your mouth.
Ha ha ha ha!
It's been so long since I've had such
responsive prey.
But judging from your wound and your
breathing, it won't last much longer.
My body, unlike yours, does not know
fatigue.
Give up any hope you had.
As we speak, my colleague is disposing of
your companion outside.
You can't rely on him to help you now.
Heh.
So this colleague of yours, is he strong?
Yes, he is.
Though not as strong as myself.
What's so funny?
I've got nothing to worry about then.
My companion, as you put it.
I've fought him plenty of times,
and I've never beat him once.
Aaaaah!
Errrr. Quit that!
Hold still so I can cut you off!
Stop!
Miserable behemoth!
You're smiling at me, aren't you?
I'll spill your insides!
I'll show you how thinly you slice!
Now you're frightened!
I'll carve out his shoulder, Rose!
Now you've gone and done it, you brute!
You've knocked off my head!
You're empty inside.
Yes, that's what they said when they
sentenced me.
And thanks to the circumstances,
it ended up quite literal.
You don't recognize me like this,
do you?
What do you mean?
Don't tell me you forgot!
After all, it was thanks to your help
catching me that I ended up here.
A condemned man.
Number Sixty-six was my name on death row.
But back when I was flesh and in trails,
I had better names.
Barry the Butcher.
Or my favorite, Barry the Chopper.
Barry the Chopper?
You're the one who kidnapped Winry.
That's right.
And after being caught, imprisoned,
and executed, I've come back from a pit of
fire to take my revenge on you,
maggot!
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
Is that so?
What do you mean, is that so?
People get terrified when a
serial killer comes back from
the dead, and an empty suit
of armor moves on its own.
You should be saying, Ah!
Or, Ah!
What's wrong with your body?
Ah!
Take it easy.
You're going to hurt my feelings.
Hmm.
Are you an executed prisoner, too?
No, I'm not a crook.
I suppose not, no.
Why would you have been helping the
police?
But who cares where you came from?
I know your weakness now!
You'd better beg for mercy.
Your life belongs to me.
If I destroy the blood seal on your armor,
you'll die!
The same goes for you, right?
Ah!
But I still have the advantage,
you rotten beast!
You don't know where my blood seal is.
And you don't know where my seal is,
either.
Ah!
Then I'll just have to chop you up until I
find it!
And you can't do that because you don't
have a knife!
Ah!
Why do I have to get the crazy one?
B and C block
both turned up zilch.
He's not a magician.
We know he's here somewhere.
I want him found, whatever it takes!
Yes, sir!
He has guts, that's for sure.
Attacking a military facility in the
middle of Central.
I still don't understand, Major.
Why is Scar so preoccupied with Edward
Elric?
What's he trying to get from him?
That's not your concern.
Where are the Elrics now?
Uh... The Elrics, right, sir?
I don't know.
Uh...
You're acting suspicious, bloch!
I'm sorry, sir!
I'm sorry!
You see, they...
Permission to speak, Major, sir?
Hmm?
With your authorization, I'd like to
relocate any troops we have available.
What are you talking about?
Helping out the Elric brothers,
Major.
I know their current location.
The Central Laboratory, number five.
Hmm.
And what else can you tell me?
You're on a downward spiral.
Your moves keep getting sloppier.
Admit it, little man.
You're through.
Who are you calling so little you can't see?
Too small a target to hit without a
magnifying glass?
Ha ha ha ha. At least you still
have enough energy to scream.
But that, too, will pass.
Not the auto-mail again.
Oh!
Why don't I...
You give me far too little credit.
Did you really think you could beat me
with the toss of a spear?
Please.
Thank you for the struggle.
You've done well to last this long.
But your limit's been reached.
Relax.
Admit your defeat.
There's nothing you can do to win now.
We'll see about that.
You're forgetting a key detail.
I didn't come here alone.
Now, Al!
Attack!
Huh?
Sorry.
I didn't hear you come in.
What?
Whoa!
Ah!
No fear.
I'll spare no more.
Everyone knows that.
Why are you stopping now, boy?
My blood seal isn't broken yet.
Your soul's attached to your helmet.
Now that it's cut off, your body's just a
useless hunk of iron.
You're no threat to me anymore.
Now down to business.
There's something you need to tell me
about.
The Philosopher's Stone?
If you came here, there's little else you
could be seeking.
Good, then let's cut to the chase.
Tell me all you know about the stone and
its connection to this lab.
I can't do that.
Really?
Listen, Slicer.
Beating up dogs don't get to call the
shots.
You tell me now or I'll break your seal.
The battle isn't over yet.
Ahh!
Ow.
It can't be.
Haven't you heard of sharing?
One set of armor doesn't have to mean one
soul.
A second blood seal.
This one on the body.
Are you okay, older brother?
Yes, younger brother.
Just barely.
And your brothers?
Did I forget to mention that?
Yes, you forgot.
That's what made the mass murderer and the
slicers so great.
He was a pair of mass murdering brothers.
All this time I've actually been fighting
two people.
That sure reeks of foul play.
All's fair in war.
Isn't that what he said?
Yes, brother, it is.
How dare you injure my older brother.
I'll slice you off at the knees so you're
even closer to the ground.
More short jokes, huh?
You'll pay for that.
Just like him.
Oh no, I'm not giving you time for
alchemy.
I'm getting lightheaded.
I'm losing too much blood.
End of the line.
I'm really gonna die here, aren't I?
No, dammit, I can't.
I can't die here.
If it ends like this.
And who's gonna finish the job and get Al
back to normal again?
This is for my brother.
And this is for mine.
You don't have time to transmute.
To beat a serial killer, I guess I'll have
to act like one.
A partial transmutation.
He stopped at step two, breaking something
apart.
Sorry about that.
But I don't have time to die.
I've got work to do.
Curse you!
Now you've done it, tinny.
Oh, shut up and rust!
The slicer deserves better than this.
You'll pay, alchemist.
We'll tear you apart.
Won't we, older brother?
No, younger brother.
It pains me to say it, but we've lost.
There wouldn't happen to be a third
brother, would there?
Both: No.
You can pat yourself on the back,
child.
This time, you really won.
Perfect.
Then this time you can tell me everything
you know about the Philosopher's Stone.
No, I cannot say.
Listen to me.
You must destroy us.
You heard him.
Finish the job.
There's nothing for the defeated but
death.
That's our rule.
I'm not killing anyone.
That's not what I do.
Hmph.
You're too generous with your words.
Saying anyone, not anything.
As if we could still be called human in
this twisted state.
I didn't say kill us.
I said destroy.
Destroy these things we've become.
Now get on with it.
The only way I could do that is if I
admitted your definition was right.
And if I did, if I accepted you
weren't human, that means
I'd have to admit the same of
my brother and I can't do that.
He's your brother.
Damn it!
I hate you!
Can we call it a draw already?
I'm worried about my brother.
Brother?
You're kidding.
That little pipsqueak alchemist is your
brother?
Yes.
And he gets angry if you call him that.
I see.
This changes everything.
[Laughs]
What?
How?
So then it was your brother who put you in
that armored shell.
Isn't that right?
Yes, he did.
He risked his life to do it.
To save me.
Oh, that's just rich.
[Laughing]
What are you laughing about?
Nothing.
I'm sorry.
It's just, brotherly love is so beautiful.
Gets me every time.
Even when it's a total fraud.
A fraud?
That's right.
Artificial affection.
No.
You're wrong.
You don't know anything about it.
My brother loves me for real.
And I love him.
What a naive worm you are.
What if you're a fake?
An imitation?
How would you know the difference?
Your brother's the one who crafted you in
this form.
How do you know you don't love him because
he made it so you would?
Tailored your memories and personality to
suit him best.
That just isn't true.
I'm Alphonse Elric.
I'm exactly the same as I was when I was a
boy.
I know I am!
But that's the trick, isn't it?
Your so-called soul.
It's invisible.
Undetectable by any scientific tool.
But what if you were designed in a way to
make it impossible for you to decipher
what's real and what lies your brother has
been feeding you?
No.
That can't be.
My brother's a person.
I'm telling you.
And that means you guys are too.
I don't want to kill you.
I can't.
Ha ha ha ha
Ha ha ha ha!
Are you all right, older brother?
Yes.
It's funny, that's all.
Ha ha.
As long as I remember, my brother and I
thrived off stealing, carnage, and murder.
We were demonized, spit on, called
animals.
Forget biology.
We were inhuman because they couldn't
stomach what we did.
And now's the first time we're treated as
people with when we're scraps of metal.
It's too much.
What a stupid irony.
I'm a person.
I'm real.
I'm Alphonse Elric.
How can you prove this Alphonse ever
existed?
That the identity isn't a lie of
convenience?
Where's your body?
Have you seen it?
He said it was gone.
For the whole thing to be a fabrication?
Mom?
Everything?
It couldn't be.
There's this thing, see.
It's something I've been meaning to tell
you for a long time now.
But I've been kind of scared, I guess,
of what your reaction is.
What was he trying to tell me?
What was he scared of?
Am I not what I think I am?
Brother?
Full Metal Alchemist.
Episode 21: The Red Glow.
If there's one single color that can
describe a human life, that must be it.