This is a joke.
What does she
mean, cool our heads?
I hope she doesn't think we're gonna
have any trouble surviving here now.
She even forbade us
from using alchemy.
It's just like last
time, isn't it?
Yeah, really.
I mean, what's the
point of doing this again?
Does teacher think we
haven't grown up at all?
Oh, I don't know.
I'm sure she has her reasons.
No, wait!
Go back!
Edward!
Alphonse!
Don't move around, girl.
You'll get wet.
Okay.
But what do you want them to do?
I don't want them
to do anything.
That's right.
What's right?
You left them on an uninhabited
island without any provisions.
And what do you mean you
don't want them to do anything?
I mean just that.
Right.
You know...
I just don't think I
understand you people at all.
It's okay to do nothing.
It's alright to just stop and
think things over for a while.
Those two need some
time to do that right now.
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one, and only truth.
Al... let's escape.
Ah!
That's impossible!
I can't swim!
Come to think
about it, neither can I.
Yeah, we're different
from back then.
We're smarter.
This is fun, isn't it, brother?
You bet.
It has been a long time since we
went on a vacation together, huh, Al?
A vacation?
Good one!
Here, take this.
A knife?
This is an uninhabited island.
There's no electricity, no Wells, no
house to protect you from the rain.
As for wild animals,
there probably aren't any.
You two have to survive on this island all
by yourselves for one full month, all right?
Oh, and you can't
use any alchemy.
What?!
I'll come to pick you up
in a month, okay, boys?
What?!
Wa... Wait!
One is all, and all is one.
Oh, and boys, if you still haven't figured that out by
the end of the month, I'm sending you back to Risembool.
Bye!
One is all, and all is one.
We understand the concept now, but back then...
Yeah, we had no idea what she meant by it back then.
Man, were we dumb.
One is all, and all is one, huh?
Damn, that crazy lady sure
gave us some weird homework.
It doesn't make any sense.
Yeah, one is all,
and all is one?
What's that mean?
Maybe it's a riddle.
It sounds pretty stupid to me.
Yeah, but she said if we don't find the answer
to it in a month, we can't go through real training.
We were tricked into coming to this
island by that crazy, sadistic witch!
What the hell does this have
to do with alchemy anyway?!
Let's sleep.
We'll have to get up early
tomorrow to look for something to eat.
Yeah.
What's up, Al?
Need a restroom?
What is it, brother?
Go to the bathroom by yourself.
You idiot!
Wake up!
Get out of here!
We can't get out of here!
If we leave now, we'll
never learn anything!
Brother!
Damn it!
Alphonse!
Run!
Oh, man.
You better not be lost
or I'll kill you myself!
Al!
You don't want to eat me!
I take terrible!
Brother, it's just me!
Oh, Al!
I'm so glad it's you!
I was afraid you got lost!
Look, it's a fox.
There's two of them.
Well, how'd it go?
Let's check.
All right!
We got ourselves some dinner!
Don't forget to
dry yourself off.
You don't want to rust.
Okay.
Who was that person, brother?
Oh, man.
He's so scary.
She said there
were no wild animals.
I think he was more
dangerous than any wild animal.
What should we do?
What can we do?
Our ride's not coming
for another month.
First thing's first.
If we're both hungry,
then we can't fight.
Yes!
My brother is a genius!
Looks like these traps work
even if you don't make them right.
So, how are we supposed
to eat that brother?
We kill it.
Do we have to?
You do it.
No, you don't understand Ed.
You have to do it.
There's no way I can.
I've never killed
an animal before.
Well, I haven't either, Al!
But that's no fair!
You always make
me do your dirty work!
I do not!
Ah!
Stop!
That's our rabbit!
Brother!
Are you okay?
That bite looks bad.
That stupid fox!
When we find that damn
thing, I'm biting it back!
Brother!
It has babies.
I guess she's the mother.
Mm-hmm.
Let's pass on the meat
and eat fish instead.
I'm starting to wonder
if foxes are edible.
Just be patient, Ed.
Got one!
Fire!
Time to eat!
Food!!
Almost ready.
Brother!
Yeah?
What's up?
Come with me.
Ow!
What happened here?
What do you mean, what happened?
You got hungry and ate
it all before dinner time.
It wasn't me.
But look, there's
your handprint.
Look at it carefully.
It's a right hand.
So someone else is here.
Someone else?
You mean...
Well, at least now we know
why Teacher brought us here.
She thinks we didn't
get enough the last time.
Wait, where are you going?
To find the masked man.
We might as well go ahead
and get this over with now.
We're not giving
up that easy, Al.
One month.
I think we can hack it.
Hey.
So why are we here again Al?
I don't remember.
Me either.
What would happen if we died
here before she came back for us?
We can't!
Winry and Aunt
Pinako would be sad.
And there are so many things I
haven't done yet that I want to do.
It's just that I... I
don't understand.
And what this has
to do with alchemy.
I hate this.
I want to go home.
All right.
Where are you?
Food for Brother.
Brother, look what I found.
Hey, what's up with him?
Did you call me?
Brother!
Then... who was that over there?
The cicada...
I see...
It died.
Death.
If we die...
The same thing
will happen to us.
It died...
Let go of him!
Let go... of my brother...
We talked about what would
happen if we died here... Remember?
Yeah.
A lot of people would be sad.
That's a subjective opinion.
But look at it objectively.
If I die, the world would continue to
move along as if nothing had happened.
Because you're
just a small part of it.
Don't call me small.
Well, when the small part, in this
case me, dies, the body remains.
Water, carbon, ammonia, lime,
phosphorus, salt, saltpeter, sulfur, magnesium,
fluorine, iron, and
aluminum, right?
Right.
The body's only a combination
of those simple elements.
Nothing more.
We are destined to be decomposed by
bacteria and become nutrients for plants.
Then you follow
the process further.
Those plants nourish herbivores.
And those herbivores
nourish carnivores.
Even others like us.
And though we lose awareness, our
lives keep moving through the system.
I'm sorry.
The great flow that
maintains the universe.
Call it the cycle of life.
The course of nature.
Each of us is just a
small part of that current.
One in the all.
And yet, without all the
individual ones, the all can't exist.
This world flows by following
grander laws we can't even imagine.
To recognize that flow.
And work within it.
To decompose.
And recreate.
That is alchemy.
28 days.
And hey, we got some breakfast.
All right, boys.
Let's hear it.
What does it mean that
one is all and all is one?
The world is the
all and I am the one.
Hm?
Hm.
All right then...
Let's begin your training.
Whaaa?
Yeahhhh.
I guess we aren't gonna
find the guy in the mask.
What's it matter?
We already learned the only lesson
this island has to teach us, right?
Yeah.
When we were kids... we taught ourselves
the answer to one is all and all is one.
We didn't understand
everything that meant.
It was a mistake to
try to bring Mom back.
We learned that the hard way.
The cycle of life only
goes one direction.
Not even alchemy
can change that.
I guess Teacher brought
us here to remind us of that.
And to give us time to think
about the consequences.
Well, did you remember?
Yes.
And did you realize?
Teacher, we know what
you're trying to tell us.
It's true that we went against the laws of
alchemy when we tried to bring our Mom back.
What you see before you
is our punishment for that.
But we just want to regain the bodies
we lost when we made that mistake.
Are you trying to regain something you lost
because of a mistake by making another one?
We know it's not
what you taught us.
But we... we... We
have to try, dammit.
We can't just give up.
Even though we may not have
been able to... to bring Mom back.
We are still alive.
So you're determined
to move forward?
Yes, ma'am.
So be it.
Is there someone out there?
What are you talking about?
Of course there is.
Somebody was on the
island when we were kids, too.
We figured it was just the same
guy in the mask from before.
Impossible.
Since I was the brute
in the mask back then.
Wait a minute!
That was you the whole time?
Yes.
I sent him to make
sure you didn't die.
But he nearly killed us!
It looks like we don't have
time to discuss this right now.
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 29 The Untainted child.
I saw it, brother.
The scar on his
shoulder looks familiar.
Who is this boy?