I couldn't believe it.
Come on, eat something.
You need to eat to get
your strength back, right?
Fine, suit yourself.
I don't know why I have to take
care of this stubborn mule anyway.
Hey, is there
anywhere that still hurts?
I could bring you some medicine.
Has his condition improved?
He just won't listen
to anything I tell him.
We try to help him and he
just leaves and gets hurt again.
Those of us who have the blood of Ishbal running through
our veins are protected by our god, Isbala, up above.
Everything has happened
as God designed.
What's wrong?
Not joining in?
Of course I am!
Isn't that why you hired me?
I'm going to slice through their
flesh and bathe in their blood!
Yes, slaughter them all!
Spare no one!
What is this?
More suffering?
Is Ishbala sending
us yet another trial?
No.
This is not the will of God.
These are deeds wrought only
by soulless and wicked men.
No!
You're not strong enough!
Ishbala...
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the worlds one and only truth.
A while back in Risembool, there
was something you wanted to tell me,
but you couldn't.
You said you were
afraid of how I'd react.
You remember that, don't you?
I can't remember parts of my
past because they never happened.
My memories and
my soul are fake.
Something you created.
Isn't that what
you wanted to say?
No, what Ed wanted to tell
you was that... Stop lying to me!
Is there anything else you're
hiding? that you want to say?
What about you,
my so-called brother?
Answer my question.
Why won't you say anything?
Unless it's true!
Why didn't you say anything Ed?
If I'm nothing more than a bunch of
made-up memories, then what do I do now?
No, really.
I mean I covered....
If I'm just made-up, then that
means Mom could be made-up too.
Stop!
Thief!
Somebody stop them!
You little Bratz!
Get back here!
Nobody steals from me!
We lost him.
Here, eat up.
I don't want any!
What were you thinking?
You just picked that up
and stole it out of nowhere!
If Mom knew we were...
There, see?
You can't be so
hard on yourself.
You shouldn't take things
that don't belong to you.
Did you hear that?
This old pile of
junk said something.
No, I'm not a pile of junk.
Hey, you guys look like...
Are you from Ishbal?
Uh...
Um, excuse me.
Have you seen anyone
that looks like this?
Hmmm, no.
I'm sorry, I haven't.
Okay, well, thank you.
Don't worry.
As soon as we find him, you can talk to
him and set him straight on everything.
Edward?
Winry, I'm scared.
There is something I've
wanted to ask him for a long time.
But I've always been too
afraid to talk to him about it.
What is it?
Oh, no...
Please Al, I... don't...
Edward,
Sometimes the answers never
come if you don't ask the questions.
It must seem very bizarre to find so
many people living in a place like this.
No, not at all.
It's just not what I was
expecting when I followed them.
Don't worry about it.
I guess these two were causing
some trouble on the surface.
By the way, where did you get
that strange armor you're wearing?
Is it some kind of uniform?
Relax, he's not
part of the military.
Scar!
Our paths entwine.
Don't they, Alphonse Elric?
I didn't know you
would be here, too.
Well, do you two
know each other, then?
We do.
In a sense.
Perfect, that makes this easier.
Stranger... I ask that you do not tell
anyone about us or this camp of ours.
I won't.
I promise.
I've heard about what
happened in Ishbal.
But why did you end up here?
Because the military
came and attacked us.
Yes.
They've destroyed our homes and massacred
our people again and again, but they do not tire.
They still just keep coming.
If those wretched State Alchemists
are indeed still trying to hunt me down,
then right now might be
their only chance to succeed.
Because you're injured.
What happened to your brother?
I don't care what
happens to him.
What, Rick?
What's wrong?
Mom's locket.
It fell off.
It's gone.
Who cares about that
dumb old thing anyway?
Just forget about it, all right?
When I fell...
Hey, wait!
Wait for me!
You can't!
Somebody might see you!
Rick!
Leo!
Don't worry.
I'll bring them back.
I don't know what
happened, Alphonse Elric.
But if you and your brother hate each other now,
then that makes things a great deal easier for me.
Scar, what do you
think about me?
I mean, when we're
talking, do you...
Do you sense anything?
Do you think I'm human,
even with this body?
What do we have here?
A pair of Ishbalans.
Stinking rats.
Come on, Rick.
Give it up.
You're never gonna find it.
Is this what you're looking for?
Hello?
Yes.
Oh, is that so?
Yes, by all means, follow them.
Find their little nest.
So, that locket used
to belong to your mom?
Uh-huh.
What's inside of it?
I don't know.
It's broken and won't open.
But that's okay.
Get rid of that thing, will ya?
No way!
You shouldn't talk like that about
something that was your mom's.
Oh, that's really funny,
you calling her a mother.
All she ever did
was force rules on us.
She was never nice
around us, not even once.
She was just
trying to protect you.
She loved you.
No!
She never loved us!
We didn't mean squat to her!
It's strange.
It seems like he would do
anything to forget about his past.
The exact opposite of me.
I want to get my memories back.
My real memories, if I have any.
Okay, you two go in first.
Wait a second.
Okay, it's clear.
Batard!
Let him go!
Now!
Stop!
Yes.
Right.
I understand.
Thank you.
Wait, Al?
Where are you?
What are you trying to do?
So, they were mercenaries.
Yeah, they're using an old military
installation on the outskirts of the city.
That's where Rick
should be, too.
But Scar, are you sure
we should be doing this?
I mean, it's going to
be kind of dangerous.
Hey, do you have some kind of
problem with us coming along?
No, it's uh...
You have to realize stranger, nothing is stronger
to an Ishbalan than faith and his loyalty to his kin.
If the life of an old man can help
save the boy, then I will freely give it up.
He's right.
Ishbalans protect their own without
hesitation, no matter what the cost is.
Except...
Except for Mom.
She flat-out abandoned us.
Really?
You heard from Al?
Yeah.
And I think he may be involved
in something very strange.
I remember how it
happened perfectly.
Mom was praying to
Ishbala like she always did.
Rick, are you sleeping?
I never told Rick
what really happened.
But I promised myself that
nothing would ever hurt him.
Because I would protect him.
Over there.
The military is going to give
us a huge reward for this job.
Then we can sit back and relax.
We captured one of those children
just like you ordered us to, boss.
Are you sure
they'll take the bait?
Of course they will.
He's one of their
own people, right?
But more importantly, the armored guy
and the scarred one will come along, too.
So he's an Alchemist, huh?
Get him!
always love it when I'm right.
You and the others
take care of the tin can.
This one's all mine.
Scar!
So, we meet
again, little brother.
What are you doing here?
Why bother fighting?
You're not real.
Just a collection of
fabricated memories.
Once I've put you out of your misery, you won't
have to worry about what's real and what's fake.
Wont that be nice!
You leave him alone!
Brother, what are you doing here?
That's a stupid question.
We've been worried
sick about you.
He's been looking for
you all over Central.
Brother.
Fire!
Al, all this time I've
been too afraid to ask you.
But I need to know
the truth, okay?
It's my fault you don't
have a real body anymore.
Do you hate me?
What?
Do you?
I wouldn't blame
you if you did Al.
But I've gotta know.
Do you hate me for
all that's happened?
That's what you've
been trying to ask me?
Al!
Behind you!
Brother!
I can never... I
can never hate you!
What?
I'm not dead.
I guess even a murderer with a reputation like
he has can make a mistake if he's in enough pain.
Shoot!
Somebody shoot him!
Time to give up.
It looks like you're the
only one who's left here.
Who the hell are you?
A dog of the
military just like you.
You're a State Alchemist?
But that doesn't make sense!
We're on the.... the same side!
Well, this is a surprise.
A real State Alchemist.
Please allow me to thank
you for making me look like this!
Ssss... Stop it!
Get off me.
Get off.
Rick!
No.....
No Rick you can't.
Please, no!
Rick?
It's Mom's locket.
She saved me, see?
Hmm.
Oh, this is eye medicine.
Medicine?
Evidently your mother suffered from
an eye disease that leads to blindness,
but as our people do, she pretended to be
fine so that you boys wouldn't have to worry.
Come to think of it, she once told me how hard it
was to care for you because of some condition she had.
But I'll bet it was harder
on her on the inside.
Our mother couldn't see, Rick.
That means...
Rick, Leo where are you?
I can't find you!
Wh...
[Screams]
She... she was looking for us.
She ran into our room to find us and
protect us from the soldiers, and that's when.
Oh, no!
What the hell's going on?
I was working for the military!
So why did that damn state
Alchemist interfere with us?
Does the Führer
even know about this!
Because maybe I should
give him a phone ca.....
So where will all of you go now?
There's another group of our people living
and hiding free from the state, just like us.
We'll travel downstream
until we reach them.
Al, thank you for everything.
Now when I think about my mother, I'm going
to treasure every single memory that I have.
Yeah, me too.
And from now on, I'll
know my memories are real.
I'll have faith in that.
Alphonse Elric.
Earlier, I did sense something.
Tears that can't
be seen, but felt.
Those tears were... human.
Thank you.
Hey Scar, so tell me something.
Did the Ishbalan people ever
possess the Philosopher's Stone?
Is that the real truth?
And then the
military came after it?
No, Ed.
It's the other way around.
We wanted the stone to keep the military
from wiping out our race and our way of life.
But did you create one?
A Philosopher's Stone?
Let's get going.
Hey, hold on.
I want an answer!
Brother, let him go.
Those people need Scar.
He can help them.
Al, let's get going.
Right.
You know, Al,
I've been thinking.
We used to fight over the
dumbest things, didn't we?
Yeah.
Like, who got to
sleep in the top bunk.
I remember.
I lost that one.
Or what about that time
we fought over the toys?
I won.
We used to fight
over candy, too, right?
Hey, I never won any of them.
Fullmetal Alchemist.
Episode 25.
Words of Farewell.
Let's leave.
Let's go and not tell
anyone where we're headed.
That's the way
we've always done it.