One book in this whole mess.
It's like searching for a
needle in a stack of needles.
She can't be.
Someone there.
So you're him?
What are you here
for, scarred man?
You look like her, but
that couldn't be possible.
What smell is that?
It's like an Ishbalan with tasty
blood taped all over his hands.
Let me guess.
You've come here to take care of
the full metal pipsqueak, haven't you?
But we can't have that.
We have our own
special needs, after all.
He has to keep searching
for the Philosopher's Stone.
You're using the boy?
Silly me.
Now I think I've said too much.
OOOO Lust Does that
mean I get to eat him, too?
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Central!
It's good to be back.
But why are we standing around
when the library's waiting for us?
Brother, wait for me!
Come on.
What's the big rush, boys?
It's not as if the
library's going anywhere.
After all this searching,
we've got our first solid lead.
I can't just sit on my butt now.
Major Armstrong, sir, we've been
sent to meet you here as you requested.
Well done, troops.
I need to go directly to HQ
and get back to my other duties.
From now on, these
two will be guarding you.
Introduce yourselves.
Lieutenant Maria
Ross reporting, sir.
And I'm Sergeant Denny
Bloch, humbly at your service.
It is an honor to meet you, Full
Metal Alchemist Edward Elric, sir.
Wow!
You certainly live
up to your name, sir.
When they say Full Metal,
they really aren't kidding.
Uh, you're talking
to the wrong guy.
I'm used to it by now.
Huh?
Really?
You mean this little guy?
Uh, sorry, sorry, sir.
It's just, I thought you'd be
fuller and more... more metal.
Uh, shut up!
Come on, Major.
We don't need
babysitters anymore.
We've both been fully repaired.
Sorry, Edward.
I'd avoid it if I could.
We've informed the Major that Scar
has been spotted around Central again,
and he's specifically
targeted you in the past.
We have no other choice, Edward.
You'll just have to
put up with it for now.
But you don't need to
worry, Full Metal Alchemist.
We'll keep you and your
brother safe from harm.
I just hope you
don't slow me down.
Wait!
We have a car waiting for you!
Sorry about my brother.
He's like that with everyone.
Don't take it personally.
The boy may not look like much, but he's
come through for us on many occasions.
So make sure he
finds what he came for.
Sir, I'll try.
But I'm afraid it's
too late for that now.
As fate would have it, the library's
first branch burned down just last night.
You gotta be kidding.
Scar's unwanted posters
all over town, and several
eyewitnesses saw him in the
area just before the fire started.
Brother.
Our only decent
lead is a pile of ashes.
And I'm not just saying this
because I'm her father, Roy.
Everyone agrees!
Seriously, you have to hear the girl,
and to think she's only three years old!
She has the voice of an angel.
That settles it.
She's gonna be an opera star.
Lieutenant Colonel, some
of us have real work to do.
Yeah, I've got loads of it.
I never know where
the hours in the day go.
So, Hughes, you think
there's a way to use alchemy to
send fire through a phone
line, torch someone's ear off?
I'm not sure, Flame Alchemist.
Great question.
I'll get my people on it.
There is another reason
that I called you, though, Roy.
Based on eyewitness accounts, we're
now certain that Scar was involved in the fire.
But from the looks of things,
I don't think he acted alone.
There's signs of a struggle
that got way out of hand.
And Scar?
Any sign of what
happened to him?
There's evidence of the
fight dragging into the sewers.
His blood-stained clothes
washed up further downstream.
We don't know if that means
he's dead or just naked.
On another note, ever since the death of Brigadier
General Grand, the rumor mill's been going crazy.
People are saying that you're going
to be transferred back to Central soon.
Of course, there are some
factions here putting forth the
ridiculous notion that you're the
one who's behind these rumors.
Can you believe that?
That is ridiculous.
Still, a homecoming in Central.
It sounds nice.
Be careful, Roy.
You've got some enemies
around here in very high places.
I'm ready any time.
My advice to you is to make as
many friends as you can around here.
Friends who will support
you when the time comes.
Which is why I make
this crucial suggestion.
You find yourself a wife.
Give it a rest!
Please, Colonel, don't
take it out on the phone.
Come on, sir!
Get off the desk!
Heh heh.
We've been
searching all morning.
I'm sorry, but these are the
only books that we've recovered.
Out of the whole First Branch?
We'll be okay.
I'm sorry, officers, but I'm not seeing any
books by Tim Marcoh in the main building.
If they'd been moved here from the
First Branch, there'd be a record of it.
Wait a sec.
Isn't it possible that somebody
has it checked out right now?
I suppose.
But the circulation records
were destroyed in the fire.
Gotcha.
I guess we're never
gonna find that book.
If only we could confirm Dr. Marcoh's
book was even in there last night.
That would be a start.
Was anyone else working with
you at the library who might know?
No. Gerald and I were the only two
librarians on staff at the First Branch.
Just two of you?
Being restricted to state alchemists,
we didn't get too much traffic.
Last time I was there, I remember
a mousy girl with glasses on.
Oh, I know.
You're talking about Sheska.
But you must not have been
there lately because she was let go.
Let go?
She was an odd duck.
Never really fit in around here.
Yes, she always had
her nose in a book.
Really?
Guess she's not home.
The lights are on inside.
I'm going in.
You can't do that!
It's nothing but books in there!
I can't believe somebody
actually lives in that.
Excuse me, Ms. Sheska.
You home?
Sheska!
I don't think she's here.
Help me!
Please!
Somebody!
Please help!
She's in here somewhere!
I know!
Just keep digging!
Thank you all so much.
Really.
They always said I'd probably
die with my head in a book.
I just never thought
they meant it literally.
Sheska, you used to work
in the library's First Branch.
Isn't that right?
That's right.
Unfortunately, they fired me for what
they called lackluster performance,
i.e.
reading instead
of doing my work.
I needed that job.
My mom's sick and
I've got to pay her bills.
But being surrounded by all those
books, I couldn't control myself.
Sorry to hear that.
Let me just cut to the chase.
Do you happen to remember ever seeing a book
written by Tim Marcoh while you were working there?
It's really important.
By a Tim Marcoh?
Yeah.
It would probably have been a
thick, handwritten research journal.
Let me see here.
Thick, handwritten
research journal.
Tim Marcoh.
Yeah, I remember now.
It was a leather-bound volume with lots of
handwritten pages, very thorough, plenty of detail.
And you're sure about that?
Yeah, I remember all the books,
especially the ones in the back.
In the back?
Then it was in there and
we'll never get to read it.
Brother.
Sorry about that, guys.
I know how upsetting it can be when you
can't find that one book you're looking for.
It's a tragic story I'm
all too familiar with.
I, myself, once scaled the heights and
plunged the depths of the highest mountain
of books for three days, but still didn't
find the elusive tome I'd been searching for.
It's so tragic.
So very tragic.
Don't do that, Sheska.
You helped us out.
Thanks to you, we at least know
that the book really existed in there.
And now I think I know
what my next move is.
What?
You mean it's not
totally a lost cause?
I'm going to transmute the ashes
of these books to their original forms.
That would be incredible.
You can really do
something like that?
Watch and learn.
Wow, strong wind.
Is that what I was
supposed to be watching for?
I guess we're just
not meant to read it.
Actually, if you want, I can
reproduce the book for you no problem.
I've got a photographic memory, you see,
so I can recreate any book I've ever read.
And since I did read that book while I was
working there in the library... You can do that?
Then why in the world
didn't you say so earlier?
Well, because people have
always made fun of me for it.
But if I can be of some help...
Alrighty, it's all here.
As you can see, it's a
pretty long book, so it took
me three whole days to
get it all down on paper.
And this... this entire
pile is Marcoh's research?
Are you sure?
Yep.
Detailed step-by-step
instructions for everything
from appetizing appetizers
to delectable desserts.
It's Tim Marcoh's 1,000 Recipes
for Making Magic in the Kitchen!
One tablespoon of sugar,
a pinch of salt, a dash
of pepper... nothing too
magical about this recipe.
You think maybe you
got the wrong author?
Not a chance!
I reproduced verbatim what
Dr. Marcoh wrote in those journals.
It was all for naught.
Sorry, Fullmetal.
I don't know.
Huh?
So, Sheska, you're positive every
word's precisely as it was in Dr.
Marcoh's version?
Oh, yes, sir!
No doubt about it!
Sheska, you really
are an amazing talent.
Lieutenant, make sure
she's properly compensated.
You'll see a figure there.
Go to the State Alchemist's Treasury and have
them take that amount out of my research budget.
Al, come on.
I'm right behind you.
But I'm security!
Take care of this Bloch.
I don't get it.
What the heck is he going
to do with the cookbook?
Bake a cake?
That's a lot of money.
If he can authorize that kind of expenditure,
he really must have some reputation.
Sir, wait up!
Where are you going to now?
We're going to hold up in the
Central Library's main building for now.
After all, they've got the best
resources for this sort of work.
No way.
A library was Scar's last
mark, and he's still at large.
It's impossible for us to protect
you in that kind of public venue.
Figuring out a way to do your job
right is your problem, Lieutenant Ross.
Getting the Philosopher's
Stone is mine.
Please try to understand.
We finally got a lead.
So these are Marcoh's notes.
On the surface, they appear
to be an ordinary cookbook.
You really think the secret
to the stone is in here?
It does make sense.
Marcoh didn't want just anyone
to read it, so he wrote it in code.
As for the cookbook disguise,
you know what they say.
Alchemy was born in the kitchen.
So now all we have to do is
crack the secret language of his.
No sweat.
Damn, so much for that
whole no sweat business.
Get a marker,
make a few columns.
I thought it'd be easy.
It'd be a whole lot faster if
we could just ask Marcoh.
We're trying to keep the
military out of the loop here, Al.
And Marcoh's in the
Fuhrer's custody now.
Wakey, wakey.
So how you doing there, boys?
Lieutenant Colonel!
What's the matter?
Been too busy to come say hello?
It's these damn
scar spottings lately.
God is chasing our own tails.
So Al, did you get the full
body repair you needed?
Yes, sir.
Good as new.
They sure are chummy with the
Lieutenant Colonel, don't you think?
Lieutenant Colonel Hughes.
If there were to be an
attack here, we could not
ensure the safety of these
two as we've been ordered.
They should return to
the command center now.
I told you, Ross,
don't get in my way.
Lieutenant Colonel, as
long as Scar remains at large,
security of State Alchemists
must be a top priority.
Sorry, Ed, but I'm afraid
Lieutenant Ross does have a point.
Don't say that.
But, then again, this
really isn't my jurisdiction.
Why don't you take it
up with Major Armstrong?
No, please, anybody
but Armstrong.
We really don't have to do that.
Lieutenant Colonel,
we're close to it now
I can feel it.
I'm begging.
Hmm.
What I'd like to do is give
you extra protection, Ed.
But between hunting down Scar and
scrambling to replace the case files that
were destroyed in the fire, my men
are all completely tied up right now.
All your case files?
You mean they were
stored in the first branch, too?
Yeah.
Affidavit, suspect list,
crime scene logs, all of it.
You're in luck.
Meee!
Really?
Um, I know I wasn't supposed to
look through those military records,
but I ran out of books to
read while I was working there.
Well, that's what
we wanted to hear.
If she can actually do what you say she can,
Ed, that would certainly be a big help for us.
She can do it
all right, trust me.
So what do you say?
Does she have the job?
Honestly?
You mean a weirdo like me whose only skill is
reading might be able to work for the military?
Don't sell yourself short.
The world needs people who really
care about something and work hard at it.
You have a gift, Sheska.
You should own it.
Be proud of yourself.
Thanks, Al.
All right, I'll take the
job if you want me to.
Thank you for
your consideration.
Sure, you're hired.
And now that that's all
settled, let's get right to work.
And you should know,
I pay better than Ed.
Thank you so much.
I guess you win again, Ed.
Now I can free up a couple of additional soldiers
to cover the security in the library for you.
Wow, thanks, pal.
I wasn't even thinking about
that as a possible outcome.
Right.
Night, everyone.
Don't work yourselves too hard.
Just a minute,
Lieutenant Colonel.
Lieutenant Ross, I know full well
what you're going to say to me now.
But I know those boys too,
and they'll do whatever they
want regardless of whether
we give them permission or not.
All that we can do is protect
them as best as we can.
I expect your cooperation.
I can't agree with you just
giving them a blank ticket.
Encouraging them to continue
despite all of the dangers.
With all due respect,
sir, they're only children.
There's more going on
here than you understand.
Those two children in there have the
ability to find something that no one else can.
This state's future is in their hands,
and as adults, it's our job to enable them.
When you have kids,
you'll understand.
Brother!
I see.
You're homunculi.
Clever.
I didn't know there were still humans who
knew that word, let alone believe that we exist.
So sad.
I didn't get to eat him.
Yes, a pity.
I would have liked to have
verified Marcoh's research journal.
But I guess it makes
no difference now.
Oh, you're awake.
Really wasn't expecting that.
I thought we were going
to have to bury you for sure.
Where am I?
Hey, it's true that you're
an Ishbalan, isn't it?
Don't worry, it's not bad.
Everybody else
around this colony is too.
Grandpa! He's up!
He's not dead!
Oh, you must be quite the stubborn
mule to have come back from that one.
Well, you're the
one, aren't you?
The one on all
their wanted posters.
You can relax, warrior.
There's none among us who
would sell out one of our own people.
I had no idea there were this many
Ishbalans alive after the massacre.
It's not just here, my son.
There are settlements like this
scattered all across the country.
Our people are thriving.
Oh, sons of Ishbala, the entirety of the
world is the bosom of the Lord our God.
They still haven't found
what they're looking for, huh?
I haven't the foggiest clue
what they're doing in there,
but I wish they'd give it a
rest so we could go home.
It won't happen.
Look, they won't give up until
they get what they came for.
And we just give them
invisible security until they do.
Damn it!
I get it now.
Why they all call this
quest the Devil's Errand.
Why they either quit their
research or are driven insane by it.
Easy.
The secret, Al.
The last ingredient
of the stone.
It's live human beings.
Hey, what's the matter?
Just when I thought...
Just when I thought it was
finally within our grasp...
You're leaving?
Thank you for all your help.
You know, you could stay.
I do not belong here.
Regardless of my intentions, I've done
too many things to betray God's law.
That tattoo... it's incredible.
Yes.
It was a gift my brother gave
to me, so I couldn't forget.
Metal Alchemist Episode
19, The Truth Behind Truth.
Central Laboratory Number 5. Site of the
Most Hellish Experiments Ever Conducted.