Disguarding two.
Geez, more junk.
Just discard already!
Sorry, I'll take two as well.
Holy!
Hey, Brother, wanna
double the bet?
Suit yourself.
Sorry, I've got a full house.
I'm sorry, too.
Royal flush.
No way!
I thought for sure
I'd win for once.
Okay, this time
I'm gonna ... I quit.
I'm bored.
Bored?
Bored of what?
Winning?
You haven't lost yet.
Why don't you lose
on purpose for a while?
It's not about the cards, Al.
It's who we gotta see.
Mustang.
You don't wanna meet with him?
Of course I don't, Al!
Our best lead on the
stone turned out to be fake.
All this searching, we've
got nothing to show for it.
But we've done lots of good.
Good?
Good goes on a military report
in a sidebar for collateral damage.
I can see his face.
His sarcastic little quips.
Just thinking about it...
makes me completely nauseous.
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Are you sure it's okay to stop?
We're supposed to
go straight to East City.
It's right on the way.
Maybe we'll find something about the
Philosopher's Stone and avoid a lecture.
Besides, Aquroya's
a tourist hotspot.
I've always wanted
to check it out.
Feels kind of like we're
playing hooky, don't you think?
Stop being so...
What do we have here?
What an oddly
good hand of cards.
Ed, you cheater!
Come back.
I want everything
you won for me.
And I thought I
was just unlucky.
Keep running, gentlemen!
I want zero mistakes!
Tonight is the
night we catch her!
Finally, a dead end, Psiren.
Can't walk on water.
What are you waiting for, boys?
No!
It is a beautiful
city, isn't it?
I'll say.
Aquroya, the city of water
and perennial tourist magnet.
It sure beats the heck out of that East
City Dust Bowl and having to see the
colonels know-it-all
grin, don't you think?
What the hell's
your problem, pal?
Well, it is the city of water.
Ugh.
Hey, shouldn't we talk first?
You're coming to the station.
I got some questions
for you, alchemist.
So, you're telling me you're with the
State and that you're the famous Fullmetal,
hero of the people.
How many times do I
have to say it, Chief?
That watch should
be proof enough.
Sure, if it's real.
But I have my doubts.
I say you're too
short for a hero.
Who are you calling so small?
You want to crush like an ant?!
Brother, please.
He didn't say
anything like that.
Sorry for the third degree, kid.
Had to test you.
We've got a thief on our backs named
Psiren and we're all a little on edge.
Psiren?
Yeah.
Real name's unknown.
Only lead we got is
she uses alchemy.
So I thought you just
might be connected.
Hmm...
But you say you're
with the State.
And the Fullmetal
Alchemist, no less.
Damn that guy!
He kept saying the same
things for three hours straight.
He probably wears that hat
to hide the hole in his brain.
Still, doesn't it concern you?
A criminal using
alchemy to steal?
Oh, crud.
Brother, you don't look so good.
My stomach feels...
Well, it looks like a little bit
of food poisoning, that's all.
It's not from eating too much?
Oh, shut up.
We'll need to give
you an injection.
Clara?
Injection?
Yeah, just a poke.
Ah!
Get away from me!
I don't need it!
Just a little needle
and you'll be fine.
Yeah, I feel better.
Don't be be a baby.
Take off your coat.
I hate you, Al!
Why do you want to
sell out your own brother?
You're evil!
You don't mean that.
I'll turn you all into fish!
There.
You're all done, Ed.
That didn't hurt at all, did it?
Fast work.
You didn't even notice.
And after all that fuss...
Yeah, so what's your point?
We all have to grow
up sometime, right?
So, is the rude commentary
included in the bill?
She was so good at her job.
Smart.
And gorgeous, too.
I can't stop thinking about her.
You've got the weirdest
taste in women, Al.
She was a bad gift
in pretty wrapping.
That won't do, Mrs. Crabney.
You can't get better
on an empty stomach.
I'm sorry.
I just can't get it down.
It hurts my teeth.
Well, that bread's
too tough, isn't it?
We'll have to make
you something tastier.
You all right with that, Ed?
Of course.
Just give me a minute.
That looks dangerous.
Let me do it, brother.
You'll hurt yourself.
I'm fine.
Back off!
There we go.
Why don't you boys eat it?
You still with me, Al?
Yeah.
Sorry.
I was just thinking.
That Nurse Clara?
There's something really giving,
calming about her.
She kind of reminds me of Mom.
Don't be ridiculous.
That woman's nothing like her!
I've gotten so clumsy.
Don't worry about it.
It's just a piece of fruit.
Good as new.
You're alchemists.
I didn't realize that.
Mr. Elric!
Let's make a tape
saying I'm innocent.
You can play it
back all you want.
I know you are.
I know.
And this time I'm
asking you for a favor.
Officers, presenting State
Alchemist Master Edward Elric.
Salute!
Jeez.
So, what do you want?
First, I want to
apologize for earlier.
All those questions.
I did what you said, sir.
I got in touch with Colonel Mustang
at the Eastern Command Center.
I paid long distance
and everything.
He sounded nice.
Angry, but nice.
He said you really
are a State Alchemist.
I sure pegged you wrong.
Like I said.
Yes, indeed, sir.
In light of this new information,
I wanted to ask you...
I'll need more.
As much as you like.
This is it.
Psiren's next Mark.
With you on our side, that thief's
hold on this city will finally unravel.
Yeah.
I'll do whatever I can tonight.
But that's a lot of people.
A lot of ways for
things to go wrong.
That's Psiren's M.O.
Most thieves don't announce
their heists before they happen.
Psiren tells every
paper in the country.
Journalists, thrill-seekers,
even Psiren groupies flock to see.
It's become a spectator sport.
It is quite a following.
Well, the stardom ends tonight.
It's amazing how quick your popularity
fades when you're wearing stripes.
I'm going to check
the security station.
I'm kind of surprised
you took this job.
Guess I'm just curious.
Yet another way to use
alchemy to do wrong...
Clever move.
Come on Al.
Hey! Hold it!
Alchemy's the greatest thing
we humans have going for us.
And yet here you are stealing with
it and making things even worse.
Not to mention I put up with a very
mindnumbing interrogation because of you.
I'd say you owe
me a major apology.
You've just been pinned, Psiren.
I didn't mean that!
You've never fought with
a woman before, have you?
Makes for a whole
new style of action.
Err!
Hey! That was a dirty trick!
It's a shame I can't
show you my face.
It's a real treat.
Sleep tight, pipsqueak.
Who are you calling a pipsqueak?
You know I'd be
tall, too, in heels!
Al.
Al!
You'd think I could keep track
of a seven foot suit of armor.
You.
What a surprise.
The kind nurse is really Psiren.
Or do all women here
have tattoos on their chests?
I... I don't know what you mean.
But I can't talk.
I just came in to
get some medicine.
Right.
And medicine that you
manufacture using alchemy.
Now drop the act,
you lying fraud.
Come on now, little man.
Who's telling lies?
I did say that I was
beautiful under the mask.
That's hardly the point!
Brother?
Brother, bad news.
Is something wrong?
What do you think, Al?
Look at her!
That nurse you
thought was so great?
She's Psiren!
The transmutation
circle's proof enough!
The world isn't black
and white like you think.
You kids are too
young to understand.
A lot can happen in life and--
Please!
I understand.
I just found out.
This hospital's scheduled
to be demolished.
Clara, you became a thief out
of necessity and compassion.
You're trying to save
this place, aren't you?
Yeah, that's right.
You think I like this, flinching
at every passing patrol.
But this hospital needs
money for all its patients.
I needed to...
See, Ed?
I told you she had heart.
Just like Mom.
Mr. Elric!
A new notice from Psiren!
Am I interrupting something?
Mr. Elric?
Looks like you've got
less security this time.
Yeah.
Psiren's made mules of
my men too many times.
I'm trying something different.
We've got a little trap rigged up in
that mansion right next to her target.
A trap?
Don't worry, you'll
see it soon enough.
No one will call our force
incompetent anymore.
I'll hang her little
suit over my desk.
But stick around.
We'll need you if
anything goes wrong.
What are you going to do?
Now what?
Thanks, kid.
It was a good break.
Why'd you help?
It's nothing personal.
I wasn't helping you.
I know a little about bending the
rules sometimes to do what's right.
It was for the hospital.
What's so funny?
Nothing.
You just sounded so grown-up.
I am grown-up, okay?
Is that so?
Well, as a grown-up woman,
I always repay my favors.
Is there something you'd like me to
do for you, Mr. All-Grown-Up Man?
Actually, there is one thing.
You're a savvy alchemist.
You must have heard of
the Philosopher's Stone.
I want you to tell me
anything that you know about it.
I have to get it, no matter
what or how long it takes.
Sorry, Edward.
I can't help you with that.
But how about this?
If you ever do figure out where a Stone is,
tell me and I'll be happy to steal it for you.
Hey.
I'm happy that you can
do this for the hospital.
Yeah.
Thanks to you, Ed.
What's going on here?
Don't tell me that
Flake tricked us.
That couldn't be.
Claire's the last person who
would do something like that.
This has to be a mistake.
The only mistake here is inside
that metal skull of yours, Al.
She's robbed you of your senses
and played you like a freaking harp.
Don't say that, Brother.
You know what'll happen.
Brothers shouldn't argue.
It's sinful.
Am I imagining this?
Wish you were.
It's terrible about
the hospital.
I tried to save it, but I
couldn't get the money in time.
I was devastated.
The guilt was too much.
I didn't know how to go on.
So I became a nun.
Poor Clara!
Yeah, I bet.
It's the truth, Ed.
But those who do
believe will be saved.
The Great Lord has told me
there are other places that need me.
Like this convent
we're standing in.
It's scheduled to
be demolished, too.
I only pray I can help.
You'll do it, Clara.
You just need to
try harder this time.
We'll help however we can.
Brother, more news!
Yeah, what is it?
They're saying
Psiren struck again.
The whole city's in an uproar.
She did it!
The convent is gonna be saved!
It has to be a mistake.
Maybe she couldn't find someone to sell
what she-- Have your brains turned to mush?
She's a con artist, Al.
She's been snowing
us for a good laugh!
The only saving she's
doing is in her bank account!
Don't start that again.
That's not how she is!
Do I need to put you
two boys in a corner?
Ah!
Wait!
And which dress-up doll outfit
are you wearing today, Clara?
I know!
You're a schoolteacher, right?
You're working for a school that's about to be
shut down, and this time you won't be too late.
Isn't that right, Clara?
Isn't it?
You guessed it.
But maybe we shouldn't
talk about it with the K.I.D.s.
Like you care.
Stop jerking us around.
What are you?
Really?
Nothing but a thief, after all.
A common criminal who uses
alchemy for her own selfish gains!
That's a very good question, Ed.
But as I tell my children, students,
the best answers we find on our own.
Extra!
Phantom Thief Psiren
announces her next big time mark!
Why do you people
buy into that junk?
She's nothing but a thief
who's feeding off the attention.
What are you talking about?
We owe Psiren for
saving this place.
Attention's the
least we can give.
She's Aquroya's Star of Hope.
You're gonna have to
explain that one to me.
We're the City of Water.
And we're sinking.
By several feet a year.
Come see us in five years' time, and the
whole place will be at the bottom of the lake.
News like that isn't exactly
good for the economy.
When it went public,
everyone who could left.
The rest of us, well,
we got lonely and sad.
That's when she appeared.
Psiren.
Like a lit match on a
fuse, the city burst into life.
Reporters came from all over.
Tourists flocked here again
for a chance to see her.
Thanks to Psiren, we're having
one last bloom before we drown.
What do you think, brother?
I mean, it kind of makes sense.
Maybe Clara really did
become a thief to save the city.
In a different way
than we thought.
Maybe.
I guess the only thing I
can say for sure is this:
She tricked me.
The Fullmetal Alchemist.
And she's at least
going to pay for that.
I thought you'd show up.
It's phenomenal, isn't it?
A date here, on the
water, in the moonlight.
Just the two of us...
Shut up, thief.
Oh dear, romance
me with small talk.
Yes, a thief.
Someone obsessed with
objects that don't belong to them.
Like the Philosopher's Stone?
Maybe so.
It's funny.
Every crook I meet wants to tell
me how much I'm just like them.
But there's a big difference
between us and the burdens we bear.
Yes, bare.
Love to.
See ya, kid.
I can't breathe.
That was pretty sharp, kid.
I'm sure you're going
to be a fine grownup.
When you are, let's
do this deal again.
It's always more fun when
it's a woman and a man.
Clara.
But let me offer you one last
little kernel before they haul me off.
About a certain funny Stone?
Go to the city of Xenotime
and take a good look.
I've heard there's someone there who's
researching the components behind it.
Maybe he could help you out.
Xenotime...
Come on, Al.
Are you still holding
a grudge on me?
I had no choice, you know.
I was the officer and
she was the crook.
We just played our part.
That's not true.
She's not a crook.
You've told me plenty
of times that you can't
always go by the rules
or follow the norms
when you're doing what's right.
Clara... she's kind
and giving and heroic.
You think the
same thing, Brother.
I'm sure you do.
I don't know, Al...
When it comes to
her, I guess I never will.
Hey, it's an oven in here.
I don't guess you'd
mind unzipping me a little.
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 11:
The Other Brothers
Elric, Part 1.
Another Brother, Another me.
And one red stone that
binds us all together.