Funny, I hear greed
finally bit the big one.
Indeed.
And in a sense, his death
suited him in the most perfect way.
Violence so intense, it
bordered on the beautiful.
Ed can murder us all he wants.
You know who
will just replace us.
Speaking of, Sloth is taking
care of the new wrath as we speak.
Just think of the
possibilities it'll present.
Is something wrong?
Don't let this get to you.
Greed was weak, so he died.
End of story.
It's not that.
Have you ever wondered
where we come from?
Or where we go after we're dead?
You're a mess.
Sorry, folks, but if you don't mind,
I'm just about to close up shop here.
Do what you will,
but we're not leaving.
Oh, you're not, huh?
We've grown to
like it here at Tubbs.
I think we'll be staying.
Now you listen to me!
Hey, stranger!
Lousy service.
Can I eat him?
We did skip dessert.
See you outside.
The thought keeps rising like
a bubble to the top of my mind.
Where did I come from?
Where will I go?
Oh no!
Jimmy, talk to me!
Say something!
Excuse me!
Make way!
May I see him?
I might be able to help.
There you go.
Good as new.
I can't thank you enough!
Is that you?
Lujon...
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Are you sure we're
on the right road?
All I know is we're heading south, and we're
bound to run into the Ishbal camp sooner or later.
Sooner than later, I hope.
But what makes you believe the Ishbalan refugees will
tell you anything about the Philosopher's Stone anyway, Ed?
Because it's the only lead we've got, and we have to
take every chance that we have to get closer to the stone.
What is it?
I thought... I thought I heard a
woman scream just now, but I'm...
No, get away!
Who the hell are you?
Come on, guys.
A band of thugs in the forest?
That's so cliché.
What was that, shortstop?
Ed.....
It's been two years.
I never thought I'd see you again,
and I've got so much to tell you.
But before I go into that, there's
something I need to ask you.
It's just... I've never been
able to come to terms with it.
The reason you left,
Lust, can you tell me that?
You just disappeared.
You didn't even say goodbye.
That was a long time ago.
You can't expect me to recall.
I sure as hell do!
Everything I know that's
meaningful, I learned from you!
Alchemy!
And more delicate things.
About life.
Why have you come here?
You've never left your village.
Are you looking for something?
Well, yes.
I'm in search of a new stone.
You recall that, right?
Thanks to the Philosopher's Stone you gave me, I
saved my whole village from that horrible disease.
But now, somehow, that
damn sickness has returned.
And the power of
the stone has faded.
Please.
Will you lend me
your strength again?
Help me save them
like you did before
Lust?
I need you.
It must have been a landslide.
Just look at all those bodies.
Can I eat them?
Can I eat them, please?
No, leave them be.
I've been meaning
to put you on a diet.
We have a survivor.
Take these.
Please.
Take these herbs
back to my village.
They need them desperately.
Over there!
I see them!
If anyone can hear me, answer!
Lydia.
Lydia!
Come on, Lydia.
Hold on.
I'm so sorry, Lujon.
Here, take them.
I told you not to go.
It was too dangerous.
These herbs won't
do us any good.
What are you two doing here?
I saw you earlier back
in the carriage, right?
You should leave.
Or it's too late.
There's an outbreak
of fossil disease.
And no one who's contracted
it has survived for very long.
That's why we've come.
I'll cure it.
I'll wipe that disease
off the face of the planet.
You'll see.
I'll do it with alchemy.
So you're traveling by
yourself to find this Lujon guy?
Yes.
You shouldn't have come alone.
It can be pretty
dangerous out here.
Even if you do have
someone along to help you out.
I know.
But I had a feeling if I didn't come,
I'd never get to see Lujon again.
And I don't know if I
could deal with that.
So, why is it that this Lujon guy
left your village in the first place?
For good reason.
To search for another
Philosopher's Stone.
That's nice.
The stone?!
Yes.
In order to cure a horrible epidemic in my village,
we need the power of the Philosopher's Stone.
So Lujon set
out in search of it.
Because only the stone has the power to combat
the terrible disease that no medicine can cure.
Okay, Lydia.
Drink this.
It should make you feel better.
Thanks, Lujon.
Looks like you came out
pretty unscathed, considering.
Lydia!
What is it?
What's wrong?
Are you hurt?
No, it's nothing.
The saucer just
slipped out of my hand.
Lujon!
Are you here?
It's my son.
He needs help.
The body becomes like stone.
Soon it'll be solid.
Motionless.
He'll die.
Frozen in agony.
All things evil and unclean
must leave this child at once.
Almighty, hear the cries of
pain and anguish and give aid.
Answer the prayers of the stricken child and
drive from his body the evil that dwells within him.
The enemy will fall
in cower and shame.
Victory will belong to the light,
which conquers the curse of darkness.
I'm sorry.
Vanjie, no!
He can't!
He was my only son!
How could this happen?
All of my efforts
haven't done anything!
What's the point
in even trying now?
Please, hear your loyal servant.
Just send us aid.
Please help us.
Please help me.
Help me save her, Ishbala.
I love her so much.
God of Ishbal, please
don't take her from me.
Spare their lives.
I beg you.
Breaking down the body's dead
parts, those already lost to the disease,
and rebuilding them to their original state seems to be your
only recourse now that conventional medicine has failed.
You are too inexperienced
with alchemy to do that.
But I will teach you.
You'll learn the
power of true Alchemy.
I'm so glad you're coming
back to the village with me.
I can't say that enough.
I told everyone back home I was
leaving to look for the Philosopher's Stone,
and that was the truth.
But really, I was hoping I
would find you most of all.
I wanted to see you as well.
I've had this strong
feeling since I left.
Like a door left unclosed.
It's really no problem.
We're headed that
way ourselves, actually.
Glad to hear it.
But I still feel bad for going
back home without finding Lujon.
Well, what did you expect?
If you don't have any good
leads, how can you find him?
It's certainly not your fault.
I don't mean to pry, but is
this Lujon guy your boyfriend?
I know it's none of my business.
Not quite.
He left me.
To be honest, I've loved him
as long as I can remember.
But there's another woman
he loves far more than me.
So this is where you
practice the great art.
It's quite a library.
Hey, what are you doing?
They're mostly junk.
The first step is finding
which ones are true.
I want you to read
these all in exact order.
And memorize every word.
I can't!
I just can't get
my head around it!
I don't understand!
It's okay, you will in due time.
You have talent,
so be confident.
It does wonders for a man.
These memories... why
does he make me have them?
And who is that man?
Good.
That's right.
What's this?
It's my gift to you.
This Philosopher's Stone will magnify your
Alchemic power and help you get the things you desire.
Man must crawl before he
walks and walk before he flies.
See if you can return this bird to the air
and then maybe you're ready to move on.
May the great creator save this creature
and watch over him so he does not stray.
Let it be so through day and
night under sun and moon.
No evil shall harm him.
As I, a humble servant, employ the knowledge
that God gave us to bring him back to life.
I actually did it!
Well, what did I
tell you, Lujon?
I knew you had talent
buried somewhere.
It's all because of you.
Thank you.
I have to ask again.
Why did you have to abandon
me the way you did, Lust?
Why did you run away?
You must have known how I felt.
Or did you even care at all?
You shouldn't seek all
the answers, believe me.
You might not
like what you find.
I don't understand.
What are you trying to say?
I'm not too proud.
I'll beg you, please
don't take him from me.
Did he tell you that we're
engaged, Lujon and I?
We're going to be married
just as soon as I get better.
My, how sweet.
You'll have to invite
me to the wedding.
I'll be sure to
catch the bouquet.
Stop treating me like a child!
I mean it!
Leave us alone!
Lydia, with this power
I will make you well.
Let the disease which wrecks
her body in pain be forced out.
Let the pure body
reject the evil presence.
Watch over her, God.
So that through all hours of the day and
night, under sun and moon, she might be
cleansed of this plague
and protected from harm.
That's amazing.
Lujon, save my son!
Help me!
How have the lessons been going?
There's nothing to worry about.
Everything's going
exactly as planned.
I'm counting on you.
Why do you think I spread
this epidemic in the first place?
It wasn't just for laughs.
Lujon's managed to cure the disease
with a fake Philosopher's Stone.
They're so happy.
But that won't last for long as the power of the stone I
gave him becomes unstable and gradually fades away.
And then the ball
will start rolling.
And the man in the pit of despair with
the taste of forbidden fruit on his tongue
will search for the real
Philosopher's Stone.
And do our work for us.
We've done it time
and time again.
Deja vu or something.
And all for a little stone.
Excuse me.
Oh, Lydia.
You're as beautiful as ever.
Thank you.
Have you seen Lujon yet?
Isn't it about time for
the ceremony to start?
I don't know.
Probably.
Listen, I don't know
how to say this.
You've taught me
more than just alchemy.
Things I don't
want to just forget.
What are you talking about?
I want you by my side.
Forever.
Who are you?
Why do you haunt me?
I want you to go to her, Lujon.
I can't.
You heard me.
Lust, please.
Right now.
Lydia!
Lust, you sure it's
okay we leave now?
Envy scary.
We're approaching the village.
Hold on, guys.
I've come back to help.
Catch me!
You're too fast!
You've saved me
and this village.
Just like you
did the first time.
Do you remember it now?
That day, I held you and
you were happy, I know.
But this time it's
gonna be different.
This time, I won't let go.
Don't go!
Please!
You don't have to
hide from how you feel.
No!
I love you!
We'll be happy, Lust.
No!
W...Why?
You are my little mistake.
Nothing more.
Where did I come from?
And where will I go?
Not for me to know.
Lujon!
Lujun!
Lujon, are you here?
Where are you?
Answer me!
Hello?!
Lydia!
How could this be?
What is this?
Hey...
Hey..... Lust, I'm hungry.
Please, just one.
Lust!
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 36, The sinner within.
When people see my Automail,
they get scared because it's unknown.
I don't blame them
for that feeling.
But feelings
aren't always right.