That ought to do it.
You ready?
Don't be scared, Al.
Everything's perfect.
Let's go for it.
Alchemy the science of
understanding the structure of matter.
Breaking it down, then reconstructing it
as something else.
It can even make gold from lead.
But alchemy is a science.
So it must follow the natural laws.
To create, something of equal value must
be lost.
This is the principle of equivalent
exchange.
But on that night, I
learned the value of some
things can't be measured
on a simple scale.
[SCREAMS]
That was Edward!
Wait Winry, look!
My brother and I knew the laws of science.
Of equivalent exchange.
That gain required sacrifice.
That something had to be taken from us.
But we thought there was
nothing more we could lose.
We were wrong.
No.
Alphonse, say something!
Al, no!
Stay with me!
Dammit!
This wasn't supposed to...
AHHHH!
What have I done?
He's gone.
Mom?
Is that you?
[Ed screaming]
I hate deserts!
ERRAHH.
It's nothing but sand!
If I had some grass, I could turn it into
bread.
I'm starving!
Eh.
Hey Al, where'd you going?
AL!
Hey!
Down here!
AHHHHHH!
I sunk again.
Reason number two I hate the desert.
I don't understand
why you keep falling in!
I get full!
Full of what?
Get back here!
What are you gonna do?
Nothing!
Then why are you chasing me?
Stop and you'll find out!
I promise I won't get buried again!
Not unless it's by me!
Ed!
Are you ok brother?
It's your fault for not stopping when I
said.
You wouldn't stop either if someone were
chasing you.
Shut up.
I'm too tired to fight.
I can almost hear it.
Wait a second.
I can't hear it.
Al!
Look!
Hey, wait!
Water, water, water, water, water,
water, water!
Guess this explains the nasty stench in
the air.
What's wrong?
Hm?
Is it blood?
Nope.
More like blood red wine.
Hey!
Get away from there!
You know that's off limits to kids.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
You're out of towners.
That explains it.
You'll have to forgive me.
I thought you were trying to sneak a
little nip.
Fountain stocked with free wine?
That's pretty ritzy.
This town must be loaded.
Yeah, we do all right here.
Oh!
I almost forgot.
Time for a little soul food.
Children of God who live upon this land,
pray in faith that ye may be saved.
As sun lights the day,
so does the sun god Leto
illuminate thy path, and
draw near to the sun.
Well, that's freakish.
Some kind of religious broadcast.
Your buddy's in a suit of
armor, and you're wearing
gloves in the desert,
and you call us freaks?
May this town be blessed, and may we
continue to experience growth and prosperity.
What's your deal, anyway?
You street performers?
I don't think so, Pops.
Do I look like a clown to you?
Well, you must have some
reason to journey out this far.
We're just trying to track something down,
that's all.
Now, who is this guy on your airwaves?
Why, that's Sir Cornello.
Ah.
Doesn't ring a bell.
You're kidding me!
You've never heard of the great prophet
Cornello?
What's great about him?
He can perform miracles, for one thing.
I've never seen anything like it.
This town was a godforsaken
dust bowl before Cornello
got here and transformed
it into a desert paradise.
Cornello can even forgive sins.
Yeah, we're on the sun god's
good side because of him.
He gives us blessings.
Ah.
I just remembered.
We have to be somewhere.
You ready to split?
Yeah.
Okay.
Oops.
Now you've done it, buddy.
What do you expect wearing a stupid tin
suit?
Don't bust a lung, Grandpa.
We can fix it.
It's in a thousand pieces!
I'm sorry.
Let me try.
Sure.
That drawing.
What's it for?
You'll see in just a second.
It's called the transmutation circle.
Okay.
Here goes.
If you are lost, follow
me and you will be found.
It's really a land of prophets.
Your buddy can work miracles like
Cornello.
It's nothing like that.
It's science.
We're Alchemists.
We're the Elric brothers.
Not to brag or anything, but we're pretty
well known.
Elrics?
Not familiar.
We don't have any alchemists in these
parts.
I fix things for a living though.
Let me know if you need a job.
He doesn't need any work.
That's Edward Elric, the Fullmetal
Alchemist.
He's been a celebrity around D City.
They say he's a real child prodigy.
Heh.
Wow, a real-life famous person.
I see, you got the name Fullmetal because
you wear that armor.
Hey, would you come to my daughter's
birthday party?
Uh, I'm not the Fullmetal Alchemist.
He is.
You mean that little shorty there?
Shorty‽
Could a shorty do this?
What else you wanna call me, a half-bite
beach-proud midget?
I'm still growing, you backwater desert
idiots!
I see there's plenty of excitement around
here today.
Ah, Rose.
Don't mind me, I'd
hate to spoil all the fun.
That's okay.
My name's Alphonse Elric.
Nice to meet you.
And I'm Edward, Al's older brother,
also known as the Fullmetal Alchemist.
Older brother?
But shouldn't it be the other way around?
ERR!
Easy, Edward.
Hehehehe
Hey Rose, have you finished
your shopping for today's offering?
Yeah.
Well then, maybe you could take them to
Temple with you.
They say they're looking for something.
I bet Father Cornelo could help out.
You know, have them ask for God's grace.
Uh, that's okay.
We don't really... It's alright if
you don't have an offering today.
And besides, he has rooms for
travelers you could stay there tonight.
Thanks, but, uh...
As a matter of fact, we'd love to
take you up on that, wouldn't we, Al?
We would?
You mean you want to?
Mm-hmm.
It sure is nice to see
a smile on Rose's face.
Yeah, she's beginning to
act like her old self again.
Her heart must be healing at last.
Hey Al, remember that woman at the shop?
She knew me.
Have we met before?
No, I don't think so.
You shouldn't worry.
Hm?
I'm sure Cornelo will help you find what
you're looking for.
And besides, if you show him you're
faithful, I bet he could make you taller.
What's wrong with you people?
I'm not short!
You come from a desert
tribe of giants or something!
Edward, please!
You want some of this too?
Serve in true faith that all thy prayers
may be answered.
As a man opens blinds
to let the light flood in, so
open thy heart that the
sun god may shine on you.
Choice words is always your holiness.
Yes, Father.
We'd be lost without you.
Father Cornelo?
Ah, Rose.
Pardon me, Cray.
May I put some travelers
in the pilgrim's quarters?
You really delight in helping
others solve their troubles, don't you?
Well, that's what you teach us,
Father Cornelo.
So that's what I do.
Or try to.
And God sees those good deeds
and writes them all down in stone.
But you must be patient, Rose.
We need a little more time
to grant the miracle you seek.
Yes.
I spoke to Rose.
That grave belongs to her boyfriend.
He was all she had.
Her parents died when
she was a little girl.
She's convinced that Cornelo
can bring him back to life.
And he's leading her on and
letting her think he can do it.
Well, maybe he can.
What if Cornelo really is a holy man?
Those scriptures.
Maybe there is something else out there.
Something we can't explain.
Don't count on it.
What do you think?
Well, it looks pretty obvious.
He's using alchemy.
Yeah, but still.
Something's wrong.
It's not equal... Hey, guys!
How are you liking your
first miracle gathering?
He's amazing, isn't he?
Well, he's an amazing
actor, I'll give him that.
But those aren't miracles.
He's swindling you.
Now, Ed, we don't know that.
We just know he's using alchemy and he's
ignoring the laws.
What laws?
This isn't witchcraft.
It's a science.
And you don't make things out of thin air.
In chemistry, a reaction has to be
balanced.
So does alchemy.
It's an equation, Rose.
Your output has to be of equal mass to the
materials you started with.
The base elements have to be similar,
too.
Like the radio I fixed.
I can make it bigger.
Or a tree or something.
It's our founding principle.
To obtain something of
equal value must be lost.
But that Holy
bastards totally disregarding the law.
Because he's working miracles!
What do you say now, Ed?
I'll bet you can't do that with alchemy.
It's a true miracle.
It has to be.
Edward Elric?
Yes, Cray.
Word has it that he was certified as a state
alchemist when he was only 12 years old.
They call him the Fullmetal Alchemist.
You're sure it's him, Father?
I'm afraid so.
The military they represent must have
witnessed our paradise and wished to intervene.
They are greedy, evil souls.
We must save my children from them.
Understand?
I will carry out the will of God.
Your heavenly reward
will be great, my dear Cray.
The boy's presence troubles me.
I don't like it.
Don't you worry.
Even if Cray should fail,
there is one other way.
So?
If you pray and polish
the altar enough times,
Someone who's dead
will be brought back to life?
Something like that.
Water, 35 liters.
Carbon, 20 kilograms.
Ammonia, 4 liters.
Lime, 1.5 kilograms.
Phosphorus, 800 grams.
Salt, 250 grams.
Saltpeter, 100 grams.
Sulfur, 80 grams.
Fluorine, 7.5.
Iron, 5.
Silicon, 3 grams.
And trace amounts of 15 other elements.
What's that?
It's all the ingredients of the
average adult human body,
down to the last specks of
protein in your eyelashes.
And even though science has given us the
entire physical breakdown, there's never
been a successful attempt
at bringing a human to life.
There's still something missing.
Something scientists haven't been
able to find in centuries of research.
So what makes you
think that hack-job priest
with his parlor tricks
is going to be able to?
And in case you're
wondering, all those
ingredients can be bought
on a child's allowance.
Humans can be built on the cheap,
if there's no magic to it.
Well, if there's no magic, then you bring
someone back to life!
Just a matter of time, Rose.
Science will find a way.
Science is the answer to everything.
If I were you, I'd drop the scriptures and
pick up an alchemy book.
We're the closest things to gods there
are.
You're not a god.
You're nothing close to it.
And neither is the sun.
It's just a mass of hydrogen.
Get close to it like Cornelo claims,
and all you'll do is burn up.
Great, Ed.
Push your total cynicism on someone else.
Don't worry, Elric.
Your brother will join you soon.
Cray what are you doing?
These two are enemies of God.
This is his will, Rose, not mine.
I don't think so, mister.
I got it!
Strike!
He doesn't have a head!
Yeah, that's Al.
Please don't be scared, Rose.
This is how I am.
But you're not there.
It's true.
I don't have a body.
But I'm here.
This is my punishment for setting foot on
holy ground where mortals are forbidden.
We made a mistake, Rose.
And we're paying for it.
Rose, wait!
Cray was right.
They are evil.
What have I done?
They made me doubt you, Cornelo.
Forgive me.
Please.
I can't see a church
social down here, can you?
There she is!
You've wrestled with the
darkness and prevailed Rose.
Thank you for bringing them here.
State alchemists, brutal enforcers.
I had a feeling one of you
would show up someday.
Well, let's not chalk that up
to pious premonitions, okay?
You knew we'd come for the stone.
Errr.
Do you mean this, young man?
I knew it.
Alchemy without a transmutation circle.
Completely ignoring the
principle of equivalent exchange.
It could only mean one thing.
Yes, the mythical gem.
The legendary amplifier.
The philosopher's stone.
That's it, Al.
It's ours.
Cough it up, Cornelo.
That stone belongs to me now.
And if you hand it
over peacefully, I won't
tell the people here
what you've been doing.
What's that?
Restoring their town to peace and
prosperity?
Do you know what would happen if my
miraculous wonders suddenly stopped?
Nobody wants that.
Do they, Rose?
Don't listen to him, Rose!
He's just a conman!
Nonsense.
Would a conman restored
life to a dying town?
When I arrived, this town was
full of strife and I brought peace.
They came to me with parched
throats and I created water.
I built buildings for them
and even gave them money.
They believed that
heaven had forsaken them,
but I gave them hope
and became their prophet.
Why does the military
want to destroy all this?
I don't care what the military wants.
I'm here for me.
What?
I need that stone.
We need it to make something right again.
So that's it?
This is all about you and what you want.
What about us?
You don't care.
Rose, we're only
trying to... It's no use.
Enough.
There is no point in arguing.
If you want the Philosopher's
Stone, you'll have to take it from me!
AHHH!
Al!
Ed!
Hold on!
Armor is a disadvantage in soft sand.
You can't draw transmutation
circles in it either.
Let me introduce you
to one of my creations.
You of all people will
be able to appreciate this.
A Chimera.
You combined animals.
The most depraved kind of alchemy there
is.
Maybe so, but most effective!
ROAR!!!
All right, big fella.
You want to play?
Let's go for it!
H-H-How'd-did you do that
without a transmutation circle?
Bring me his head, my pet!
NHAHAHA Now snap it!
Err
Wrong leg, pal!
And here's the right arm!
AHH!
Errrrr.....
Huh?
[SQUELCHING NOISES]
What's the matter, you poor bastard?
Can't get a good taste?
Mouth-watering... Ayy Glulitany...
That's impossible!
Those claws on your leg!
The teeth on your arm!
No one could survive that!
Unless...
Ah.
Your limbs!
They're fake!
Brilliant deduction!
Oh, God!
Don't look away, Rose!
You need to see what happens
when you try to bring a human to life!
When you cross into God's
territory or whatever the hell it is!
Is this what you want‽
Look!
His arm!
His leg!
They're machines!
I see.
Now I understand you, Elric.
You crossed the line.
You did what is strictly forbidden.
You tried to create human life and
your bodies were taken to the other side.
Told you, Rose.
Get too close to the sun and you burn.
Apparently so.
But you were crazy enough
to find out for yourself!
You are the Fullmetal!
The Fullmetal Alchemist!
Fullmetal Alchemist.
Episode Two, Body
of the Sanctioned.
A counterfeit Philosopher's Stone,
brings false promises, and false relief.
But the tears it brings, are real.