What's going on?
I feel strange.
My body...
You bastard!
My work is so intricate, only an
explosives artist like myself can defuse it.
But you'll have to find somebody
else, because I'm about to retire.
No need to hurry.
You still have
plenty of time left.
I've made his armor react slowly with the oxygen in
the air, gradually spreading until he's completely black.
I want him to have time to think about his death
and reflect on how meaningless his efforts have been.
No!
It has to be a lie!
My body!
I'm scared.
Stay still, Alphonse Elric.
I'm not sure what's happening with your
body, but we don't want to make it any worse.
Just try not to exert yourself.
I wouldn't touch him if I
were you, scarred man.
Homunculus.
Just leave us alone.
That arm's only good for
destroying things, not remaking them.
Now, if Edward were here, he'd be able
to transmute his brother into some other
substance, disrupting Kimbley's
alchemy and stopping this bomb.
You think that would work?
Altering his composition?
Leave him.
He's a lost cause.
Miles, you have to think of yourself now
and your own goal of forging the Stone.
Just as I thought.
You aren't my brother's love.
The woman I knew would never
have acted so heartless and cold.
Stop it!
Shut up!
Shut that thing up!
Ed...
Get up Ed!
Get up!
And move forward!
Go Rose!
Get out of here!
Get off me!
Get off!
Damn it!
I'm not gonna sit back and let you
keep using my right arm for your alchemy!
It's mine now!
Now now, that's enough, Ed.
Come here.
Give Mom a hug,
my Prince of Cool.
No, Ed!
Don't do it!
It's been haunting
me for a while now.
Your appearance.
So much like her.
Still, I tried as hard as I
could not to think about it.
Not to face the truth.
What we made... on that night...
We created you.
Hmph.
Ed!
So it's true what you are.
Our sin and our burden to bear!
Clearly, you're with them.
Okay, so we know you've
been working in the Military.
But why?
What's the point?
Don't touch her!
I'll kill you!
Come on, Rose.
Let's go.
It takes more than that to end the
life of a Homunculus for good, Ed.
You'll never defeat them if
that's the best you can do.
Isn't it great, Rose?
Your voice!
It's finally back!
I guess so.
Thank you.
And thank you for telling
me what I needed to hear.
And...
for your baby's cry.
I haven't heard anything
from Kimbley yet.
Or from your chimeras,
for that matter.
They're under the
Führer's command.
I don't know why
there'd be a problem.
Well, obviously there is.
If there's not a problem,
then why aren't they back yet?
How long does it take
to find a kid's corpse?
Have Scar and Kimbley
killed each other in battle?
Or is the Crimson Alchemist
just out having too much fun?
There's no time for this!
So this is your little
command center, huh?
Cozy.
If I'd known you were coming,
I would have cleaned up.
You hands are...
What is that thing?
There's no need to be cruel.
Lieutenant, calm down.
He's no threat.
No, just a pity.
His name is Shou Tucker, called the Sewing
Life Alchemist back when he was a human.
Hello, Major.
Huh.
I take it you've had a sudden change
of heart and won't be helping me now.
I've never been on
your side, Archer.
I've only been playing the part.
I had to get to the bottom of the
corruption plaguing our Military.
And sometimes you have to
play with vermin to sniff out a rat.
You're naive if you think you can have a
useful Military without a little corruption.
Tucker!
What are you hoping to
accomplish with this circus act?
A decade ago, you annihilated Ishbal
and came back a hero of the state.
Now I have Lior.
It's my turn for fame.
Come look!
Tehehehehe.
Death.
Soon they'll all be dead!
Not if that human wannabe can't get a grip on
her own emotions... and pull it together in time.
We'll see.
I suppose her musings are fine
as long as she takes care of Scar...
and makes sure that he too
becomes an ingredient in the Stone.
The Philosopher's Stone?
We still get one?
We'll take it ourselves
after everyone else is dead.
It will be as if the Stone
never existed at all.
I'm sorry I don't live
up to your memories.
I would never have
expected you to.
I told you.
You are not the same woman
my brother tried to resurrect.
You just look like her.
But if I use the Philosopher's
Stone to be human, I'll become her.
No you won't.
How do you know?
Because the dead can
never come back to life.
What are you gonna do to him?
Tell me dammit!
Stay back!
Now just shut your
mouth and watch.
Now what have you done?
That arm...
was given to me by my brother.
He trapped the souls of
the dying Ishbalans inside it.
By turning his own body
into a transmutation circle.
He did that for good reason.
To create the Philosopher's
Stone within himself.
A gift that he passed on to you.
So that means...
I've attached the
locket to his armor.
That way you can't
get anywhere near him.
You can only stand
back and watch.
Have you lost your mind?
You wanna turn this boy
into the Philosopher's Stone?
Better that than a bomb.
You said that if we changed his body
into something else he wouldn't explode.
It was the only
way I could help.
And what about the actual stone?
Don't tell me you're planning to hand
it over to those boys when you're done.
I don't even know
whether or not this will work.
But if by some miracle it
does... the stone will be theirs.
They can do with
it what they want.
I'm afraid I can't
let you do that.
I need you to make the real
Philosopher's Stone, you understand?
Don't waste all your work, all the
work of your brother just to save that boy.
How is that going
to fulfill your dreams?
If you kill me where I stand right now... would
that help you make your dream come true?
Have it your way.
And if there does come a time when a
stone is made... I'll find a way to use it myself.
Whatever happens to that poor
boy now... it's not my responsibility.
Brother...
please... do something.
Just keep going.
The next city's not
too much farther.
We have to go now.
Do the best you can.
I've got to go track down Scar
wherever he is so I can turn him in.
You're going to hand
him over to the Military?
It's the only way the
people of Lior can be
cleared of any blame.
I have no choice.
Please don't do it.
It's not right.
But you understand
why I have to.
Equivalency, right?
I don't know.
Maybe there's
something else I can do.
I'm not sure what... but maybe I can figure out a
way to use what happened with the Führer's secretary.
to possibly persuade the
Colonel to... I don't know.
Maybe sit down and
negotiate or something.
But please, don't count
on me to protect you.
Keep going.
Before their troops
figure out you're here.
The farther you get
from them now, the better.
Of course.
We know the stakes and have
no intention of being caught.
We'll disperse a handful of us in each
town we pass, blending in with the population.
They're all counting
on you now, Lyra.
And you.
Okay, Ed.
I'll see you.
Uh-huh.
Well no.
This time it's goodbye.
Sir, there's no sign of
anyone in there at all.
They must be planning
a surprise attack.
What's that?
Someone's up there!
Colonel!
What was that?
What?
Did he fall?
I don't know.
What was that?
Well, they've killed
a State Alchemist.
I should have known
that killer was behind this.
But if he thinks he can intimidate
us by killing a State Alchemist...
...he's about to find out
how sorely mistaken he is.
The tank division will patrol the perimeter while the
infantry charges into the heart of the city to capture Scar.
They had orders not
to move into the city.
Then this must truly
be the will of Ishbala.
I found him!
You fool.
You know it takes more
than bullets to get rid of me.
I couldn't control myself.
My damn body
has a will of its own.
You... you loved me, didn't you?
No, not you, but her.
I hated my brother so much.
He turned his back on the teachings of Ishbala to
immerse himself in the sacrilege of Alchemy instead.
And even though I knew he'd
given me his arm to save my life...
...still there was no room in my
hate-filled heart for forgiveness.
But the Elric brothers...
...they live only
for each other.
That's true.
Seeing their love
for each other...
...it made me long to
say those words myself.
Brother, I love you.
So that's why you did the same
thing for this younger brother...
...as your older
brother did for you.
Come on, let's go.
This life of wickedness.
...has one closing act.
Tell me.
What's your real name?
Long ago, this body did have
a holy name given by God.
But that person died years ago from
a life of sin, malice, and retribution.
There he is!
He's getting away!
After him!
Then goobye, Scar.
Hold on!
Wait!
Well, I guess you survived.
The people of
Lior have given up!
The only one left now is Scar.
Given up, you say?
I have trouble buying that.
Not after they've just killed
the Crimson Alchemist.
But you had orders
not to invade Lior!
I'm afraid the battle's
already begun.
You can pretend it's beyond your control...
...but because of your senseless warmongering...
...these soldiers are being led to slaughter
and they don't... The target's been located, sir!
We're engaged in combat now!
Good.
This is a mistake!
Wait, don't go!
You'll all die, dammit!
Brother...
The man who inflicts
suffering, can't rest.
His guilty mind won't allow it.
But today, I can finally close
my eyes to the living nightmare...
...and lay down, knowing
that I won't wake again.
Brother.
What the hell is that?
Noooo!!
Colonel Archer!
You idiot!
My god, is everyone all right?
Somehow.
Has Colonel Archer's
battalion moved yet?
Well, they did.
But really, it's the
strangest thing.
All of a sudden, Lior
started glowing bright red.
Yeah, and they've been
out of contact ever since.
I thought I was dead.
What just happened out here?
Pull yourself together.
Gather up all the survivors.
Hello?
Al..
Brother?
No, brother!
You have to get away from me!
I'm gonna explode any minute!
Okay.
I don't get it.
What are you doing out here?
huh. Am I... I'm back to normal?
My body's normal again!
I mean, not normal
normal, but normal!
All right.
I don't know what you're
talking about, but... Oh, right.
Well, first Kimbley
turned me into a bomb.
Then Scar killed him and Lust said if my armor
was turned into something else, I could be saved.
So Scar put his hand on me
and it was like his arm was me.
And... uh... Listen,
open up your chest plate.
Just do it, Al.
Brother....
What is it?
Well, Al...
A minute ago, The
transmutation circle in Lior was activated.
Scar... he created a Philosopher's Stone,
but he didn't do it inside his own body.
Yes, that's right, boy.
You've finished it.
Now the very thing you've been
searching for is attached to your soul.
You mean I am the
Philosopher's Stone?
But that doesn't make any sense.
Why would Scar do that?
You should go.
It won't be long before
everyone's after you.
My colleagues and the state.
And what about you?
I thought you were
after the stone, too.
Oh.
Brother... I'm...
That's right.
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 43,
The Stray Dog.
I'm sorry, Colonel,
but this was our cause.
And now we have to go back.