You're not going to
believe who's here!
Ed, do you know this guy?
Yeah, and that means...
And just where do you
think you're going, Ed?
You've always
been so predictable.
Hello, teacher.
What are you doing here?
That's your teacher?
But that means she's...
An Alchemist.
Taught us everything we know.
Where is Alphonse?
Ma'am!
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Well, I want to thank you so
much for escorting us here.
Do you know where
I can find Alphonse?
Um, well...
I'm Alphonse.
That's right.
Of course you are.
Now, as I was saying...
So you're hiding
in disguises now?
Don't worry.
I've had plenty of stories reach me about
my idiot apprentices breaking away from
everything I taught them to
become the scum of the military.
Isn't that right?
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
The official transfer
just came through.
Looks like you'll be working
in Central starting next week.
That's right.
Things won't be the
same without you.
You've been quite
colorful, to say the least.
Oh, I don't know.
I'm nothing compared to when
you were younger, General.
And Check.
Not too bad, huh?
I haven't had to do much
with you covering everything.
Now I might have to
start working again.
You have my deepest sympathy.
Checkmate.
You finally beat me.
Consider your win a
farewell gift, Colonel.
With honor, sir.
General.
Hm?
I have a request.
There are a few subordinates I'd
like to transfer with me to Central.
Sure, that's fine.
And take this, too.
Thank you, General.
You sure you're
gonna be all right, guys?
Yeah.
We just didn't expect
her to come looking for us.
Damn it.
She took my watch.
And I can't exactly say
I'm comfortable like this.
It looks like we're headed
directly for Dublith, too.
I'm kind of surprised.
For some reason, I always figured your alchemy
teacher would be some old crone, but she's a beautiful lady.
How are you surprised?
You met her years ago, Winry.
We first became her students in
Risembool, back when we were boys.
I don't remember that.
Sure you do.
It was that day it
wouldn't stop raining.
ECW 26%, ICW 34%, lipids 19%,
and protein... uh... This is dumb.
Maybe we'll learn faster if we
start with human composition.
Why are you guys
studying so hard all the time?
What are you up to?
Can't tell.
It's none of your
business, Winry.
No fair!
You guys are always
hiding stuff from me!
See ya!
Hey!
We're having stew tonight!
Don't be late!
Okay!
Great, Winry!
See you then!
Whoever invented
stew was a genius.
I mean, it's got milk in
it, but it still tastes good.
What are you talking about?
You know I hate milk, and normally you wouldn't
put it in vegetable soup, but with stew it works great.
It's like being a
good scientist.
You have to think
outside the box sometimes.
You know, we do
have limits, brother.
There's no way we can learn
this whole thing on our own.
I know.
The missing step
in human alchemy.
What do you think it is?
I have no idea.
My question is why it's
forbidden in the first place.
I guess because it's so dangerous,
and no one's ever been able to do it right.
Remember that country
they say died in a single night?
You mean the story of the
Philosopher's Stone in the Eastern Desert?
Yeah.
Someone tried to make a complete human,
and the whole population got dragged into it.
That's just a fairy tale, Al.
Huh?
These are his formulas.
If we could learn how
to make sense of them...
But even if we could understand, transmutations
that deal with humans are still forbidden.
We've already decided, Al.
We're bringing Mom back.
No matter what.
I just hope they can keep
the river barricades intact.
Boys, stop!
We're gonna go help!
Come on.
Give me a hand.
I need more bags.
It's too much.
Over there!
Over here!
This is bad.
Hey, bring some more
sandbags over here!
Move it!
Come on.
Here goes.
We did it!
The circle washed away!
So now what?
Who's that?
Stand back.
This could get a bit messy.
Look, lady.
We can handle this.
It's dangerous.
Leave!
Or stay.
No way.
She didn't use a
transmutation circle.
And she moved all
that earth all at once!
There.
That should hold for a while.
I can't believe it.
Who in the world are you?
Oh, just a couple passing by.
Where's your hospital?
Somebody get a doctor!
It's all right, lady.
Just hold on.
We can't thank you enough
for what you did back there.
The whole town of
Risembool is in your debt.
Coming through.
Clear a path, guys.
Excuse us.
Hey there, old lady.
Some friendly advice.
Don't call me old.
We're sorry, ma'am.
We want to be your apprentices.
If you'll take us.
Apprentices?
We can already do a little
alchemy, but we need to know more.
We want to be the best there is.
With your help.
No.
But why not?
I'm not looking to
take on any students.
And besides, I've
got a store to run.
I need to get back to Dublith.
Please take us with you!
Make us apprentices!
Oh, shut up already!
What are you trying to accomplish
by learning alchemy anyway?
Just tell me that!
Well, um...
We want to help others out.
Do you have your
parents' permission?
Well, we...
I'm afraid they have no parents.
I've been looking after them
since their mother passed on.
It always happens.
I'm just too nice.
I'll give them one month.
Do you mind if I take
them with me for that long?
I'll test them to see if they're even
worth teaching alchemy to in the first place.
See if they have
the right talents.
And what happens if
you find out they don't?
Then I'll send them
back right away.
But what if we pass?
What'll happen then?
Then we'll begin
your alchemy training.
You guys realize we're not
coming back in a month, don't you?
I knew you'd say that.
Training!
I bet you there's a
gigantic laboratory.
You think we'll get
to read a lot of books?
Of course.
How else are we
going to learn anything?
Oh, yeah.
Teacher, you did your alchemy at the river
without a transmutation circle, didn't you?
How did you pull that off?
Are you a State Alchemist?
State Alchemists are thugs who take an innocent
life without blinking if someone gave the order.
Oh, yeah.
So you stayed with her.
There.
Got it.
Much better.
Let's move out, Al.
Brother!
All that work and you still haven't
learned a thing, have you, boys?
Check.
Hey, wait a minute.
That's the rule.
- Are you sure?
So what's the story
with that game?
It's a form of chess they got
from the eastern island countries.
Hello?
Yeah, he's here.
Hey, that was a real fun time we
had the other night, don't you think?
I was hoping this weekend
we could have an encore.
Please, let me get that for you.
Havoc here.
Let's make this quick.
I'm working on some
important business.
That's it.
It's all fixed.
Thank you, sir.
Huh?
Hello?
Please, sir.
Add me to the list.
I'll do a good job.
When you were with Investigations,
you worked under Hughes, right?
Come in.
Master Sergeant Kain Fuery, Second
Lieutenant Heymans Breda, Second Lieutenant
Jean Havoc, First Lieutenant Riza
Hawkeye, and Warrant Officer Vato Falman.
You five will be transferring
to Central with me.
If you have objections,
get over them.
That is all.
So much for our escape plan.
I know.
I've got chills just thinking about
what she's gonna do to us now.
Yeah.
Teacher!
Hey there, Menny.
So how's Chiko doing?
She's gonna have babies soon.
Goodness, your house
is gonna be crowded.
Izumi!
Welcome back!
Hey there, Mason.
That you, Edward?
Haven't seen you in a while.
So you've finally grown
a little bit, haven't you?
He loves to piss me off.
So, uh, who's your
big armored sidekick?
It's me, Mason.
His little brother, Alphonse.
That's one heck
of a growth spurt.
Are you going to eat, Ed?
Uh, ehh, No, thanks.
Eat it now, Ed.
Yes, ma'am.
Same goes for you, Al.
It's really tasty.
No, that's okay.
I'm full.
Wow, it sounds like you two have
been on one brutal journey since you left.
You shouldn't be getting
into so much trouble.
Well, it hasn't been all bad.
We've helped out several
people along the way.
Seriously.
We even helped deliver a
lady's baby a few years ago.
Please, you call that helping?
We just ran around screaming our
heads off, thinking she was gonna die.
I guess so.
But the point is,
we did our best.
It was like that old proverb.
When a mother gives
birth, she risks her life.
And when the baby is born,
everyone around her is blessed.
Yes, that's true.
I'm sure it was the same way
when your mother gave birth to you.
You boys should be
thankful for the lives you have.
And what about you, Izumi?
Do you have a child of your own?
I'm sorry.
I was just, uh...
You've improved your
alchemy, right, Ed?
Can you show me?
Sure.
If you want.
Let's go.
Right.
I'll go, too.
Izumi.
I'm okay.
They've witnessed another
life come into this world.
That's an invaluable
experience for anyone to have.
All right.
I'll start.
Hey!
You have gotten better.
Okay, my turn.
Welcome back, teacher.
Yeah, welcome home.
My train broke while
we were playing.
Now it doesn't roll right.
So, can you fix it?
One of the axles is broken.
Okay, give me that.
Come on!
Can't you just fix
it using alchemy?
No.
You shouldn't rely on
alchemy all the time.
If you can fix it with your
own hands, then you should.
There you go.
All fixed.
Yeah, but now it
looks really ugly.
There are far uglier sights.
In the future, if you want all your things to be so beautiful,
then I suggest you don't break them in the first place.
Bye, teacher.
Thanks a lot.
I'll be back if it breaks again.
Let's try to keep it
to once a day, please.
Teacher!
What is it, Menny?
What's wrong?
It's Chiko, my cat.
The cat must be up there!
I'm on it.
Nice cat!
Chiko?
Uh, teacher?
Is Chiko broken somewhere?
Hmm...
No, Menny.
Chiko's dead.
But you can make her
better, can't you, teacher?
You can fix anything.
You can fix Chiko, too.
No, I can't.
Lives and things are
different, and I'm not a god.
Chiko's life has ended, and
she isn't ever coming back.
But...
She was... She was just here!
I can't bring Chiko back for you, Menny,
but I can help you make a grave for her, okay?
How does that sound?
Everything that
lives has to die.
That's the nature of the world.
And when the body returns to the
soil, flowers will be nourished and bloom.
A soul impacts other souls
and lives on in other hearts.
Everything in this
world flows, circulates.
That goes for
human lives, as well.
Even for someone like me, who's come
to know so much on the subject, it's still
difficult to make a child understand
the actual nature of death.
Teacher...
Over all these years, have you ever wished
you could bring someone dead back to life?
That's the second time
you've asked me that, Ed.
I just asked out of curiosity.
What's this got to do
with my question, anyway?
The basis strength of a transmutation
circle is the nature of the shape itself.
The circle represents
the circulation of power.
By drawing it, that
power can be evoked.
By understanding this circulation of power and the
laws that govern it, you can harness it for yourself.
And one who works within this system of flow
to create new things, that is the true Alchemist.
The world, all of us, follow
the motion of a great current.
Every living being's
death is part of that flow.
And reviving them
would disrupt it.
We mustn't do that.
Al, that armor
is empty, isn't it?
Ed, your arm and leg
are automail, right?
How'd you find out?
Your weight when I threw you.
The sound of your steps.
You thought I wouldn't notice?
You fools.
Teacher... On the roof.
You didn't use a
transmutation circle, did you?
So come on, tell me, Ed.
Did you actually see it?
Yes.
How did it happen?
Tell me everything.
Teacher...
I...
We...
No...
We transmuted...
transmuted our mother!
Ah!
[Ass Kicking Continues]
Full Metal Alchemist.
Episode 28.
All is one, one is all.
It's the core of
alchemic theory.
As imperfect as we are,
the entire world lies within us.