Where am I, what city is this?
Hello?
Who are you?
Oh hell, I think I'm in someone else's
body.
This is incredible.
Why have I never heard of these flying
machines?
It seems in this world scientific
discovery developed along a different track.
Physics and advanced machinery instead of
alchemy.
Came as quite a shock to me too when I
arrived.
In this world?
I thought you realized.
You see...
This is the other side of the gate.
The Philosopher's Stone.
Those who possess it, no longer bound by
the laws of equivalent exchange and
alchemy, may gain without sacrifice,
create without equal exchange.
We searched for it.
And we found it.
It sounds like there's some kind of ruckus
going on at Central.
It's too chaotic to know what though.
You might say that the one advantage to
being completely surrounded with little
hope for escape is that we don't have to
deal with the goings on at Central.
I guess it doesn't really matter what's happening
as long as Colonel Mustang is able to succeed.
Yeah, but I think the important question
is... What exactly is he succeeding at?
Because we sure as hell haven't been told.
For all we know, it's a revolution.
Lieutenant Colonel!
They've sent in the tanks!
Why don't you let me handle this?
I haven't perfected my Colonel Mustang
impersonation.
Hmm?
Is something wrong?
Not really.
No matter what it is, you know you can
talk to me, Selim.
I'm actually quite good at keeping
secrets.
So, if you have something to say,
I won't tell, not even to Mom.
I'm sorry, Father.
Hm?
Well, I... I saw your secret treasure.
I didn't mean to.
Honest.
I'm sure you didn't.
It's just I hadn't planned on showing you
until you were older.
So you aren't angry?
I could never be angry with my dear Selim.
You do understand that by giving you this
key, I'm trusting you with my life,
so I expect you to protect it at all
costs.
Yes, Your Excellency the Führer.
What's wrong.
There's a strange woman here.
She demands to see you immediately.
First Lieutenant Hawkeye.
What a surprise.
Forgive my intrusion, Your Excellency,
but I must speak with you.
Hurry up!
She's headed towards the front!
Stop her!
Okay, let's move.
Where are we supposed to go?
We've set up a rally point for all the
dissenting soldiers to regroup.
If we go down, we'll do it together.
What news?
We're in trouble!
There's been a breach of security at the
Führer's mansion!
Put your mind at rest, Führer King.
I'm on my way.
This world is tragically violent.
Throughout the course of this war, millions of people
have been killed with the use of highly toxic gases.
But the single most terrifying instrument
of death is yet to come.
You saw it in the gate, didn't you?
The lives of those that have died and will
die in this world become the energy for.
the alchemy used in ours.
The energy?
That doesn't make any sense.
What about the la..
Law of equivalent exchange.
There's something you don't understand.
It takes more than equal mass to restore a
broken radio.
The energy used to put it back together
must come from somewhere, too.
And energy cannot be created or destroyed,
only redirected.
So that's the secret?
The lives of the people who die here, cross the
gate and become energy we need for transmutations?
Is that what you're telling me?
Inside all of us, there lies a smaller
version of the gate you pass through.
Alchemists have the ability to open their gates,
crossing worlds and feeding off the tragedies of this one.
It happens every time you draw
a circle or clap hands.
You sound just like that head case Dante!
All the same crap about there being no
equivalent exchange.
I wasn't aware that you knew about her.
I know everything.
I know the two of you were lovers because
I read the letter.
I know you've been keeping yourselves
alive, jumping from one body to another.
But what I don't understand is if you and
that evil bitch were so perfect together,
why did you feel the need to marry my
mother?
Did you get some sick satisfaction out of
pretending to be a normal human?
I loved your mother.
With all of my being, I had never loved
until her.
You have to believe that.
Then why?
Why did you leave us?
I just couldn't let you see me like this.
The thought of it was too much for me to
bear.
Come on, gluttony.
You're just one meal away from creating a
perfect stone.
So, stuff your face, big guy.
Lust!
Where did my lust go?
Where?
Look, half-wit!
We're all waiting on you!
Now listen to me!
If you don't get your fat ass over there right
now, I'll force him down your throat myself!
We've come too far for you to screw it up
now!
But where is she?
Where is she?
Where's Lust?
You poor thing.
It seems there's no other way.
Gluttony?
Keep your distance.
The only thing left inside of him now is
his urge to feed.
Without his mind, there will be no more
human attachments to distract him.
Now, he is pure.
I knew Dante couldn't create the stone,
at least not without my help.
I thought if I just stayed in hiding,
she'd finally fade away.
But I had to do something once she'd set
her eyes on you.
So in return, she sent you beyond the
gate?
Not beyond the gate.
Just inside it.
And she separated my mind, body, and soul while I
was inside, leaving me to wander in that limbo forever.
But despite her efforts, I put myself back
together and wound up here.
Is that what happened to me?
Not quite.
The success of alchemy seems to be the
diverging point for these worlds.
We share the same history before that,
and much is still the same.
As you see, there's a boy here that's
physically identical to you.
There's probably a boy like Al as well.
That makes sense.
But that doesn't explain how I got this
body.
It's highly probable that your true body
is still somewhere inside the gate.
But your mind and soul have crossed over into this world,
and they were attracted like magnets to this Edward's body.
Lieutenant Colonel Churchill needs to see
you immediately.
Hey, wait!
Wait!
You must open the gate that's inside you.
Only then can you find your way back to
your true home, Edward.
But aren't you coming too?
I'm afraid that's not possible.
Since my body has already crossed the
gate, I'm completely a part of this world now.
And because alchemy seems to be impossible
here, I'm stranded.
But luckily, it isn't too late for you.
There must be something we can do.
I know it's hard for you to understand,
but I believe it's best I'm staying here.
That way, I can live the remainder of my
life in the body your mother loved.
You should know I was relieved to find out
the law of equivalence wasn't true.
That people mustn't always be required to pay a
price in order to gain something of value in return.
Because even if I lived for a thousand lifetimes, I
could never do enough to deserve the gift of my children.
You and Al.
I can't agree with you.
I know if I try my hardest, I'll be
rewarded.
And I believe that applies to all of us.
It doesn't matter who you are.
If you work hard, it pays off.
I know equivalent exchange is true.
But this world...
If it's childish to believe in this,
so be it.
I'd rather be considered a child than
follow a doctrine of cynicism and chaos.
Apathy.
I thought I didn't care, Dad.
That I didn't need to believe in things.
But I was wrong.
It looks like a zeppelin's been hit.
What about the location of Colonel Mustang?
As far as we know, he's been heading up a
campaign in the war against the North.
That's been a subterfuge.
He's been here the entire time,
plotting a way to take you down.
It's probably a rat.
There's no reason to be alarmed.
I'll have a look just to be safe.
You two stay here with my family.
But, sir... In the unlikely event
that something should happen,
I want you to take them to
Central Headquarters immediately.
Why am I not surprised you decided to face
me alone?
Your behavior leads me to assume this
isn't the first time you've betrayed my trust.
You've got a hell of a lot of nerve
lecturing me about betrayal.
Are you referring to the fact that I am...
...a Homunculus?
Whether or not you can call yourself a human
being is a non-issue as far as I'm concerned, Bradley.
Then what's the problem?
Ever since I've become Führer,
I've done nothing but improve this country
by winning wars, purifying our population,
and exponentially expanding our territory.
You couldn't care less for this state.
All you wanted was the Philosopher's
Stone.
You started those conflicts because you knew people
pushed to despair by war tend to seek refuge in the Stone.
People are foolish.
Foolish enough to let you profit off their
pain and suffering!
You've got me all wrong.
To stop the human race from leading itself
to ruin, I intervene and take the Stone,
thereby preventing its use.
I think of myself as one of God's guardian
angels.
There's no such thing as God.
We can't know that for sure.
However, devils do exist.
They're the Alchemists who dare to get in
my way.
How unfortunate.
A quick slash of my sword changes the air
currents, disrupting your precious alchemic reactions.
How can you expect to manipulate the air's
composition if it's constantly in flux?
My ultimate eye sees your alchemy at work.
Even if you did pull off a flame,
it wouldn't have any accuracy.
Soon, Rose, you will surrender yourself to
me.
Huh, Envy!
Do not allow him to use his alchemy!
Stop squirming!
Bring her back!
Bring my mommy back to life!
Please!
What a terrible child.
Bursting in like the entire universe
revolves around him.
Not even caring that one false move
could activate the Philosopher's
Stone before it's reached its full potential.
He should be grateful I've allowed him to
live as long as I have.
Master...
The gate...
It's still here!
Edward.
Brother?
Alphonse...
My automail...
I'm really here.
But does that mean the other Ed had to
die?
his life... traded from mine?
Quite an amazing feat, Edward.
Dr. Marcoh?
I never did know where you went.
Sure you did, Ed.
After all, you were the one who found the old Doc and
just waved goodbye as he went into the Führer's custody.
Now that was a great idea.
The poor man ended up in that thing's
stomach.
Wouldn't have died if you hadn't tracked
him down.
Of course, you were bad luck for a lot of
us, weren't you?
I'd still be with my wife, an adorable
little girl, if I hadn't met you.
It must be tough fighting against a friend
that you've already killed once.
Is that all you got?
Release me.
Impersonations with guilt trips attached?
Damn you.
You'll have to do better than that.
You're still a Homunculus under that face.
Have you forgotten what I did to your
friend, Sloth?
I killed her while she was wearing the
face of my own mother.
Really?
That must have been very hard for you.
So, not as tough as you think.
I'd reconsider the use of alchemy if I
were you.
You think I'm going to listen to you?
Go ahead and use it if you want.
It's not like I care what happens to your
brother.
The Philosopher's Stone
has already been activated.
If transmutations occur near him,
who knows what could happen?
Let's find out.
You're going to pay for this!
Keep trying, Ed.
I'm much stronger than you.
Don't hurt me, Edward.
Don't mess with me!
Edward, please stop it!
Calm down.
Give up, kid.
You don't have what it takes to kill me.
I don't think you could have picked an
easier target!
Show me what you really look like!
Instead of being a coward whose only real
power is to hide behind other people's faces!
Do you really want to see?
Stop jerking me around!
You asked for it!
What's wrong?
I thought you wanted to see.
Your... His son!
Envy was the very first Homunculi,
created by Hohenheim almost 400 years ago.
The result of the failed human transmutation of
our son, who died prematurely of Mercury poisoning.
I suppose you could say that Envy was once
your brother.
But then he abandoned me.
Started fresh with his perfect wife and
kids.
Needless to say, I never did like being
replaced.
Brother?
Edward.
Ed.
EDWARD!!!!!