You really don't
know who this is?
Trust me, if we were going to send
someone here with you, it wouldn't be a kid.
I would have just come to look
after you myself, like last time.
Look after us?
You tried to kill us!
I was just doing my job.
Izumi told me to
toughen you up a little bit.
Nearly dying of starvation and getting her
asses beat was supposed to toughen us up?
How would you do that to kids?
What kind of monster are you?
Stop bitching about the past and think
about someone other than yourselves!
Yes, ma'am!
Teacher?
He's just a kid.
He probably climbed in someone's
boat and drifted here on accident.
I'm sure his parents
are looking for him.
I'll find out.
Teacher!
Brother!
That light!
That kid's an alchemist!
Ed, wait!
Listen, you!
You turned your
own fist into stone?
How the hell...
Please stop!
What just happened?
His clothes!
What are you doing?
He's just a kid.
He's an alchemist!
What if somebody sent
him here to spy on us?
Spy on you?
Don't you think you're
being a little bit paranoid, Ed?
I'm just being careful.
Where are your
parents, little one?
How did you get out here?
Don't know.
What's your name?
I don't know.
Can't remember.
I don't know!
Hey, now.
No more crying.
I've got you, little one.
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
You've had enough.
You're be get sick.
I'm glad you two are back.
I was getting worried about you.
Hey we don't die that easy.
How's Izumi?
Has the teacher
forgiven her students?
We went against her teachings, Winry.
She taught us, that we were just a small part of the world.
There's a cycle to the whole thing.
A flow.
But we were conceded, we thought we
could bend the world anyway we wanted.
We were young, but that's no excuse.
We let her down.
Yeah.
I don't think she'll ever
completely forgive us.
Come on.
Your-You're too strong!
You got me!
Let me go!
Come on, you little monsters!
Have mercy!
That's not fair!
Everybody makes mistakes!
Doesn't she know that?
I'm going to tell her
what I think about...
No, you can't do that!
Just wait a minute!
Al was kidding!
I'm sure she'll forgive us!
Yeah, she just worries about us.
That's all.
We know she loves us, Winry.
So...
what are you going to do about the boy?
Uh..
I'm not sure.
Why does he bother you?
I don't know.
I guess I just think Teacher
trusts him too much, too easily.
In any case, he'll be staying with her
for a while until the police find his parents.
I think he's just
a lost little boy.
I hope you're right, Winry.
This meat is too tough!
Maybe we shouldn't
be doing this.
She locked it with alchemy.
If we open it, she'll know!
That is true.
You just put this back
exactly the way it was!
Why me!?
You wanna play?
Everyone's dead, so I got bored.
Did you come to play with me?
They're not dead.
They're just asleep.
I know what we should play!
This game!
See, I've won!
I watched you play
this game before!
So it was you.
You were watching
us on the island.
But why?
Where'd you come from, kid?
Stop.
You're hurting it.
Let go!
Play with me!
An animal isn't a toy
for you to play with, kid.
I'm playing!
Hey, keep it down!
You're gonna wake
them all up, you idiot!
I'm playing!
Okay?
Fine!
Look!
You can do that, too.
Can't you?
Don't lie to me.
Earlier on the island, you transmuted
a rock onto your hand.
And your clothes were
transmuted, too, weren't they?
Calm down, brother.
You're scaring him.
Al, you saw what
he did, didn't you?
Alchemy without a circle.
The only people who can
do that are me and Teacher.
And then she acted like she
didn't even notice he did it.
I call that strange.
What's the matter?
Just use alchemy.
Untie it!
Brother, I really don't think this boy
has anything to do with the others.
Al, I've seen his face
somewhere before.
I know I have.
I just need to figure out where.
Ed what did you do?
I didn't do anything.
I couldn't transmute a body and
a bed together even if I wanted to.
How am I supposed to
sleep with all this noise?
Hey.
Hold on, Teacher.
We didn't do anything.
It's true.
I know Ed lies sometimes,
but he's not lying about this.
I promise.
Thanks, Al.
You're a big help.
I know that.
No alchemist I trained would
transmute something so unrefined.
Not even mixing animals
into chimeras is this crass.
Let me go!
Let me down!
Stop crying!
It's all right.
Now can you remember
what your original form was?
That's all you have to do.
Just remember what you were.
It's okay.
Just take your time.
Now explain yourselves!
What were you trying to accomplish
by frightening this poor child?
Please forgive us, Teacher.
I'm sorry to say, Teacher, but
I don't think that boy is human.
I think he's one of those
creatures who've been hunting us.
Just who or what is hunting you?
Who knows?
They say they're homunculi.
Thank you for always
coming by like this.
But are you sure it's okay
considering your new job?
Yeah, don't worry
about it, really.
I work at home, so I
make my own hours.
Oh, Sheska, I don't know if you're still investigating
the incident with Maes, but please be careful.
Oh, don't worry about me.
I'm not a very brave person.
I wouldn't get involved in something
I thought was terribly dangerous.
Bye-bye!
Good night, Sheska.
See you tomorrow!
Huh?
Ah!
Just a minute colonel.
Pfftbffft.
Ouch.
That hurt.
What are you doing
skulking around here?
Is it wrong of me to drive by and
check on the wife of an old friend?
Can't even show your
face in there, huh?
Not when you refuse to
investigate the death of your own pal!
Or maybe you're just too busy
thinking about your promotion.
Come on.
Lay off, will ya?
Here, these are the copies of all the documents
Brigadier General Hughes was reviewing before he died.
The reason for his death must be in there
somewhere, and you should be looking for it, too.
And congratulations on your
new office at Central Headquarters!
What does all this mean?
Oh, I can't make sense out
of any of these stupid records!
Okay, a list of all the external
calls connected to the Central
Command Center on the day
Brigadier General Hughes died.
But there's no relation
as far as I can see.
So, the reception clerk?
The Ministry of Justice?
The desk of the
Fuhrer's secretary?
I don't get it!
I can't keep losing
track of all of you.
I have a few things I
need to accomplish myself.
Their teacher lives in
a town called Dublith.
Why don't you try there?
I'll leave greed to
lust and gluttony, then.
What should I do with the Elric
boys if I find them in Dublith?
Nothing.
They still haven't
given up on the stone.
Arrange for them to have
another opportunity to create it.
You may be the youngest among us,
but you give orders like you're all grown up.
Of course I would like those boys
to create a Philosopher's Stone.
But we can't have them sticking
their noses into that Ishbal business.
I assume you understand.
So why don't these homunculi
create their own Philosopher's Stone?
They just said that they
couldn't create it themselves.
That they can't perform alchemy.
That would mean this child's
different from all of them.
That's true.
But I've never seen Alchemists
transmute their own body.
Involuntary systems get in the way,
and no human should be able to do it.
You know that.
And think about it, teacher.
He transmutes without a
circle, just like you and Brother.
So that must
mean... Al, leave it.
You lost your memory
when it happened, right, Al?
What do you mean?
You remember it,
though, don't you, Edward?
Yes.
The gateway.
I remember.
How could I not?
The truth.
That's what was in there.
The truth?
Brother!
Brother, please!
No Al!
Brother!
I couldn't understand
what was going on.
It was as if a vast amount of information
was being implanted directly into my mind.
And suddenly I knew things about
alchemy that I'd never learned.
Everything.
And I knew that I was just one step away
from achieving a complete human transmutation.
Mom!
Let me go, please!
No!
Hold on!
One more time!
Show it to me one more time!
The truth was inside there!
Everything was in there!
Equivalent exchange?
What do you want?
A payment?
Damn it.
This wasn't supposed to...
Mom?
No...
This isn't what I wanted.
Al...
It's all my fault.
I'm sorry.
I understood when I
was inside that gateway.
If I acted now,
there was still time.
Give him back.
He's my brother.
My leg.
My arms.
My heart.
I'll give them to you,
whatever you want.
Just give him back.
He's my brother!!!
Al.
[Screaming Al]
[Screaming Al, But Longer]
By the time I came to, I
was already in the shell.
And the thing that was
supposed to be Mom was dead.
I saw the truth while
inside that gateway.
That's why I'm able to transmute without a circle
and how I bonded Al's soul to the suit of armor.
I learned it all in there.
You really think it's the truth
that's beyond that gateway?
Of course.
What else could it be?
I don't know.
A shortcut?
The secret to a magic trick?
Teacher, I just
remembered something.
That boy.
I saw him while I
was inside the gate.
That proves that he isn't human.
He's something else.
There's one way to make sure.
We'll worry about it then.
Teacher!
Don't go near that
child till I get back.
Understood?
Izumi.
It's all right.
I just need to make sure.
I'm sorry.
I'm going alone.
Those boys still
don't know, do they?
You didn't tell them how
a homunculus is born.
Gentlemen, how nice
of you to join us?
I'm Alex Lewis Armstrong.
Welcome you with the
utmost respect and admiration.
You know, you've got a real
sick sense of humor, Breda.
You scared us to death.
Still, you never know
when he's gonna strike.
You might as well be prepared.
Next time, it'll be him.
The major isn't in
town at the moment.
Is that right?
Where is he?
He's off conducting an investigation with
the officer assigned to the court martial office.
The man who's taken over
for Brigadier General Hughes.
Yeah, I've been wondering.
Who is that guy?
I believe his name is Archer.
Lieutenant Colonel Frank Archer.
So, you've heard of him?
He's a man dedicated
to his military duties.
Wait, I don't get it.
That's a good thing, isn't it?
By military duties.
I mean to say that
the man enjoys war.
Lieutenant Colonel, I know
I've already told you this, but...
Yes, you don't know where the
Elric brothers have run off to.
What are you, a broken
record, Armstrong?
But there's no evidence
they even went south.
I believe there's enough evidence
for us to investigate further.
Why?
Do you have someone
watching them?
Those children are
not traitors, you know.
Perhaps.
But I don't have any intention of just letting them roam
around freely the way Mustang has done up until now.
For the sake of the upcoming
battle, you understand.
Sorry about this, but Izumi told me not
to let you guys out or she'd skin me alive.
Did you ask her
where she was going?
No.
She asked me to have the boat ready,
so maybe she went to the island again.
The island?
That's weird.
What are you doing, Al?
Shh.
Just a second.
All right, now let's get
your hair out of there.
Winry, sorry, but since we can't
come out of our room... Hi, Al.
Hey, what did you guys
do to this boy anyway?
He's completely terrified.
Winry, this may sound strange,
but there's something I need to ask.
It's about the boy's body.
Will you check something for me?
Al, what are you talking about?
You mean the scars?
Yeah, I was surprised too.
What do you suppose
happened to him?
They go all the way around the
base of his right arm and left leg.
Al, wait a minute.
You don't think...
Think about it, brother.
You said you saw his face
on the other side of the gate.
What's wrong?
Guys, if Izumi finds out
about this, she'll kill you.
This won't take long.
Come on, you guys.
Izumi told you not
to go near this boy.
I can't let you do this.
Like he said, this
won't take long.
It's not true.
Tell me it isn't true.
It was... it was an
equivalent exchange.
Mom's body, in
exchange for my leg.
Al's soul, my brother's
soul, in exchange for my arm.
I thought it was an
equivalent exchange!
Tell me, do you
know what this
gash is from?
It's the scar
from the fox bight.
This is my arm!
Ed, no!
Edward!
What if it's true?
What if the boy's arm
and leg really are his?
Full Metal Alchemist
Episode 30, Assault on South Headquarters.
Teacher, I am a dog of the
military, and I have to do my job.