There aren't any more books
here about the Philosopher's Stone.
Just shoot me in
the head, will ya?
I can't believe that
Cornello’s Stone was a fake.
Now we're out of leads again.
Mustang's gonna
scream my ears off.
Brother, look!
Introduction to Alchemy.
Takes you back, doesn't it?
Eh, I guess.
See?
This line goes here.
Hey!
I'm bored!
One more second, Winry.
All right, we're done.
What do you think, Winry?
I think that's a lousy present.
Well, that's not the present.
It's just an outline for one.
[Winry screams]
[Barking]
Winry!
That was our very
first use of alchemy.
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed that
to be the world's one, and only, truth.
Take the memories of distant days,
tear them up with your own hands,
and squeeze the life
out of your sorrows for me
Come on, and pierce my
heart as it yearns for your love!
Looking at the sky, thinking
tomorrow must be coming,
it's too much for my
captivated heart to take
As a bird flutters
along beside me,
I wonder where he
managed to find his light
Say, would you carry me
along on your back as well?
And leave me at the
highest place there is,
far away from kindness?
Take the memories of distant days,
tear them up with your own hands,
and squeeze the life
out of your sorrows for me
Come on, and pierce my
heart as it yearns for your love!
Fullmetal Alchemist: Mother
They weren't trying
to scare you, Winry.
They went to a lot of trouble.
That's right.
Edward and Alphonse were just
trying to do something special for you.
I'm sorry about this.
It was a misunderstanding.
But no mistake of talent.
You know, I’ve found
even the most gifted folks
give up before they do
anything of real merit.
But your boys have
one heck of a start.
Look at this work!
I know, it's stunning.
But they shouldn't know
anything about alchemy.
Well, they are
his sons after all.
Okay boys, no secrets.
When did your dad
teach you alchemy?
How can we learn from
somebody who's never here?
We learned it from his book.
You mean you really
understand it on your own?
Yeah, more or less.
So, are you upset with us?
You mean for using alchemy?
No, Ed, I'm proud.
I think I'll brag to
everyone I know.
Now, be sure to put the books
back where you found them.
We will.
And when your dad gets
back, make sure you thank him.
Okay.
And that door is
off limits, okay?
We hear you!
There they are!
Get that one!
No, you can't
pull that one first!
Dad left a long time ago.
When Ed and I were still boys,
Mom stared off into the distance a lot.
But she carried on as
if nothing were wrong.
We started studying alchemy,
like our father before us.
The more we learned,
the more she smiled.
She praised us, and we
competed with each other.
We became absorbed in the science
that made you feel like you were magic.
Mom!
Look, Mom, look!
Whatcha got there?
Brother made it!
Isn't it awesome?
I can still only do this one.
Well, I think they're
both gorgeous.
You two really are his
kids, no doubt about it.
You think Dad
would be proud, too?
Yes.
Once he comes
home, he'll tell you so.
Okay.
I'm going to Winry's!
Brother, wait!
Brother?
Why are you so angry
at Daddy all the time?
Come on, why do you think?
He ditched us.
I can't say I hate him.
I don't remember him enough.
But when Mom thinks
of him, she gets sad.
That's reason
enough not to like him.
I guess.
Come on, let's go
show this to Winry.
What do you mean “dead”?
Don't be stupid, Al.
They're plain dead,
my mom and dad.
But how?
I thought they
were just doctors.
They went to be surgeons
for the war in Ishbal.
There was a surprise attack.
Winry, our dad’s
gone too, you know.
We make it okay.
Shut up, you idiot.
Your dad just ran off.
My parents are both dead!
They can't ever come back!
That's not necessarily true.
I read it in a book.
There's this artificially made
thing called a homunculus.
It's sort of a living doll
without a mind to begin with.
But some scholars believe, with
alchemy, if you're willing to give up enough...
STOP!
There'll be no talking like that in
this house, you understand me?
That's a forbidden science.
Alchemy is not some
magic end-all answer.
That's why we
automail engineers exist!
Backwards old bat!
You know, she's right.
Winry's already lost
more than we ever will.
Poor Winry.
Can you imagine how that'd be?
What's the matter with you two?
Come on, Ed.
Even you.
My little man.
What could be so bad?
Come on, Al!
You couldn’t beat a
snail with a broken leg!
Hello, Mom, sorry we're late!
Mom?
Mom!
We just have to wait.
I can tell you this isn't some
sickness she contracted yesterday.
She must have been dealing with
this for years, not telling anyone.
Honey...
These are all
letters he sent us.
If we mail something to each of
these addresses explaining everything...
Someone is bound to know where
he is and can tell him to come home.
Damn it!
I don't want him here!
But it's the only way.
She has to see him.
Your dad.
He left us some money.
I've never touched it.
I was saving it for you boys.
Use it and take
care of each other.
Don't be silly.
We'll use it with you.
Edward, would you be a sweetheart
and transmute something for your mother?
Yes, I know.
A ring of flowers would be nice.
You see, your father always
used to make them for me.
And that's what we
finally understood.
The reason why mom had
always smiled at our alchemy.
It had reminded her of dad.
Brother, I'm hungry.
And I'm cold too.
How are we going to do this?
How are we going
to live without her?
We're not, Al.
We're going to bring her back.
Look, it's right
here in his notes.
I don't understand it all, but he's written
something about human transmutations.
If we can just decipher it...
But Aunt Pinako says
human alchemy is forbidden.
This book says the same thing.
Forget about that.
If scientists could bring people back to
life, we all know we'd be better off, right?
Alchemists tried for centuries
and couldn't figure it out.
Slapping a forbidden label on it was just a
way for them not to feel bad about their failure.
But--
But maybe we should
ask dad about it first.
Don't start with
that junk again, Al.
Mom's life drained
away waiting for him.
It's all his fault she's dead.
He didn't even
come to her funeral.
No, this is something our
dad couldn't do, but we will.
We have to.
We used some of the money
to find ourselves a teacher.
And we learned
alchemy from page one.
The serious kind.
We were done
making dolls and roses.
Water, 35 liters.
Carbon, 20 kilograms.
Ammonia, 4 liters.
Lime, 1.5 kilograms.
Phosphorus, 800 grams
Salt, 250 grams.
Saltpeter, 100.
Sulfur, 80.
Fluorine, 7.5.
Iron, 5.
Silicone, 3 grams.
And trace amounts
of 15 other elements.
Yeah, that's everything.
The physical ingredients
of a human body.
Now if we can just put together a soul, we
should be able to calm mom back from the other side.
Edward, you sure
we should do this?
Of course.
Don't wimp out on me now.
But--
No one's ever done this right.
I mean, alchemy is
equivalent exchange.
The body content seems simple
enough, but what about the soul?
What could we possibly offer?
Just hold out your finger, okay?
What's a soul, really?
When you take out the myth,
it's just the spark that starts life.
This is our blood.
From her blood.
That's a fair trade.
There's something
foul in the air.
Brother, something's
going wrong here.
[Al, Screaming]
AL!
EDWARD!!
[Crying out]
Brother!
Brother, please!
NO--AL!!
[He screams]
And that's the last
thing I remember.
Him.
Reaching for me.
His leg already broken
down by the forces of alchemy.
Ngh...Ugh...
Huh?
What is this?
[Whimpering]
Uh?
I'm sorry, Al.
Brother!
What happened to you?
And me?
What happened to me?
There wasn't much time.
I used my right arm as
material in a transmutation.
All I could manage was to attach
your spirit to the armor in the corner.
Oh, no.
But... what about mom?
You shouldn't look.
It wasn't human.
Huh?
I don't understand, Ed.
What happened?
Your theorems and equations.
They all seemed right.
The theorems
weren't the problem, Al.
It wasn't the math.
It was us.
Please.
Help him.
He's gonna bleed to death.
Al?
Is that you?
We didn't even know you
were back from training.
How did all this happen, Al?
Well, clearly, it's a
product of mischief.
You were trying to bring
back your mother, weren't you?
Well, that explains
a few things.
A human transmutation.
I've never seen such a
furious reaction before.
Pardon me.
A state alchemist?
What are you doing here?
I have no time
to entertain dogs.
Can't you see
these boys are hurt?
Take it easy, ma'am.
I'm just checking the mail.
One of our letters!
Then you know where my dad is?
I only wish, kid.
We've been looking for
Hohenheim for a long time.
And we're still
only kicking up dirt.
Well, if you didn't have any
information, why did you come?
You sure as heck aren't
going to find their dad here.
Let's call it nostalgia
or misplaced curiosity.
Whatever it was,
I'm happy I came.
If these boys can try
human alchemy and survive,
their dad just dropped
a rung on my priority list.
I want you out of this
house immediately!
I've had enough lives
wrecked by the state!
The name's Lieutenant
Colonel Roy Mustang.
State alchemist.
Pay me a visit at
Central sometime.
Good morning, Winry.
[She squeals]
Al! You're on!
I mean, you're awake!
I'm sorry... I was just...
I-I would've...
But I can't... um...uh…
There's some money in the house.
In a closet.
I'm sure it's safe.
There are more important
things to worry about right now.
That's not what I'm saying.
I want you to
take it as payment.
For automail.
I can't go through my plan
lugging around a couple of stumps.
I'm going to visit that man Mustang
and become a state alchemist.
I was hoping you weren't
conscious to hear that talk.
He's not the only
one I've heard from.
The teacher we had told
us about state alchemists.
They've got access to the Federal Library in
Central with books on alchemy no one else has.
They'll pay you and fund your research and
those pocket watches amplify alchemic reactions.
Please tell me that's
not all your teacher said.
What about state alchemists being the
military's attack dogs called into war to
mow down the lives of people
the state tells you are bad?
Did your teacher mention that?
In the attacks that took the lives of my
sons, there were alchemists involved.
When war comes again,
are you ready to do the same?
I don't want to be chained to
the state any more than you.
But I'll do whatever
it takes to fix things.
Fix you or the world?
Make sure you ask yourself that.
Just bear with us, Ed.
[Ed cries out]
It's the highest quality procedure
we can do.
[He cries out]
Stay out of the room, Al.
I'm impressed, Ed.
Even adults scream in
this part of the operation.
We're attaching each one of
your nerves to the mechanism.
This pain’s nothing...
compared to what he's given up.
It's been enough time.
We should see what we can do.
To train the mind to its
potential, you gotta train the body.
That's what our teacher said.
But I don't know…
How good can you be
as an empty heap of steel?
Better than a couple chunks
of automail, I know that.
Brother, are you serious
about being a state alchemist?
I'm serious about trying.
I'm gonna see this Mustang guy.
And find out if I have a shot.
I don't want you to join.
I've made up my mind.
Then I will, too.
You can't.
Brother, are you going to
try to bring back Mom again?
I mean, we agreed it
was a mistake, right?
All the bad things
that happened...
I'll become a state alchemist.
And I'll find a way to
get you back to normal.
With a real arm and leg again.
Then you can forget about all these
other things you say you have to do.
It's not your
burden to carry, Al.
Well, why shouldn't it be?
I wanted you to stop, but I
went along with it anyway.
I'm the one who had the
feeling, I should have acted on it.
And then you gave up
your arm to save me.
You've got no place feeling
sorry for me, Al, okay?
But, Brother... I'm serious.
I'm the one who has to fix
things and get your body back.
Then?
You won't try with Mom again?
Well, chances are there isn't anything in
this world we could trade for Mom's soul.
And besides all that...
I don't...
I don't want to risk
losing you again, Al.
Good.
I'll have to come
with you, though.
Why's that?
You're no good without me.
You just turn into a jerk.
Thanks for the endorsement.
But seriously,
we're all we've got.
From now on... we can't do
anything that could pull us apart.
Even though we were trying
to restore our own bodies...
it was still human
transmutation we were after.
A forbidden science.
If we failed the next time...
there would probably
be nothing left of us.
We had no idea what
the future would hold.
But we knew there
was no turning back.
So...on the day we left... we
burned down the family home...
and all the familiar
things inside.
Because some memories...
aren't meant to leave traces.
With you always in my sight,
I can manage to draw breath
And for me, that ought to
be enough in itself, and yet...
All little old me ever does is
repeat the same old mistakes
How much strength
do I need to come by
before I can get by
without hurting anything?
I am not going to stray,
I'm going to trust this love,
and with it I will go on living!
I'm going to take these wounds,
the ones that will not close,
and squeeze them tight!
The two of us must
keep on walking,
since we can never return again
Even now, deep within my heart,
I still feel the pain
of this indelible sin
Darling
Full Metal Alchemist
Episode 4: A Forger's Love.
In a forest village
a man confronts
his foolishness... when
a doll comes to life.
But he'll repeat his same mistakes,
if alchemy can bring him love.