You should take this with you.
You know, I was picturing
a more poignant ceremony.
Trumpets or something.
Sure, Edward.
Congrats, you're a
dog of the military now.
Lieutenant Havok, take him home.
Yes, sir.
Nina...
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain something of
equal value, must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Come on, Chief.
You look like the
sky is falling down.
Don't let the
Lieutenant-Colonel get to you.
His mind's on a case now.
What case?
There's a serial killer around.
Only targets women.
Ugh... Sounds like
police business.
Why does he care?
It's the military's backyard.
It's dishonorable.
Mustang cares about that stuff.
Or wants a promotion.
It's true, kid.
Mustang's no political novice.
He'll do whatever he has to to
move up the chain around here.
But if that's all he was
about, we wouldn't follow him.
Tell me then, what
else is he about?
You'll learn soon enough.
Check it out.
Whoa, is that the real thing?
Hey, get that back,
you stupid mutt!
Does that thing have a big
tag on it that says Alexander?
Guess he's still Ed.
Your tenant's becoming a star.
Who would have thought that a 12-year-old
could actually pass the exam, right?
He is a prodigy.
Hopefully that's a blessing.
Alexander!
So, to honor Edward's groundbreaking
achievement, we're going to have a feast.
What do you say?
Hooray!
Are you serious?
Mm-hmm.
Would you like to
join us, Lieutenant?
Sorry, full schedule.
Is that so?
Oh, Mr. Tucker.
The Lieutenant Colonel asked
me to pass a message along.
Your assessment
day is coming up.
He says he's
looking forward to it.
Yes, I'm sure that he is.
This assessment deal, is
that something the state does?
Mm-hmm.
If I don't submit meaningful findings for
my research each year, they'll revoke my
certification as
a state alchemist.
Wow, that's a lot of pressure.
Last year, I didn't exactly
get a positive assessment.
So this year, it's do or die.
Let him have it, Daddy!
I know.
Why don't you make
another talking chimera?
Yeah, and we'll be
around to see it this time.
Well, that is what
everyone asks for.
I promise I'll let you
all see the result.
OOO A letter.
Who are you writing to?
A person.
It doesn't matter.
Ohhhh, it's to Winry, isn't it?
Hey, it's just a simple report.
Just passed the alchemy exam.
How's the weather?
That whole thing, okay?
Winry's a pretty name.
Is she your girlfriend?
As a matter of fact...
She's not!
We're friends!
I know.
I'm gonna write a
letter to my mom, too.
So your mom lives far away.
Doesn't she, Nina?
That's right.
She told my dad he was a good-for-nothing
alchemist who couldn't do anything right,
and she went to
live with her parents.
Hopefully, she'll
send a reply this time.
Here.
My wife.
She just couldn't stand
being poor, and she left us.
As luck would have it, I joined the
state alchemist practically the next day.
Eh.
The state's been
good to me these years.
They've given me this
mansion, this entire lifestyle.
If I don't pass the assessment,
we'll go back to the way things were.
I sometimes doubt we could.
Daddy, you can
pass it just like Dad.
Heh heh heh.
You're barking.
I get it.
You want to go
for a walk, right?
Listen to me.
I don't want this simple stuff.
I need the info on the talking chimera
that Shao Tucker made two years ago.
Hey, Sheska.
Know anything about this?
Um, the Tucker
reports are restricted, sir.
You don't have access.
Well, would you
check on it, please?
I'm not some normal kid.
That watch is what got you in here, but
you need clearance from the Brigadier
General to read those files.
Brigadier General, huh?
Surely you've heard of him?
The Ironblood Alchemist?
He's the authority on adapting
alchemy for military tactics.
If his name is attached, it
must be some military secret.
This is getting interesting.
I'm telling you,
you can't go in.
This branch is for
military use only.
Stop!
If you want access,
you've got to get a pass.
I was told this was the
only place to find out.
Stop!
What now?
Sorry.
Passed the test
like everyone else.
Hey, come back!
My brother.
What is this?
Why did you Mark me so?
This vile sign.
What do you want me to do?
Look, Elysia.
Your big brother Ed is here.
Honey, he's trying
to tell you something.
You're not listening.
Hello.
Take your time.
You know I don't
mind holding her.
Back to work.
You were asking about
Tucker's Chimera, right?
Yeah.
You being in the Investigations Department,
I thought you could tell me something.
You do live with the guy.
Why don't you ask him?
You know, he's so busy with
the coming assessment and all.
Hmm.
I don't know too
much about him myself.
I know that Chimera he fashioned
got him into the alchemy program.
First one ever that could
speak the human language.
You're sure it was real?
Definitely.
But it only spoke once.
It said, I want to die.
Apparently, it wouldn't
eat after that and died.
It was in pain. But why would
he make such a misserable thing?
Who knows?
But someone in the military
thought it had some sort of relevance.
How do you think
he got that mansion?
And what happened
to Tucker's wife?
What do you mean?
She died before he
arrived here in Central.
Is that wrong?
Yeah.
Go ahead.
Serial kill?
You sure?
Oh, hell!
Mom!
That makes five.
Hasn't investigations
found anything yet?
Don't blame us.
Mom......my
Mom
Noooo!
Sounds like you saw
something pretty awful, huh?
It's no big deal.
You were crying out for your mother
the whole time you were asleep.
And you kept saying
you were sorry.
I've had my suspicions about
you two ever since I saw your body.
Now I'm sure.
What you boys did,
it's strictly forbidden.
But I can understand.
Science is a powerful
thing, capable of so much.
If you can, it's
difficult not to try.
Who are you?
What do you want?
I don't know what Roy Mustang's
been filling your head with.
But the research of Shao Tucker falls
under the jurisdiction of me, Basque Gran.
The Brigadier General.
So that's you.
The Sewing Life Alchemist is one
of my top priorities, and I know
you've been snooping around.
I can no longer permit you
two to take shelter at his estate.
Where are you
going, big brothers?
Are you coming back?
Don't worry.
We'll come play with
you again real soon.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Don't forget!
Don't they just eat at you?
I hear when that kid showed off his
transmutation abilities without the use of
a circle, the King actually opened
up his mouth and complimented him.
Now that upstart Mustang's
getting points for discovering him.
My points, Tucker!
I'm sorry if they caused
trouble for you, sir.
I smoothed things
over for you last year.
When you turned in a pile of
trash and called it a research.
Fail it again and I'll get
the heat for endorsing you.
But, General... What, Tucker?
Would you rather the
alternative approach?
You want to pass the title of
Sewing Life Alchemist to that boy
and go back to your old life?
Drifting the streets of some backward
town with ideas and an empty stomach?
Your assessment's in two days.
It's time to show or roll over.
Daddy.
Are you hiding somewhere?
I'm at the end of the
line here, Nina.
Daddy.
Really think this
is a good idea?
What if you lose your
certification for this?
If that's what it takes to prove
me wrong tonight, then so be it.
Over here.
Come on in, boys.
I told you I'd let you see.
It's a perfect version.
A chimera that knows
the human tongue.
Listen, dear.
That's your friend Edward.
Look.
Edward....
friend?
Yes, exactly.
That's very good.
Unbelievable!
It really can talk!
I'll have no problem
getting the funding now.
I can't believe I didn't see it.
The other one it was too old to adapt.
Edward, my friend?
Yeah.
That's right.
Edward, why does it hurt here?
Brother?
So, Tucker.
Something wrong?
When was the first time you made
one of these human-speaking chimeras?
I thought I told you.
It's been two years now.
And when exactly did
your wife leave you?
Two years ago.
Why?
And those letters
that Nina wrote.
Did any of them ever reach her?
What are you getting at?
Tell me this.
Where have Alexander
and Nina gone to?
I hate prodigies like you, Ed.
Too damn perceptive.
Brother!
This guy used his own wife, Al!
And this time?
His daughter!
And his dog.
He transmuted
them into that thing.
An easy process when
you use people, right?
Why are you getting
so upset, Edward?
It's the nature of
scientific progress.
Animal testing,
experimentation, trial and error.
All advancements have a price.
Shut up!
I'm not gonna let you
rationalize this, you monster.
That was your
own family, dammit!
You've been toying
with people's lives!
Toying with lives?
What?
Like your arm and leg there?
Or your brother's body?
Or trying to bring
your mother back?
That's toying, isn't it?
You don't really think you're
any different from me, do you, Ed?
Why, Mr. Tucker?
The whole point was to pass the
assessment and continue your way of life.
But now your family's gone.
What life is left?
That's the funny thing.
I didn't have a reason.
I fully understood no matter
what I did, my life would be ruined.
I could either do it with
the science or without.
And so I chose
science to see if I could.
What kind of man... When you have the
power to do something, it's hard not to try.
Isn't that what
we agreed on, Ed?
Aren't we so much alike?
No!
Sure.
Part of me did it for
respect and this house.
Just as you partly did
it for for your mother.
But there's more.
You're desperate to
put your mind to use, Ed.
To see what you're capable of.
To put the world
under your fingers.
That's the essence of alchemy.
You did it for knowledge.
Control.
Above all, you did it
just to prove you can.
You're wrong.
Alchemy isn't meant to be.
I'm not like you!
I'm not!
Not!
Brother, you'll kill him!
No, big brother.
Nina, I want you to
bear with me, okay?
This may hurt.
What are you doing?
You're not planning to
split them up, are you?
You don't know how!
If the chimeras of perfect transmutation fuse to
the core, there's no way to separate them now.
Careful.
You'll just do to them
what you did to your mother.
You promised you'd
come play with me.
I know.
Assaulting army personnel?
What the hell's going on?
Spare me, sir.
He used his own daughter.
Mr. Tucker will face a court martial
and will take the chimera with us.
Naturally, you're to tell no
one what you saw tonight.
WHAT‽
You want to cover
it up, don't you?
You knew about this!
You want to make
some half-beast ar..
Let's go.
Yes, sir.
Damn it.
I'm not going to let them
turn her into a test subject.
Nina!
Brother!
Your makeup.
Yes, you're made up of one
part human and one part beast.
But I don't understand, brother.
How do I know that?
You poor thing.
You're a sin against nature
and your body is in so much pain.
Oh merciful God who shapes us all, please
return these scarred souls to your unending ruin.
You see her?
God I understand now.
The reason my brother
gave me this cursed arm.
So that I could find the alchemists
who have fallen from your path.
And with their own
demon arts, destroy them.
It's like an alchemist
deconstructed her.
But who?
I guess it doesn't matter.
Even if we did find them,
it wouldn't bring her back.
I'm sorry, Nina.
Brother, don't...
Full Metal Alchemist!
Episode 8, The
Philosopher's Stone.
Brother is tormented.
We're only a couple of children.
There's nothing we
can do about the killings.
At least... that's
what we thought.