Don't you see?
After these people lost Cornelo,
a widespread panic set in.
The higher-ups at Central
saw this as a golden opportunity.
A sanctioned slaughter
disguised as crowd control.
That opportunity was
created because of you, Ed.
And the people of Lior are destined to suffer the
same fate as the Ishbalans if the military has its way.
That's not true.
I will complete the Philosopher's Stone and
put an end to this oppression once and for all.
Wait!
I said wait!
This Chimera was even more advanced
than the ones Tucker was making.
I guess she was all that
was left from Laboratory Five.
I think you knew about this.
You and Lieutenant Colonel Archer
were well aware of what was going on.
Come on, Armstrong.
Spill it.
We have a right to
know what you're hiding.
Stop it.
Al.
Major Armstrong had
nothing to do with this.
I was the one hiding Marta.
What are you talking about Al?
I can't really go
into it right now.
Except to say that all this eye for
an eye stuff, it's never gonna work.
So please, stop
fighting each other.
Major, I am well aware that you are
only trying to follow in Hughes's footsteps.
Keep heading for the top.
I'll stay here and
support you from below.
That's really what you're
wanting to say to me now, right?
Old pal.
Forgive me, Colonel, but I
don't know what you mean.
Al!
Marta!
Listen carefully.
I don't have much time.
Here, get in.
You've got to tell Ed.
Tell him what?
That they're planning on
turning Lior into another Ishbal.
What?
And your leader.
The Führer.
He's a...
Homunculus!
We must stand
together, my brethren!
Any violence on our part is an open invitation for
those military vermin to authorize destroying us.
Just like Ishbal.
Lure them in, but do not resist.
Ishbala's vengeance
shall rain down upon them!
Really classy, Scar.
Using a bereaved mute
woman as your mouthpiece.
She's not just any woman.
She's our divine holy mother.
She's given us all the courage to stand
on our own without the help of a corrupt.
military or false
prophets like Leto.
Listen, as long as you're taking orders
from somebody else, nothing will ever change.
What?
You must understand, Ed.
Not everyone can
be as strong as you.
Are you wearing perfume, Lyra?
Yeah.
Bathing is a rare
luxury around here.
Yeah, well, the smell's
making me nauseous.
What do you intend
to do about Scar?
Something.
I sure as hell can't let
him go through with this.
I agree.
Despite Scar's best intentions,
there will be civilian casualties.
And if he fails to transmute the soldiers
into the stone, well, that's a risk we can't take.
I don't understand.
I thought you were one
of Scar's biggest fans.
My only true allegiance
is to the people of Lior.
Lyra, I need your help.
I have to send a letter.
It's me, Al.
He arrived this morning from Lior
with a message addressed to me.
Is it from my brother?
Is he okay?
Yes.
And according to Edward's letter, Scar's
turned the whole city into a transmutation circle.
He's warning us to stay out of
Lior no matter what happens.
Sounds like Scar's planning to use the soldiers
as components for the Philosopher's Stone.
What did you say?
In order to create the Philosopher's
Stone, you have to sacrifice human lives.
In Scar's method.
Thousands of lives.
No... no way.
So that's what they were actually
using the Laboratory Five for.
I can't believe this depravity's
been going on under our noses.
Al, I want you to head for Lior.
Once you're there, you
can meet up with Ed.
Okay, but... If I can get Bradley to
hold off, Lior will most likely surrender.
That way we can arrest Scar
before any conflict begins.
All right.
Al, wait.
This belongs to Ed.
Make sure you get it
back to him, all right?
All of those foolish
enough to run, shall die.
Talking beasts?
Are you out of your mind?
Chimera.
Then it must be them.
There's more.
They were with some guy who was
blowing stuff up with his bare hands.
What?
What is it, Scar?
Do not be deceived.
They are only trying to provoke
us into making the first attack.
Stick to the plan at all costs,
and we shall be victorious.
Now I need you to lead the
people through the escape route.
I will stay behind and extinguish the
parasite that's been tormenting your city.
You have an obligation to
get them out of here safely.
Yeah, yeah, I know.
Well, I suppose we
better get going then, huh?
Aren't you worried about
what Scar's planned?
If Mustang got my letter, the
military won't step foot in here.
Without his components,
Scar won't be able to do a thing.
He'll never succeed, Rose.
The only thing left for you to do now is
to get out of here while there's still time.
It's over.
Lior will fall.
You can blame me if you want.
I should have tried harder to
find a way to stop their madness.
Excellent.
Looks like all 7,000
men are accounted for.
Lior will be pleading for mercy
before the sun sets tomorrow.
Well, I'm not so sure.
Perhaps we ought to wait.
What do you mean?
According to the letter Colonel Mustang
received, the Fullmetal Alchemist is
still alive and well.
I believe it would be in our best interest
to try and solve this thing diplomatically.
But Führer, that's
never going to happen.
He's right.
Besides, you know we can't launch an assault
on civilians without a legitimate reason, Archer.
Pride, I don't
understand this decision.
Fortunately, that's
not your department.
Scar is counting on you
to send in those troops.
He has got to have those lives in order
to transmute the Philosopher's Stone.
Yet you seem
hell-bent on fouling it up.
You'll have to take
it up with the boss.
I'm not sure what our master's intentions
are, but I know these orders are absolute.
uh-oh.
Well, that's just
not good enough.
If Scar wants to create the
Philosopher's Stone, I'm going to help him.
Don't you think you're taking this
infatuated schoolgirl routine a bit too far?
We're alive because
of our master.
Don't forget that, Lust.
We aren't alive.
Hence the search
for that damn stone.
I guess I'll have to
take care of this myself.
Thanks for nothing, traitor.
Are you coming, Gluttony?
Want to, but I'm afraid.
Why are you
running, you cowards?
Even those Ishbalan weaklings put up more
of a fight than this, and that's not saying much.
I've overestimated them.
I thought surely they would have issued
a counterattack after all that I've done.
Guess I'll have to push harder.
So it is you.
The Crimson Alchemist.
Who the hell?
Ah, now I remember.
That scar is definitely
my handiwork.
I thought I'd got your arm.
I swore an oath not to kill
another State Alchemist.
But I'll make one
last exception!
Damn.
Oh, now it makes sense.
That's your brother's
old arm, isn't it?
How touching.
Don't bother using those stones.
I'll just absorb their
lives into my arm.
And then I'll use them to
create the Philosopher's Stone.
Why do we have
to leave the city?
We should stay and fight.
Because that's not what the
Holy Mother has planned for us.
Speaking of plans, Rose, what
are we going to do once we escape?
In the event that Scar
isn't able to succeed?
You'll be just fine.
You'll go into hiding.
Enough worrying.
I'm not worrying.
I'm just trying to make sure that we
keep moving forward with our struggle.
I know we can't fight now,
but we can do something.
Perhaps we could
alert the other cities.
And we could tell them
about Ishbal and Lior.
We could start a coup.
Talk about a pipe dream.
Even if you manage to get more people on board,
there's no way you could defeat the State's Army.
Lyra, I want you to take Rose
and get out of here right away!
I've been waiting
for you, Edward Elric.
Well, well.
It's teachers, kid.
It's Wrath.
Wrath!!!!!
Rose, you idiot!
Run!
Make it stop!
Now!!!!
Not so fast!
Rose, get out!
Scar was just using you!
You don't have to die for him!
Please go!
Go!!!!
I know what the weakness
is for you Homunculi.
Greed told me.
You lose strength if you get
close to a certain person's remains.
The one who was supposed to be brought
back in the transmutation that created you.
It makes you realize
that you're fake.
And that's why it hurts when
you're up against the real thing.
Those rules don't
exactly apply to me.
I was transmuted using my
own human body as material.
So you see, I don't
have an actual body now.
But if I had to choose
one, it'd be yours!
What the....
Go get some help!
Do you really think it wise to be chasing me around like
this when the Military could step in at any moment, Scar?
Oh, I think I'll chance it to
avenge my brother, Kimbley.
You're risking your own life for
something as pointless as revenge?
And what is it that
you're killing for?
Nothing.
Nothing?
You mean to say you slaughtered
all these people for nothing?
At the end of the day, a human being is not much
more than the components used to create a common bomb.
If you think about it,
we're not that special.
Not you.
Not me.
We're all empty.
We're all worthless.
I might be empty!
But not worthless!
Cut me some slack, Al.
I'm just a state alchemist
trying to do his job.
Just like your brother.
You're just a murderer!
And you've got to stop this.
It won't solve anything!
Stay out of it, Al.
You don't understand.
What will you accomplish?
By shedding more blood.
Please.
Just walk away.
Well, how do you like that?
Looks like I've managed to get
rid of both of your arms, old boy.
Do you smell that?
Smells like defeat.
Any minute now, your arm will begin
to absorb the oxygen from the air.
And then, kablooey!
You say humans have
no impact, no meaning.
So tell me, how much of
an impact I make on you?
Scar!
Go and find your brother.
I must do what the
two of you cannot.
What were those stones
doing on Ed's watch?
Really, Al?
You didn't expect me to play
without a loaded deck, did you?
Alphonse!
It's gonna be so
magnificent, Al.
I can feel your makeup.
You'll make such a great bomb.
Farewell, my friend.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
Hello, Edward.
My son.
Why didn't you
bring me back to life?
Ed.
Give me the body I deserve!
Stop it.
Shut up!
Shut that thing up!
Shut up.
Shut up!
Ed.
Get up Ed!
Get up!
And move forward.
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 42,
His name is unknown.
It's all happening so fast.
I'm a bomb, all the Homunculi are here, and
could this really be the Philosopher's Stone?