No!
Al!!
Teacher!
What's happening?
Al!
Help me.
That right arm of yours
is such a nuisance.
Your brother's gonna
help me crush it into pieces.
All those ugly mechanical parts.
What did you just say?
And I'll take
everything you have left.
No you won't!
No Al!
Al Don't!
Brother.
You said a Homunculus
couldn't do alchemy.
But this one's
different somehow.
And I think I know what that is.
He can transmute his
body into different materials.
By forming a
circle with its arms.
His left leg and right arm.
Because he's a Homunculus,
he can shape-shift his body.
But the real reason he
can perform alchemy is...
Because he has both
Edward's lost arm and leg.
Impossible.
This power isn't yours.
It was stolen from my brother.
His arm and leg!
Give them back!
Now!
No!
My turn now!
Brother!
Al, you have to stop this now!
What do you mean?
Are you defending
this Homunculus?
He isn't human.
Human or not, he
belongs to Izumi.
So what exactly do
you want edward?
Only what's mine!
This leg was the price you paid.
You got sommething for it didn't you?
And in exchange you
got your brothers soul.
Tell me, what price are you willing to pay now
to get your limbs back and deprive me of mine.
Equivalence?
Shut up!
Ed, no!
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Teacher?
You two boys are not
to get involved in this.
I command you.
The boy is my sin.
And mine alone to bear.
Teacher!
Not so fast!
Winry, make sure Izumi's okay!
Hey, wait a minute!
She told you guys to stop!
Funny running into you here.
You trained on this island as a
child, isn't that right, Fullmetal?
Brother, that woman... That's right,
but what are the two of you doing here?
It seems we're searching
for the same thing.
The Homunculus?
Yes, I've heard that's what
the enemy is calling itself.
Tell me, how much do you boys
really know about this subject?
Do either of you know the reason
they say Homunculus is born?
According to ancient alchemic text
and tradition, if the Homunculus actually
exists at all, it's
spawned by an Alchemist.
The unwitting side effect when
someone attempts a human transmutation.
Your father wrote about
it in his research as well.
I don't care about him.
My reasons are
no one's business.
Very well.
But if the boy that Lieutenant Colonel
Archer found was really a Homunculus,
that means someone
attempted a human transmutation.
And that is definitely
my business Fullmetal.
Human transmutation
is forbidden.
All culprits will be
punished severely.
Do either of you know
who might have done this?
Shouldn't we be worrying
about the Homunculus?
Our men are
already on his trail.
Sorry, we don't know anything.
Now if you don't
mind, we're in a hurry.
Brother?
We can't let them find
out about Izumi, okay?
I know.
I think we managed to fool them.
It wasn't that hard.
Dear Wrath, that
makes all seven of us.
Now I think it's time we
pay the old woman a visit.
Lucky for us, it's close.
I think we need to
talk to her about Greed.
Why Greed?
Because a long time ago,
she's the one who created him.
But why?
Why would you tell
my brother that heresy?
Your brother had a
great thirst for knowledge.
I simply did my
duty to quench it.
Yes, the only thing I did was hand down to
him the ancient memories of our noble people.
Do you know what you've done?
The question is, do you?
Never forget, Ishbalan.
Inside here,
they're still alive.
Countless souls waiting.
He's in here!
Look!
Due to circumstances beyond our control,
we were forced to leave our encampments.
As the leader of my people, I
accept full responsibility for this.
New residences for you and your people
have been arranged for you in the south.
You will all be
taken there soon.
Tell your people
they are not to resist.
Yes.
But before we leave, all of
your people must be registered.
By face and by name.
I see.
You're here on a manhunt.
You may begin.
Do be careful.
I'm sure I saw the homicidal
maniac among the crowd.
I recognized him from
all the wanted posters.
Is the reward still the same?
You had better
not be wrong, Yoki.
Mommy.
Dammit, where is he?
The one with the
X-shaped scar on his face?
I know you're hiding him!
Tell me, you scum!
What's this?
You buffoons better back off!
I'm protected by the...
He's been shot!
But I didn't hear a gun.
Hold.
your fire, you bastards!
Everyone, please, stay calm.
Who shot that man?
It's all happening again!
Another massacre!
I can't take any more of this!
Yeah, they're right!
I refuse to live in
fear any longer!
Too many of our friends
have been slaughtered!
Death to the military dogs!
Yes!
Come on!
Go back where you came from!
Leave us alone!
Take that!
Time for crowd
control, Lieutenant.
Yes, sir.
What are you waiting for?
I need you to
cover me right now.
And clean that mess off
your forehead, would you?
Sir!
It's a shame when a teacher's
as misguided as her students.
Ed, Al, despite my sins,
I have to draw the line.
You can no longer
study under me.
I didn't teach you alchemy so
you could echo my mistakes.
Destroy your own bodies.
Disrupt the world's flow.
I won't stand for
your fighting, either.
But Teach...
We appreciate
all you've taught us.
Please, take care of yourself.
Come on, guys.
This can't be the end.
Are you sure you want to
leave on bad terms like this?
Take care, Sig.
Goodbye, you two.
Make sure to stop by
next time you're here.
But... I don't think
we're exactly welcome.
Idiots!
Now that you boys are no longer Izumi's
students, you're free to start a real relationship with her.
As equals.
That's right!
You don't have to feel
constrained anymore.
She can be your friend now.
Aw, dammit.
Al, we can't leave yet.
Okay.
Just watch your head.
Teacher, we need a lead.
I know you can help us return
our bodies to the way they were.
We won't take no for an answer.
Leave!
We're not leaving.
Not without knowing how to get a
Philosopher's Stone without human sacrifice.
It's our only chance.
Leave!
We won't leave!
Then I'll cut you up!
Do what you will!
We won't go.
There must be a way for us to send
that Homunculus back to the other side.
That's none of your concern boys.
I told you the child
is my responsibility.
We're willing to bear your sins with
you, so you can help us bear ours.
Persistent brats.
You're keeping close
watch on the brothers?
Yes, sir.
Keep up the strict surveillance and
inform me of any new developments.
Sir!
You're back to the
Elric brothers, sir?
We've no choice.
I've received reports from Central
that the Führer has in fact traveled south.
And is conducting his own
investigation into the Homunculus.
That troubles me.
It completely contradicts
what we were told yesterday.
So if the Führer has made it his direct
responsibility to capture the fugitive Homunculus.
Then we have to make it our highest priority to
be aware of every move the Elric brothers make.
Because there's a chance they'll
lead us right to another Chimera.
And Kimbley too.
Let's go.
I've got a bad feeling
about this place.
Oh yeah?
What's that?
You guys... go back to the
Devil's Nest and wait for me.
You're not going out
there alone, are you?
I'm just curious
about something.
Very well. Al, you say you have no
memory of the other side of the gate, correct?
That's right.
Then maybe your body's still
there along with your memories.
But it sure won't be
easy to retrieve them now.
Of course it won't,
but we're up to the task.
With the Philosopher's Stone, we
may be able to open the gate again.
But this time, ignore the
principle of equivalent exchange.
Equivalency.
Tell me, do you really
believe in that principle, Ed?
Of course he does.
To obtain something of
equal value must be lost.
It's not just the law of alchemy,
it's the way everything in life works.
You do a great job reciting it.
But my son lost his
life before he was born.
And what did he get in return?
Absolutely nothing.
There was no equivalency.
Apparently, I'm not
much of a teacher after all.
Mason!
Yes!
Show them the way
to Dante's house.
They're making a trip there
tomorrow to pick up my medicine.
Enjoy the trip, boys.
It should be educational.
I wonder what Dante
is going to be like.
According to Mason, she's a
world-renowned pharmacist.
Brother, there's something
I've been meaning to ask you.
If it's true that a Homunculus is created
from failed human transmutation the... Come on, Al.
Pick up the pace.
Hello?
Anybody home?
We've been expecting you,
Dante's anxious to meet you both.
What?
I know you!
Lyra!
I apologize for my
actions when we last met.
What are you doing here?
Dante was kind enough to let
me stay here as her apprentice.
One day, I hope to be a
great Alchemist just like her.
Wait a minute.
I didn't know Dante
was an Alchemist.
The best.
And after I met you two boys in
Youswell, I knew I had to improve my skills.
And be a master Alchemist.
Well, you've sure done a 180.
It's open.
The Elric brothers have arrived.
I've been waiting for you,
Edward and Alphonse Elric.
So you're Dante, are you?
That's right.
And you two must be
Izumi's great apprentices.
I've heard what's going on.
Come with me, and I'll make a
fresh batch of medicine for her.
I'm sorry.
What's your
relationship with Izumi?
Simple.
She was my apprentice
many, many years ago.
I'm the one who
taught her alchemy.
I didn't know that.
Yes.
So that means you're
our teacher's teacher.
Yes, I suppose so.
I'll be damned.
How did I ever get so lucky?
I just stopped by to see an old friend,
and who should I find in her mansion?
Well, as long as I'm here,
I should have some fun.
You can't be serious.
You're a fellow State Alchemist.
Tell me you don't want it, too.
We just got a
message from Greed.
He's got a job for us.
Why don't you think
it over for a while?
Dante, if I may ask, what made
you want to become an Alchemist?
A number of reasons.
Maybe it's foolish, but the most
important reason is I wanted to help people.
Humans need alchemy
more than they'll ever know.
That doesn't mean alchemy is necessary for life,
but it can provide valuable relief to those who need it.
And I enjoy making people happy,
rewarding them for their hard efforts in life.
Providing a
balance, if you would.
Equivalency.
That's right.
He can only achieve happiness who
puts forth an equal amount of work.
No greater truth.
Dante, what do you think
about the Philosopher's Stone?
Why?
Are you two looking for it?
N..No, I was just curious.
Everyone who's gone looking for the stone
has found nothing but unhappiness in the end.
I wonder if mankind truly is ready
to possess such a powerful thing.
You really look
like your father, Ed.
I know.
I knew him very well.
Hohenheim of Light, he sought
after the Philosopher's Stone as well.
Tell us more.
Do you know where
your father's living now?
I don't care.
Brother.
They're separated.
Great.
Handle it just like we planned.
Nice and easy.
Let's go.
Time for fun.
It's you again!
Damn you!
You surprised?
I call it the Ultimate Shield.
Lyra?
LYra!
Don't move.
We have no intention of harming
you or the old lady if you cooperate, kid.
Dante!
Hello.
Who are you guys?
We're kidnappers.
Who are you kidnapping?
You, Alphonse Elric.
I'm sorry, but you're going
to have to come with us now.
But my teacher taught me never
to go anywhere with strangers.
Don't be ridiculous.
How old are you?
Fourteen.
If you're that old, you should be able to
think and act for yourself by now, am I right?
Listen, kid.
If you ever want to be a man,
then you gotta act like one.
You can't let your teacher
run your life forever, right?
Right.
I should think for myself.
Now you're talking.
Then we're clear.
You're gonna come with U...
I decided not to go with strangers.
That's my decision
and mine alone.
Well, this should be fun.
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 33, Al, Captured.
I have no intention of negotiating with the
lowly thugs who kidnap my my brother.
I will get him back.