Let's see.
These smell good, right?
This is Mustang.
Yes, hello, Lieutenant
Colonel Mustang?
This is Edward Elric
reporting at the station, sir.
Easy, kid.
Don't be uptight.
You know, it sounds like you've
been rehearsing this or something.
Sorry, sir.
I mean, Roy.
I mean--we're boarding
the 9:20 train for Central.
Roger that.
Hey, wait a minute.
There's one leaving
before that, isn't there?
Yeah, but we had a little
detour and we got here late.
I think it's already leaving.
Get on it.
But why does it matter?
Take it or go home!
Hey, Al!
Boarding time!
Now?
Change of plans!
Come on!
Let's test their luck.
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Fullmetal Alchemist: Episode 4
The Man with the Mechanical Arm
I can't get a solid read on
this Mustang character yet.
What kind of guy
do you think he is?
Uh.
Heh-heh!
Awww.
Brother, am I scary?
Please, your kindness in a can.
Look, Mom, he's strange.
Strange?
That's not nice, Marin.
You shouldn't
say things like that.
But look at him.
He must like armor a
lot to wear it everywhere.
Even on a train.
Do you think he gets hot?
Nothing to see here, folks.
Nope. Nothing
out of the ordinary.
Heheh
Geez, Al.
No one told me we had
tickets to the Normalcy Express.
There, you see, Al?
She's not scared.
She likes you, right?
Cooler than skin, huh?
All right, Marin, you've
bothered them enough.
[Laughter]
[Sigh]
Guess they've had their
fill of adventure for now.
General, it's great you could make this trip
and bring your family along without incident.
Yes, the bureaucrats
say the East is unstable.
Gives them an
excuse not to travel!
[Laughter]
The higher-ups
sure do take it easy.
Makes you think we're
on a pleasure line.
Speaking of, where's Hughes?
I don't like him out of sight.
Sir, he's at the switchboard talking to
Lieutenant Colonel Mustang about possible gaps.
Better be vital.
Sir?
I don't like him
tying up the lines.
I'm telling you,
Roy, it's a trip.
Ever since she got pregnant, she's
turned hotter than a love goddess.
It's the miracle of hormones.
It's like this angel flew down from
heaven and kissed her on the...
[Annoyed groan]
Lousy phones!
Cutting off my conversations!
I can't do anything here.
You're the one that we
can't do anything with.
Now, how do they expect me to run
a tight security with a family of four?
What?
And a love bird.
So how am I gonna handle it
if she has the baby tomorrow?
I mean emotionally.
Hughes.
You've told me about
this 50 times already.
If you're really having problems
containing yourself, take it up with your wife.
I already have, Roy.
I talked to her this morning.
Then stop bothering me!
I'm sorry to
interrupt you, Major.
But let me offer a
bit of feminine advice.
Babies aren't born
after just five months!
Uh, sorry I lost you.
Jeez, she actually believes
we're talking seriously here?
Major breach!
Okay, that'll do it, Hughes.
I've just gotten confirmation
from Intel we're not being tapped.
How's the train look?
Are there any
suspicious Os or Ps?
Nope.
No persons, no objects.
In view, anyway.
But I've got a bad
feeling about this.
There's been more boarding
and unboarding than...
Yeah, go ahead.
There's somebody here!
Tell me.
A man on the train!
He looks like he's
ready for a full assault!
You found weapons?
No!
He's in a huge suit of armor!
What?
Armor?
[Roy laughs]
That guy's okay.
And there should be
another kid with him.
Sort of a pipsqueak.
Pipsqueak?
He's right.
There is someone with him.
And he is small.
Who are you calling a rock so tiny that he can
only be seen with a magnifying glass, you jerk?
Relax, kid.
The colonel said it.
I was just repeating...
[Gasping]
No heroes today.
Everybody shut up and get
your hands over your heads.
Or say hello to a bullet.
[Gunshot, thud]
[Gunfire]
[Groaning]
Who are you?
Good morning, General Hakuro.
Hughes, what is it?
Has something happened?
Hughes, talk to me.
Go tell Bald.
We've got the switchboard.
It looks intact.
They didn't have
anybody manning it.
You think it's them, sir?
We've got a call to
headquarters from general Hakuro
he says it's an emergency.
Patch it through.
It's me.
Lieutenant Colonel Mustang.
You there?
Speaking for the Eastern
Liberation Front Blue Squad.
The name is Bald.
We've got the train
and your general.
What do you want?
Don't play stupid.
We lost contact with one
of our allies this morning.
Someone who was supposed
to deliver a manifesto to you.
I don't know what you mean.
Okay, fine.
I'll give you the short version.
You have our
leader in prison eight.
Bring him to Central Station.
We'll have ourselves a trade.
Very well then.
We have a deal.
But I don't want any fatalities.
If one man...
You're sure about this?
They have the manifesto.
They're serious.
But you know the General's
policy on negotiating with terrorists.
He'll hold you--Easy, Hawkeye.
No one's really negotiating
with anyone today.
I've already made arrangements.
Something ain't sitting right.
What is this Mustang up to now?
If he tries anything,
don't think it'll just be you.
I'll kill every damn
passenger on this train!
Brother?
Don't worry.
Helmet, take it off.
[Gasp] Look!
Bad idea.
You dumb kid.
What are we supposed to do now?
Don't you think they'll notice when
two of their men have gone missing?
And what's gonna
happen to us then?
They'll want retribution.
We would have been safe if we had
just cooperated until we got to Central.
That's right.
What were you thinking?
What do we do next?
Didn't plan that far.
[Groaning]
[Gunshot]
Are you guys okay?
Yeah.
Sorry about that.
Your big brothers here will
take care of this somehow, okay?
Mm-hmm
We'd better get started, Al.
Right.
Wait!
Over here!
How embarrassing.
Who are you guys?
Freelancers?
Just two old-fashioned
alchemists.
You don't say.
Well, I'm Fallman,
State Warrant Officer.
A soldier, huh?
You don't look like one.
Yes, well, there's
a reason for that.
We've got a special
passenger on board.
You know, the front car kind.
So that's why these
thugs are here, isn't it?
And they decided to
drag us down with them.
Al, I'm going up top to
throw a surprise party.
You go with him from below.
Uh?
Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, go ahead.
Get over here
quick, that damn kid.
Hey, there's something
funny going on next door.
Wait, you shouldn't do that.
[Gunfire]
[Screams]
I tried to warn you
about the ricochet.
You'll only hurt yourself.
What happened?
No, wait!
[Gunfire]
[Gunman groans]
[Sigh]
Problem bald.
We've lost all contact
with the rear cars.
What's going on here?
Damn Mustang's re-negging
on our deal, that's what.
Did you really think
this could work?
You're a ragtag extremist
group with an outdated cause.
You can't outgun
the state military.
Why don't you just
surrender while you can?
[Gunshot, he groans]
I'm the one who's giving the
orders around here, General.
Don't forget.
I want a fresh sweep of every
inch of this train, understand?
And check the outsides, too.
Top to bottom.
You know, there's a
real art to train walking.
I'm shocked you
made it this far.
Thanks. I guess.
I'm Major Hughes, and you're
Edward Elric, is that right?
Yeah, that's right.
Mustang told me about you two.
I'm an old friend of his.
The lieutenant colonel?
Yep.
And he's always bragging
about that silly promotion, too.
Come on, Ed, we'd
better work as a team.
Hey, what's the matter?
Where'd you come from?
Well, looky there.
A sitting duck. [Gunshot]
Hey!
You okay?
[Gunshot]
What the?
Oh, man, that was smooth.
Hey, you!
Don't mess with that tinder!
It's the life of this train!
Right.
Sorry.
Box of Tinder.
You can't go up there, Bald.
There's something crazy up top.
We've lost contact with
all the other cars now.
They said something
about a guy in armor.
Then the line went dead.
What's going on?
Control yourself.
Attention gun-toting extremists.
Hear me all right?
Or did you blow your ears
out playing target practice?
What the hell is that?
Let the hostages go.
You've got no right to drag these
travelers into your personal politics.
You're one of Mustang's
secret agents, aren't you?
Interfere and I'll kill these
hostages one by one.
You're just itching to
draw blood, aren't you?
All right!
Looks like... a pipe.
Okay, passengers.
Please hold onto your seats
and get ready for some turbulence!
Argh!
Whoa!
Here goes.
Welcome to the brig.
Just look on the
bright side, Bald.
You probably needed a shower.
[Gunfire]
What's the matter?
Don't like my company?
Before I finish off the
General, I'll take care of you.
Me first!
Two automailers.
Go figure.
You're just a brat.
Don't tell me the army's feeding
kids into its chop house now.
You're gonna pay
for that brat comment.
And no one's feeding
me into anything.
I'm on my own.
A little piece of advice, kid.
I used to be in
this military, too.
It was fine as long as
I was pissing on cue.
But then I wanted
this upgraded arm.
They didn't like that.
Felt I'd be stronger
than my superiors.
You see, the queen bees don't like it when
the little workers have a sting they can't control.
Shortly after the procedure,
they discharged me.
Since then, I've gotten a taste for
destroying them and the nation they command.
You understand, kid.
You've got an
arm just like mine.
You've wanted
to be stronger, too.
And the military, they'll just get rid of
you as soon as you're not convenient.
No, I don't understand.
And don't you ever lump
in my reasons for this arm.
With yours!
Well, good grief.
That was something different.
Don't take any lives.
That's all I asked you, Bald.
And as it turns out, it seems
you did just as you were told.
So I take it you're Mustang.
[Scream]
That flame!
That's awesome!
I controlled myself.
The damage to your skin
isn't nearly as bad as it feels.
You can call me Roy Mustang.
Or just Lieutenant Colonel.
Hell, you can call me
the Flame Alchemist.
Whatever you do,
remember the pain.
So he's Mustang.
Brother?
Hey!
You knew.
That's why you made
us take this train.
You put us at risk on purpose.
Come on, Ed.
You think I've got the
whole world on strings?
Anyway, you should focus
on the good news here.
The General heard about your exploits saving
the train and agreed to make a special exception.
He's letting you take
the State Alchemy Exam.
You're going to be the
talk of the military, kid.
Exception?
But you always
said we could take it!
That's the reason we came!
Be realistic, Ed.
The State's never let a kid
take a military exam before.
But... I guess
luck's on your side.
Good thing you took that
earlier train, don't you think?
Whether or not you take
the test is still up to you.
I'm not trying to run your life.
Of course I'll take it!
And pass!
I would have done it anyway!
Those people had us dancing right in
the palms of their hands, didn't they?
I guess it doesn't
matter what we do.
We'll never be
the ones in control.
There they are.
Over here.
Over here!
[Laughter]
Uh?
Hey, Marin!
Thank you, Big Brothers!
I'll remember you!
[Laughter]
Thank you.
Full Metal Alchemist
Episode 6, The Alchemy Exam.
No one but me thinks
Brother can pass the
military's rigorous tests.
But on that winter morning,
a great flower will bloom.