Look, he's awake.
Thank goodness.
Are you feeling okay?
I guess.
Where's Al?
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Sorry, Al.
That's twice now
you've been carved up.
I'll fix you right away.
Yeah.
Edward, sir, that was
some stir you caused.
What happened to you in Lab 5?
Nothing much.
Nothing much?
You and Al were seriously hurt!
Come on, I've had a lot worse.
I was just one baby step away from
getting my hands on the truth, too.
I won't botch it next time.
Edward, sir!
I apologize in advance for this.
You nearly died, and you
put your brother at risk.
You need to remember
you're still a child.
And you have to start trusting
adults with a little bit more of the work.
My conduct was improper
for a lower officer, sir.
Forgive me.
Forgive me, too, sir!
No, you've got a point.
I'm sorry.
Yep, he's gonna hate me.
It's one of his
parts, all right.
Oh, how could this happen?
I've been praised as a young,
gifted automail engineer!
It's the worst
mistake of my career!
Is something the matter?
No, nothing at all!
I just, uh, I hit my
thumb with a wrench.
Hello, Rockbell Automail
Prosthetic Limb Outfitters.
Uh, Winry?
Ed, hi there.
I've got some kind of problem.
I can't move my arm anymore.
Sounds right.
Why?
What do you mean?
Uh, nothing at all.
I just, I told you I made it lighter,
and it would be a little more fragile.
That's why it makes sense.
You've done something
reckless again, haven't you?
Anyway, I can't make it out to Risembool
right now, so I'm kind of a fix here.
Don't worry!
I'll come to you!
Just stay there and relax,
and I'll jump on the train today!
You're being unusually
kind today, Winry.
Oh, don't be silly.
You know I'm always kind, Ed.
Right.
See you here.
Thanks.
Huh.
Make sure you do the
maintenance right this time, kid.
Right.
Just following orders.
I don't know what's in there.
The Splatterpot is bizarre.
Hey, Edward.
I heard that you've been
up and around today.
Yeah, a little.
How about you, Al?
You holding up too?
Sure.
Oh, I forgot.
I haven't had lunch.
Oh, well, I'll get
you some food, sir.
Yeah.
Lieutenant Ross, why
don't you go with him?
Understood, sir.
Thanks.
I'm real hungry.
I've just been so busy.
About Lab 5...
As far as the official military report
goes, everything that happened there is
considered collateral damage caused
by Scar while he was pursuing you.
But needless to say, I'm
not really convinced of that.
We found a lot of corpses we suspect
were chimeras, and a great deal of
sophisticated equipment I can't help
but think was working until yesterday.
And surviving prisoners claim they were
taken there by Brigadier General Grand,
who we both know is in a
grave with an exploded skull.
Ed, what the hell happened?
Ed?
How should I know?
I passed out.
Don't give me that.
Just tell me what
you saw, will ya?
Homunculi.
You're kidding me.
Artificial people?
That's right.
Believe me, they
weren't human at all.
So they're connected with
the Philosopher's Stone?
I'll say.
They were trying to convince me to
create a stone for them to make them human.
And worse, they wanted me to
use those prisoners to pull it off.
That's hard to believe.
Tell him Al, isn't that right?
Yes.
A guardian whose soul
was attached to armor.
A psychopath named Envy.
Tattoos of Ouroboros, the
serpent that devours its own tail.
And the arrays to make
a Philosopher's Stone.
Those are the things I
saw in there, Hughes.
This is turning into an awfully serious matter,
and the whole thing is about a little red stone.
It's been serious for years now.
Dr. Marcoh told me the stone was used
as a weapon in the Eastern Rebellion.
Anyway, these homunculi told me they
were keeping me alive for their sakes.
That they were told to.
Thanks for the information, Ed.
I'll take it from here.
Now get some rest.
Why don't you and your brother just
worry about yourselves for a while?
Ah, cushionless seats.
Let's see... Ed said he'd have
a sign for me or something.
My warmest welcome, Winry.
Thank you for going to the
trouble of this late victory.
That works.
Edward, you didn't tell me that you
were in the hospital for this!
Yeah, well, one
thing led to another.
It's nothing to laugh about.
What's wrong?
I didn't do the maintenance on
your automail the way I should've.
And now... This is my fault.
No, don't say that!
There's a lot of other
things to blame, right, Al?
Right.
See there?
And Al doesn't lie.
Yeah, but... Your
maintenance was perfect.
It always has been.
It's complicated machinery,
and I'm slinging it all around.
It was bound to jam up sometime.
I mean, honestly, the
timing was pretty good.
If it had stopped earlier,
I'd be a lot worse off.
It broke because
I was rough with it.
Don't worry.
Could he actually not have noticed
that I forgot to use that screw?
You're right, Ed.
You're too rough.
I'm reckless klutz, really.
Lieutenant Colonel, sorry to interrupt,
but there's a call from Colonel Mustang.
Yo, Roy!
Good timing!
I've got great news!
What, your soldiers
have found Scar?
No, you obsessed idiot!
How would that be great news?
Did you honestly forget?
Tomorrow is Elicia's birthday!
We're throwing her a
party and everything!
Unless you want to become Charcoal Maze,
you'd better tell me the news from Central.
Don't worry.
If anything important
happens, I'll let you know.
In the meantime, make sure
you send my daughter a present.
Bye now!
But, sir, are you sure it's
okay not to tell him anything?
About the boys?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Right now, it's better if
he doesn't know anything.
Right.
But enough of that.
You got those reports?
Yeah!
Working nonstop without sleep,
I've managed to finish them all!
Great!
Here's a list of
what's next, doll.
Ah!
Oh!
How you doing?
Well, Ed, looks like you're
done with your dinner.
Uh-huh.
Don't be a baby.
It won't hurt much.
You didn't drink your milk.
Edward.
You drink it?
I hate milk.
It's like drinking vomit.
What are you talking about?
Milk's good for you!
Drink it!
Forget it!
I hate what I hate!
It's not like I'll die because
I don't drink that crap!
Jeez!
Then this is the reason you're always
going to... It's gonna be the size of a bean!
A bean!
Yeah!
Right, Al?
Just do what she says, Ed.
Drink the dumb milk.
Yeah, sure.
Easy for you to say, Al.
You're lucky you didn't have
to drink anything to get that big.
Shut up.
It wasn't my choice
to be this way.
Right, Al.
I'm sorry.
Hey, what's wrong with you guys?
Are you fighting?
Al?
I've never seen you like this.
Did something happen?
Why is that?
I've known you my whole life
and you don't tell me anything.
I'm standing here worrying about you guys, yet you
don't have the decency to tell me why you're fighting!
Or how you... got hurt
or anything important!
It's always secrets with you.
I don't care anymore!
Hi, it's nice to finally
meet you, Winry.
I'm Ed & Al's friend,
the Lieutenant Colonel.
Or, Maes Hughes.
Oh, hey.
Oh, and lest I forget...
This here is my
beautiful daughter, Elicia.
Isn't she a bundle
of divine cuteness?
You're dying to
meet her, aren't you?
Uh, yes, I guess.
Alright, then I'm gonna let you.
Don't you worry about Winry.
I'm gonna look
after her for a while.
Bye now.
Sir...
This is gonna be great!
You have no idea how lucky
you are coming into town today!
It's Elicia's birthday tomorrow!
I forgot.
It's Ed's, too.
Ah, that's an excellent point.
We'll have to get him a
present, too, while we're out.
So, come on.
You can tell me.
I'm dying to know.
What kind of gift are
you getting for Elicia?
What?
A teddy bear?
One bigger than she is?
Great!
She'll absolutely love that!
Congratulations!
Happy birthday, Elicia!
She's getting so big!
I'm telling you, apples always
bake better with maple syrup.
Oh, they do!
You're lucky.
My daughter's
been a handful lately.
It looks really soft, too.
You should put him in an outfit.
Hi, Elicia!
You wanna see what I got you?
My favorite story
when I was a kid!
Oh, thank you!
Your dad's friend, the bookworm.
Bookworm?
You're pretty.
Hey there, Elicia.
Can you tell me how
old you are today?
One, two, three... I'm four!
Right!
You're so adorable!
Winry, you know what?
Hmm?
Congratulations,
congratulations, congratulations.
Know why?
Daddy says when you tell someone
congratulations, good things will happen to them.
So I'm telling you!
Thank you.
That's sweet.
My, my.
If I didn't know, I'd think the
two of you were really sisters.
Do you think so?
I always wished I had
a little sister like this.
I'm just an only
child, after all.
You have brothers.
Two great ones.
No, I don't.
Real brothers would tell me things
and let me into their lives a little.
But those two have always kept me at
arm's length from anything that actually matters.
Sorry.
Can't help that.
Guys like them, they speak more
with their actions than their words.
They like people to be happy.
They do dangerous work and they don't
want to burden anyone else with their problems.
Or make them worry about them.
So they keep quiet.
But despite all that, when the pressure
valve breaks and they have to talk,
you're the one they'll go to.
Right?
You're the one they can
count on when they need to.
And that in itself says a lot.
But for brothers to count on their older sister,
she's going to have to be there and be strong.
That makes sense.
Here you go.
Thanks for waiting.
It's Edward's birthday
cake, fresh from the oven.
I hope he likes it.
Go on.
Go see him.
Here.
Oh, Mr. Hughes, don't you
have a present for Ed, too?
What's the point?
There's not a gift I could give him that
wouldn't dull in comparison to your smiling face.
Congratulations! Congratulations!
Congratulations, Ed.
Know why?
Because the more people tell you
congratulations on your birthday,
the more good things
will happen to you.
Huh.
Here it's from Gracia.
Okay.
Thank you.
It's a cake, and I copied
the recipe from her.
When you get your body back and
can eat Al, I'll make one for you, too.
Okay?
Whatever.
Oh, yeah.
The three of us always used to eat
cake together on our birthdays, didn't we?
Yeah.
Remember when Den ate Al's cake?
We knew because of the paw
prints made with the frosting.
Al cried.
Yeah, that's right.
That happened to me?
Yeah.
You and the dog were
both pretty little then.
Why, you don't remember it?
No.
Something the matter, Al?
I'll be outside on the roof
until you're done repairing Ed.
Al...
Are you sure you'll
be okay out here?
I mean, by yourself?
Yeah.
All right.
Well, I'll come back
to move you later.
Thanks.
Ed, something happened
between you and Al, didn't it?
I... I did something
awful to him, Winry.
I had the chance to do it.
To change him back to normal.
And I hesitated.
And how come?
Because in order for it to work, I would
have had to sacrifice some other people.
It all would have been for Al.
Compared to him, those other people
shouldn't have meant anything to me.
But I... I just couldn't do it.
Not with him watching me.
My conscience got in the way.
It's a good thing it did.
After all, Al is a
selfless person.
He wouldn't have
been happy in that body.
Even if it's what he wants most,
how could he take that burden,
seeing the ones who died
every time he looked at his skin?
I promised.
Think about it.
Maybe there's another reason.
Maybe he's upset because he saw the brother he
idolizes even consider taking someone else's life.
How do you know you don't love
him because he made it so you would?
Tailored your memories and
personality to suit him best!
I can implant those in the
mind of the homunculus.
Giving birth to a Nina
even more perfect.
Was I ever really human at all?
All done.
Come on now, let's go
have you take care of Al.
Yeah, but... I have no
idea what to say to him.
Just say sorry, you goof.
A simple apology.
It isn't hard to do.
You rant for hours and
you can't say two words?
Yeah, let's go.
Listen, I'm sorry.
And I'm gonna fix you right now.
I brought these
parts from Risembool.
They should be enough.
Trust me.
I'm not gonna give
up on this yet, Al.
We're gonna do this, but
we'll do it the right way.
And we'll be normal again.
I'm sure.
Maybe you can go
back to normal, brother.
And I hope you do.
But I'm not sure I ever can.
Al, what are you talking about?
Of course you can, Al.
Here goes.
How's that?
That's how you made me this way when you
attached my soul to this armor in the first place, isn't it?
That's right.
Along with my memories.
After all, memories are just information
you can reference, like a cabinet of files.
As skilled an alchemist as you are, you could
have created any memories you wanted me to have.
Fake memories?
Don't tell me that's
what you're upset about.
Why shouldn't it be?
A while back in Risembool, there was
something you wanted to tell me, but you couldn't.
You said you were
afraid of how I'd react.
You remember that, don't you?
I can't remember parts of my
past because they never happened.
My memories and
my soul are fake.
Something you created.
Isn't that what
you wanted to say?
No!
What Ed wanted to tell you
was that... Stop lying to me!
I know what the truth is.
The person named Alphonse
Elric never existed at all.
That makes no sense!
You and Ed have
always been together!
I knew you when you were a boy!
My grandma did too!
We're friends, Al!
You can trust me!
Can I?
Really?
How can I believe anyone
when there's no way to prove it?
When I'm just a hollow shell?
All three of you can
be in on it together!
So... you've been sitting on
those thoughts all this time.
Is there anything
else you're hiding?
That you want to say?
What about you,
my so-called brother?
Answer my question!
Why won't you say anything?
Unless it's truth!
Let go of me!
What's the point
of living this lie?
You idiot!
Let go of me!
Let go!
Al!
Stop!
I won't stay here!
Edward!
Alphonse...
Stay back!
Hold on...
Just stay back!
Keep away from me!
Please, Al!
Al!
Wait!
Ed, no!
AL!
AL!!!!!!
Full Metal Alchemist.
Episode 24.
Bonding Memories.
Even if everyone else has
forgotten, I still remember.
Your voice.
Your warmth.
Your smile.