Eastern Border: the Town of Lior
If he's really a prophet, who can make
miracles whenever he wants, then why is it
turning out like this?
Please, cease fighting.
Surrender and the military will honor either
side. Surrender! This is your final warning!
But Rose, isn't it bad
we're not fighting too?
What for?
Look at them all.
Humans are foolish
beyond salvation.
Foolish, foolish. HEHEHEHE
Don't be so hard on them.
After all our planning, I
think this mayhem feels nice.
Well, if it isn't our
personal prophet.
Work well!
Please, I only
mobilize the believers.
Before long, believers find differences
between each other and fight.
It's only better now, with
the military stepping into help.
No matter how many times they
repeat the lesson, they never learn.
Human beings are foolish,
miserable things, aren't they?
All this production.
Just to make a
Philosopher's Stone.
At least I can change now.
Back into this adorable form.
That one again?
You love making
yourself look young.
What else can I do?
I've forgotten what I
originally looked like.
What are you doing here?
Where is Father Cornelo?
The real one?
What have you done with him?
What should we say?
Why don't we tell
him the truth, Lust?
Cornello's been gone
a rather long time.
Can I eat him?
[Gluttony laughs]
[Screaming]
[Squelching noises]
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed that
to be the world's one, and only, truth.
Destruction's Right Hand.
Come to mention it, I did
hear some juicy information.
That curiosity of ours is left
central, heading eastward.
You mean the state
alchemist killer?
The Flame Colonel's
in the east now.
Who else?
Well, you know the
fullmetal pipsqueak is there.
Yes.
Right now, that boy is
the closest one to our goal.
We can't afford to have him moving
around acting on behalf of his own interests.
Not anymore.
I'm done, lust!
Now what have I told you?
Wipe your mouth, gluttony.
Sorry!
So, what of this killer?
We call him Scar.
That a code name?
I don't know, it's
all that we've got.
Several eyewitnesses have described a
man with a large scar on his forehead fleeing
the scenes of the murders.
And you're sure
he killed them all?
Five well-trained state
alchemists all by himself?
Nine, actually.
Five kills in central,
four of them alchemists.
Cops have turned up five more state
alchemists in various other parts of the country.
If you throw in aides and guards
who got in the way, it's into the dozens.
We know it's him because the MO's
identical, and it's not the kind of thing
you can copycat.
He explodes their brains, Roy,
and we don't know why he's doing it.
Everyone's panicked
they'll be next.
So all of central command made the excuse
they were with the Fuhrer and came here
en masse, thinking not even a killer
would come to this backwoods place.
You're here, after all.
Those up the chain that gave you this
demotion of a transfer three years ago,
they're aware of your abilities.
Your protection for them.
Hell, Maes, now you're
getting me shaken up.
So that's the big question.
Who will be the next target?
Pardon me.
Oh, thanks.
I'm very flattered, but I have
a three -year-old girl, see.
You have a call?
Oh, right.
Sorry.
Lieutenant Colonel
Hughes, go ahead.
Understood.
I'll be right there.
Well, our question's
been answered.
They found another soldier
dead at his guard station.
Skull blown up.
From the inside.
Dr. Marcoh?
You mean Master Mauro?
No, Marcoh.
Sorry, this village only has one
doctor, and Master Mauro is his name.
As you can see, folks don't
have much money here.
Travel's hard.
I used to take a half-day trip to East
City to see a doctor before he came.
He's a nice man.
He'll take in any patient, even people
they said were incurable elsewhere.
When I got my leg caught under the tractor and thought I was
done, he fixed me like you couldn’t even tell it had happened.
He treated me when I was sick
too. There was a big flash of light.
Flash of light...
Yeah, it's got to be alchemy.
This is Dr. Marcoh.
But he's a fugitive.
Why would he become a
miracle-performing doctor?
He had to know what
would draw attention.
Down!
Why?
Al!
This is a bad idea.
I'm filling up with straw.
Shh!
Who's that?
A State Alchemist.
I recognize him from HQ.
He's one of those guys
who came in with the Fuhrer.
But why is he here?
Did he follow us?
I don't know how
else to explain it.
The colonel said he's never reported
Marcoh's whereabouts to Central Command.
Come on, Al.
We better go straight
to Marcoh's from here!
Ugh!
Ahhh!
Easy there, Doc.
We don't want any trouble.
I know what you want.
You said you're
a State Alchemist.
You think you can
take me back there?
Then you are Dr. Marcoh,
The Crystal Alchemist.
Is that really true?
No.
No more questions or orders.
I couldn't bear it going
back to that place.
That's not it.
Listen.
Put the gun down.
Please.
Or have you come to silence me?
Think you can kill me?
Well, I don't have to
just let that happen.
Al..
It's all okay.
Shoot if you want.
But I won't die.
You're the only one
who might get hurt.
I see.
You're him.
You're the Fullmetal Alchemist.
No, for the hundredth time!
That name belongs to me!
So I deserted the battlefield.
When I left, I stole all the
research I'd compiled at the time.
Their books.
My notes.
I have a hunch the military is still looking
for me so they can see what I found out.
That's it.
Why he sent us.
We're researching
human transmutation.
Forget it.
I can't show you my work.
The orders from
above notwithstanding.
I dirtied my hands
with that research.
Then the military, they put
it to use on those people.
In that Eastern
Rebellion massacre.
You mean the uprising in Ishbal?
That is what you're
talking about. Right?
Armageddon.
That's the only word
that fits that battle.
Women.
Children.
It didn't matter.
Everyone was killed.
And there wasn't
any real reason.
All they said was the
people of Ishbal defied them.
Spoke out against the system.
What I was responsible
for I could never make up.
Even taking my life
would be a token gesture.
So I decided to vanish
and become a doctor.
Help people and slowly work
off some fraction of the debt.
Now get out.
I'm a ranking State Alchemist.
I have a right to that research
and anything else you know.
You're way too small
for these concerns.
I bet you were blinded
by the abundant privileges.
Access to research and prestige.
So you joined their ranks.
A foolish mistake.
If you'd been there during the
rebellion you'd feel the same way.
I know that.
I know what we're
doing is stupid, okay?
It's not your problem.
Dr. Marcoh.
About five years ago you
treated some babies in Xenotime.
I just want you to
know they're fine now.
The red water's gone.
Brother, what are you doing?
Guesswork.
Don't need circles.
Is this the red water
from Xenotime?
No, it looks a lot clearer.
Stop!
Brother!
Get off of me!
This is wrong!
He's onto something!
Ed!
Let go!
It's not really liquid.
No, it's not.
It looks more like that
ring the priest in Lior had.
The Sage's Stone.
The Celestial Stone.
The Great Elixir.
The Red Tincture.
The Next Element.
Did you really think a substance of so
many names would be limited to just the
form of a stone?
Brig...
Brigadier Grand.
Brigadier, Basque?
Well, you've wormed your way up.
You're damn right,
Crystal Alchemist.
And now you'll turn the Philosopher's
Stone and your research over to me.
The Philosopher's Stone?
That thing?
An experimental leap
at best, roulette at worst.
You never know when it will
reach its limit and backfire.
An unstable, destructive product,
different from the true Stone.
But during the Rebellion, it did augment our
abilities and make us tremendously powerful.
You're saying the military
hasn't just looked for the Stone?
In the past, it's
worked to develop it?
Never mind that
it isn't perfect.
It was made by human
hands and it worked!
That proves the
concept is possible.
The Philosopher's
Stone's not a myth.
Where're the design specs?
And what do you mean to
do with it when you see it?
Increase your
meddling, Fullmetal?
This research is top secret
and falls under my jurisdiction.
I can't permit you access to it.
Let's go.
No, let go of me!
Please!
I'm sorry I ran!
Have mercy!
You can't take me back.
I can't go back to that place.
It's too much.
I can't take it.
The testing, the experiments--
My hands are already stained!
Please!
This is just like before.
Brother!
Maybe I haven't grown
an inch since then.
But I can't let my heart stay...
Stunted too!
[The car brakes]
[It's deconstructed]
Who is that?
Finally, the
Ironblood alchemist.
Basque Grand.
Your timing's too bad.
Just as I got my hands on this.
Get away!
That face...
That's the guy I saw in
Central three years ago.
I'm sure of it.
But never mind that.
This is messed up.
My mind's telling me to run.
But my legs are frozen stiff.
Crystal alchemist Dr. Marcoh.
I heard you were dead.
I'll have to take special care.
To wash you out of this world.
For your transgressions.
I see.
Yes, go ahead.
How can I protest?
In the name of the
Great Almighty One.
Thou shalt perish.
It's okay.
Leave me behind.
You've really got to
work on that attitude!
Fullmetal Alchemist
Edward Elric.
You won't escape either!
He knows my name too?
What's going on here?
What have I ever
done to make enemies?
Okay, bad question.
But nothing bad
enough to kill me over!
Brother, this way.
Come on!
Who in the hell are you?
What are you
coming after us for?
If you're the creators of this
society, there must also be destroyers.
You can't understand.
Please, Ed, leave me and run.
You have a kind
look in your eyes.
My older brother's
were exactly the same.
Eyes that were strong and peered into the
endless distance as if seeing something we
could not.
It was three years ago, yes.
I was glad to hear you'd given up being a
State Alchemist so I could take you off my
list.
But now... Yeah,
now..too bad, isn't it?
Too slow.
Brother!
Al!
Don't mistake your fortune.
That alchemy was
designed for human flesh.
That's why you
escaped with only a dent.
This time.
Stay out of this!
My only enemies are State Alchemists
and those who stand between.
But why?
Why are you after us?
Alchemists are those who take things
away from their natural form and convert them
into something grotesque.
In hubris, they profane God, Creator of
All, claiming that they have a better design.
I come as a right hand, an agent
of God, to carry out His judgments.
I'm an alchemist too.
I may not have a State certification,
but-- Why do you seek death?
I don't.
But you mentioned you had
an older brother, didn't you?
Then you should understand why I can't
just sit by and watch my brother get killed.
Even you should-- I do.
I understand exactly how it feels to watch
your brother murdered before your eyes when
you can't do a thing.
In fact, maybe...
I'll show Ed!
I told you, you're too slow.
Automail.
So, your right arm begets
nothing but destruction also.
Don't you start with that.
We're nothing alike, pal.
That State Alchemist?
What's he doing here?
You've come for Dr. Marcoh?
I'm sorry I'm late.
The Lieutenant-Colonel ordered
me to tail you as protection.
What?
You mean Hughes did?
I heard you on my way in here.
You say you're an agent of God.
Well, then why don't you
try passing judgment on me?
That's Alex Louis Armstrong,
the Strong-Arm Alchemist!
What a righteous
day this is turning into.
That you would come here and
save me the tribulations of finding you.
Blessed God, full of Grace...
Don't pray just yet.
You're facing the technique that's
been passed down the Armstrong line for
generations.
That's hardly a blessing!
Next shot!
As you can see, it's
only children here.
I doubt the gorillas you're
looking for are four feet tall.
Does this mean you've abandoned the
so-called teachings of your little priest?
All right, then.
Tell us where the rebel faction is,
that's resisting the military governance.
Why should I?
We came to liberate this
town from that tyrant, Cornello.
We're trying to help you.
What are you, blind?
You're not
interested in helping.
You're here for control.
This is our village, not yours.
We're the only ones
who can make it better.
We'll fix it ourselves.
We've got legs.
We'll get up and use them!
You dropped this.
But isn't this
what you're after?
Didn't you think about
taking it yourself and leaving?
Of course.
And a younger me would have walked
away with it without a second thought.
But I can't forget the faces of
all those people we saw today.
And you used that in
their treatments, right?
That Stone belongs to them.
And so do you.
You ready?
Then let's head out.
We've got to find someplace where
the military and that killer won't find us.
You think we could escape?
You've got legs, don't you?
Let's put 'em to work.
Fullmetal Alchemist Episode
15: The Ishbal Massacre.
We didn't know anything about the
bloodshed, but you can't use ignorance
to escape responsibility.
Not with him.