This is Resembool?
Somehow I guess I was
expecting something different.
Sorry if it's too
rural for your tastes.
Is he still looking?
uhh, no.
I don't think so.
He was staring at me
the whole train ride.
He couldn't keep
his eyes off me.
You know what they say.
Beauty is an absolute curse.
Excuse me, but aren't you...
You're not Sarah, are you?
You've really grown up.
Sorry!
You're mistaken!
What a creep.
Pretending to know me like that.
Sarah.
Wait a sec.
That was my mother's name.
It's cruel to lie to an
old woman like that.
I thought you were in
Rush Valley studying.
And now you tell me
you've been in Central.
Sorry, Grandma.
I didn't mean to lie, but I've
been taking care of Ed and Al.
I'm sure you were.
But if that's the case, why didn't
you drag them back home with you?
Well, uh... Hey!
I almost forgot.
I met an old friend of
yours in Rush Valley.
Isn't that neat?
If somebody asks,
we're not here.
You never saw us.
Good grief.
Just a minute.
He must have followed us here.
You came back.
Sorry, Pinako.
I seem to be having some
trouble finding my old house.
I suppose you realize a lot
has changed since you left.
Wait, Grandma.
You know who this man is?
You were young.
I'm not surprised you
don't remember him.
Say hello to Ed and
Al's father, Winry.
Winry.
Yes, of course that's your name.
Sorry about the whole mix-up.
It's just been so long,
I guess I got confused.
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain something of
equal value must be lost.
That is Alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
How'd you get so fast?
Can't we slow down for a bit?
My body feels so
light for some reason.
But we can rest for
a while if you're tired.
I've been thinking about
what you said earlier.
It really explains a few things.
You mean Führer Bradley?
And your leader...
the Führer Hes a....
Homunculus!
The Military's actions make more
sense with a Homunculus calling the shots.
And he couldn't do that
just by impersonating him.
Besides, I had a run-in
with the Führer's secretary.
The one who's
always by his side.
She's a Homunculus too.
Brother, you know
what that means.
Drop it.
But teacher told us a Homunculus is born
when someone fails a human transmutation.
I said drop it, Al!
Al...
What was that place?
The giant gate.
I... I suddenly remember
seeing it before.
It felt... it felt
like the truth.
According to teacher, it's not.
Forget about it, Al.
But how did we summon it?
All we did was touch.
I'm an Alchemist.
Maybe I just subconsciously
activated the stone somehow.
I can't say for sure.
You don't really think I've been turned
into the Philosopher's Stone, do you?
Really?
The stone is this legendary thing,
with supposedly unlimited power.
How could that be me?
Nothing's impossible, Al.
We don't know what we're dealing
with, and we don't know how it works yet.
You should try not to
touch me for the time being.
But... but why?
If we come into contact again,
we could use the stone's power.
And if you're the stone, what
happens when your power's gone?
I could lose you, and I'm
not gonna take that risk.
So what are we doing now?
We're going to Resembool.
That's the first place
the state will look for us.
I know, but those Homunculi are
a bigger problem for us right now.
And if we're gonna fight them,
there's something I need first.
I've talked with some
of the soldiers, sir.
They say Kimbley was found
dead before the red light appeared.
Apparently Scar was the one who killed
him, and Archer ordered a full assault.
The civilians seem to have fled
before the Military invasion, Colonel.
The entire city was empty
when the troops arrived.
We found the secret
passage out of Lior.
We've sent a
squad to investigate.
The military's
assumptions were wrong.
They never planned to resist.
That was Scar's plan all along.
He lured us here to use our
soldiers as ingredients for his Alchemy.
The Elric brothers
are still alive.
Several soldiers spotted them on the outskirts
of town, but their current location is unknown.
They were last seen over
an hour ago, leaving the area.
That's all we know.
You don't think the Elrics would
have condoned this, do you?
Considering Ed's warning, I don't
think he was part of Scar's plan.
Not intentionally, anyway.
Colonel.
So far, we have 28 confirmed dead
and 67 injured, including five officers.
There's another
900 still missing.
I assure you, we won't rest until
we've gotten to the bottom of this.
And that is clearly not going to
happen until you find the one responsible.
Scar.
I know, sir.
No Mustang.
I mean Fullmetal.
Can you tell me why the Elric
brothers showed up in Lior?
We believe they were
in pursuit of Scar, sir.
And why would they
have been doing that?
Have they been given
orders to capture him?
Not directly.
They were given orders to conduct an
Alchemy investigation on a large scale.
So acting on their own, these skilled
Alchemists meet up with a fugitive in a war zone.
Resulting in an alchemic explosion that
takes the lives of countless numbers of soldiers.
You're going to put a noose around their necks
already before we even know what happened?
I believe we should give them a chance
to explain their actions themselves, sir.
An official interrogation,
Colonel Mustang?
Very well.
But I should warn you that if you let those suspects
get away from us, you'll be doing the explaining to me.
Go.
Ensure their success.
I've heard some very
disturbing reports.
According to my information, the Elric
brothers may be fighting alongside those
who call themselves Homunculi.
Capture them, Mustang.
If they won't go peacefully,
then take them out by force.
You're to consider
them enemy combatants.
Colonel... You heard
what the man said.
I want a report on all sightings of
the Elrics at the time of the incident.
I can't believe we're
hunting down Ed.
It's messed up.
Those are the orders, Fury.
But Scar's to blame
for this, not the Elrics.
And what about that
rampage that Archer went on?
If anyone should be under
investigation, it's that creep.
It is suspicious that they ran away, and if
we don't find them, the Colonel gets punished.
Did he really mean we should
kill them if they don't surrender?
Shall we get started, Colonel?
Yes.
You spent the
night out here again?
Thanks for waking me.
I could have slept all day.
I've been losing track of time.
Tell me, when did Trisha die?
It's been six long years.
I see.
The boys must have
been torn up over their loss.
My God, I've done it twice.
I was thinking you
were Sarah again.
You must have been
good friends with her.
I guess memories don't age.
Sara was my mom,
and a great one at that.
So much pain.
All because of that damn war.
I can't imagine
what it was like there.
Supposedly my parents, they were
executed by the military they went to help.
All because they were treating the
wounded Ishbalans the same way.
How sad we are.
You can't sum this
up with one word.
It's a lot more than just sad.
When I was little, I'd imagine the
people who killed my parents as demons.
But now I know the men who
did it, and I respect him somehow.
I feel lost.
I don't know how to make
sense of all this anymore.
There's no good reason.
We're all lost.
That's why we're sad.
Winry, you're back!
Oh, I'm so glad!
I'm starving!
Ah!
Lieutenant Ross?
And don't forget Sergeant Block!
So you followed us!
I knew we saw something
we shouldn't have!
And now we're gonna
die because of it!
Oh, please spare
our lives, I beg you!
I knew I shouldn't have
gotten involved with the Military!
I should have
listened to my mom!
Would you calm down?
Hey!
Those poor boys.
I didn't know their
home was gone, too.
You said the Military
is after them now.
What are they accused of?
All that we know is an
emergency bulletin was sent out.
The Führer has ordered that he wants
the Fullmetal Alchemist and his brother
captured, even killed if that's what it
takes, saying they've been implicated in
some kind of major offensive
against the Military in Lior.
Oh, man.
What are they up to now?
A friend of ours is a
communications officer.
He told us that a special search
team is being organized under
General Hakuro's command,
and they'll probably come here.
It's safe to assume the local
police have been told to find them as well.
The next thing I know, the Lieutenant
here says we're taking a little vacation.
I thought she was romancing me.
I thought you'd be happy
to get out of the city for once.
I can't believe you did all this to
get information to a wanted criminal.
What are you saying?
Regardless of what the Führer
says, I know those two aren't traitors.
And I'll do whatever
I can to help them.
Okay, okay.
I appreciate that, but I'm not sure
if they're coming back here or not.
Hm.
I'm sure they'll come back.
They may not have a house with
four walls, but this place is
still their home, I know that.
And besides, you're here.
I can remember a time when
no railroads led to this place.
There wasn't so much as a single dirt road
connecting this tiny little village to the eastern frontier.
To get to the east, you had to traverse that
mountain, relying on the river to lead you there.
I know that stream.
We used to play
there a lot as kids.
I get it.
Etta now will have to
come that way to get here.
Thanks for the tip, old man.
Old man.
Let's go, Sheska.
You guys wait here.
If the search party gets
here, I'll try to stall them, okay?
Thanks!
But it's been over a hundred years since
the first railroad was built through here.
What's wrong?
Just get down and stay quiet.
I don't think it's worth it.
Betraying those kids
for our own careers.
We're not doing
this for us, Breda.
I know.
We're doing it for the Colonel, so
he doesn't take the blame for Lior.
Why do you think I'm
trudging through this forest?
The Colonel?
Well, if he has to go
down for this, then so be it.
Hey, Ed.
It's uh nice to see you again.
We'll have to give
the Colonel his credit.
He told us you'd take this
old shortcut to get back home.
Look, no hard feelings.
I'm not going.
Ed, please.
I'm not a military dog anymore.
Go ahead and fire.
When that bullet ricochets off my
hand, who do you think gets hurt?
Ed, please.
Don't do this.
Go ahead.
Shoot.
Stop it!
Havoc?
I'm really sorry, but I had to.
Al, now.
I'm sorry.
Stop right there, Ed!
Edward!
If you have anything you
want to say, well, listen.
We're not your enemy here.
We're trying to help you out.
To tell your side of it
all in the investigation.
This should work for now.
I wonder if the Elric brothers are actually
prepared to fight us to the end on this.
We'll know when
we reach the end.
That was pitiful.
Let's get them next time.
Colonel, would you mind
grabbing my cigarettes for me?
Get well soon, Havoc.
How much ground do you think they've
covered while we've been down, sir?
Not too much, considering
Al can't risk getting in water.
Since his blood
seal could wash off.
Stop Screaming.
I promise I have this under control.
Tell us the truth, girls.
Who tipped you off
about the Elric brothers?
Nobody.
And don't talk to us about truth, not when
you think Ed and Al could really be traitors.
We won't know that until we've
captured and questioned them.
Aren't you going to speak?
You're the one who got
them into this in the first place.
It's no use.
He doesn't care about anything except
the bars and stripes on his uniform.
Tell me, Roy.
Was this the kind of devotion you
had when you killed my mom and dad?
What?
I told you, Al.
We can't touch.
We don't know
what it could trigger.
You know running
makes you look guilty.
Ed!
Al!
Winry?
We're running because we
knew you'd come after us.
Isn't that what every dog
does when it's chased?
Yes, but a trained dog never
defies the orders of its owner.
Then I'm a stray.
Really?
Then maybe we'll
have to put you down.
Just come with us, Edward, okay?
We're not out to hurt you.
We just want to get to the
bottom of what happened in Lior.
I'll never go back there.
You'll have to kill me first.
So what?
You're going to shirk off responsibilities
and revert to a stubborn child?
Say what you want.
I'm in control now!
Good luck making sparks now.
Al!
Major.
Sir.
I used my Alchemy to transmit
the rock into a hollow projectile.
Then I heat the air inside to
explode it into a hundred daggers.
It's an effective
attack, don't you think?
Yeah, I'm sure the two of
you put it to great use in Ishbal.
What do we do?
Stop!
Please.
Just stop.
Winry?
I once executed two people.
Two doctors.
There are no sides.
Just patients.
That's what they said as they
treated our fallen enemies in Ishbal.
But the people they were healing
would just rise up again to fight us.
The Military asked them to stop.
But they wouldn't.
And their makeshift hospital was
becoming a den for insurgents.
I got my orders in the morning.
And I shot them.
That night.
Afterwards I
tried to kill myself.
But I was too much of a coward.
So I took an oath instead.
To never follow unreasonable
commands again.
To reach a position where I
wouldn't have to follow them.
And I've stayed true to that.
I'm not chasing you
because I was commanded to.
I'm doing it because I'm pissed.
Now why the hell did you two run
away without asking for my help first?!
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 44,
Hohenheim of Light.
What the hell do you
think you're doing here?
You've got some nerve showing
up again after all this time!