What's wrong?
Something on your mind?
Your reactions are
slow and clumsy.
It seems that an artificially created soul
doesn't quite measure up to the real thing.
It must be such a shock to find
out who and what you really are.
No.
You're lying.
I'm... I'm... I'm
Alphonse Elric!
Like I said, you can't
prove that, can you?
Just accept it.
You'll feel better.
If that's the truth,
then what about you?
What about you?
You have memories
from when you were alive.
And that means...
How exquisite.
The fools keep
coming, one by one.
What about me, you ask?
It's true.
It's really quite simple.
I love to tear the flesh of
the living to kill for the simple,
intoxicating pleasure of feeling
blood between my fingers.
I kill, therefore I am!
Whether I'm real or
human doesn't matter!
I'm a killer and that's
all I need to know!
You're right.
There is no need for you to prove
you exist, because very soon, you won't.
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Ah, you.
You know this guy?
No fair!
You didn't say anything about
having other allies around!
Allies?
Gotcha!
What the... how did you...
So, you're in that
pitiful body as well.
May God show you mercy
when I send you to him.
Why is that symbol
there on your arm?
Then you've seen it before?
You don't have any
idea what that is, do you?
Tell me!
If you know what
this is, tell me now!
I see.
You're just dying to
know the truth, aren't you?
Well, now... hmm, let's see.
Um... well...
I'm not going to tell you.
[Laughing]
About 130 years, I'd say.
Let me break this
down nice and simple.
You can either remain in here as lab rats, or you
can come with me to bring hell to those above us.
Your choice.
I'm only asking once!
This building is loaded with explosives
so I can bury everything anytime I want!
And now, I must
bid you both farewell.
No, wait!
If you want to know about those markings on
your arm, you'll have to come in here and find me!
He got away.
Get up.
Oh, sorry!
Where are you going?
If you're here, Fullmetal must
be somewhere inside as well.
No!
Stop!
Wait for me!
That felt just like
an earthquake.
What was it?
Good question.
It might have been one of the many bombs set
throughout this building to destroy the evidence.
With that aftershock, there's
a chance even more will go off.
I still don't know anything
about this stupid place.
I promised I would help you.
You came here to find the
secrets of the Philosopher's Stone.
I don't know very much about it, but I can
lead you to the entrance of where they keep it.
Fine, but what about
your little brother?
I mean, we can't
exactly leave him like this.
No need to worry about me.
Just finish me off.
Get it over with.
I already told you I'm
not killing anybody, period!
You're the one who
said we're human, right?
Well, in that case,
please tell me...
How am I supposed to go on
living as scattered scraps of metal?
Well, um... Don't
connect us, please!
Do you really want us to remain here,
guarding this abandoned building alone?
In this empty, lifeless
shell of a body?
But who says you
have to keep doing that?
You think we can go outside?
Do you actually believe that people
would let us roam around freely?
Wait a minute.
My brother has the
same kind of body you do.
That's why I'm here, searching
for the Philosopher's Stone.
So I can return him to normal.
If I can just find it, I can...
If we were returned to our normal
bodies, we would just be executed.
Now do you understand?
Even if we did become human, it
would only be long enough to be killed.
Or do you think they would let us,
a couple of serial killers, go free?
No, there has to
be... Listen to us.
I'm sure it seems very noble, but you
don't understand how cruel it really is.
Teasing us.
Calling us human when we
can only live in this twisted form.
Making us remember
what we've lost.
That is truly inhumane.
No!
Stop, you idiot!
What are you trying to do?
Just shut up and watch.
What are you talking about?
He's your little brother!
He was happy you
called him human.
Now he can no longer go
back to being number 48.
This is the only thing he can
do to keep his human dignity.
No, that's not true!
I can't let you do this!
Brother, I'm going on ahead.
All right.
No!
My brother, once I fulfill my
promise, I will come to join you.
What were you thinking?
What were the
two of you thinking?
It was the only
choice he could make.
I treated you as humans.
I gave him a choice
and he still chose to die.
What could I have possibly
done different to keep him alive?
That is one of the many questions
in this world that has no answer.
I'm going to return
Al back to normal.
I won't let him go
through all of this.
Let's go.
Are we really going
to release these guys?
Those were the orders.
They're supposed to be
used for military research.
They were
sentenced here for life.
Though if you ask me, they should be
put in front of a firing squad for their crimes.
What the hell was that?
That was the sound of a building
collapsing from some sort of explosion.
What a soothing sound.
That's enough, Kimblee.
It really takes me back.
Back to the time of the
Ishbal extermination.
Get out.
You've been summoned.
This is Kimblee, the
military's madman bomber.
He killed the enemy
and a handful of our own.
Such a pleasing ring in my ear.
Makes me feel all warm inside.
So much for the great legend
of the Crimson Alchemist.
You've hit rock bottom.
Now all we need is for Envy
to gather the ingredients.
This is the moment
I've been waiting for.
Lust!
What is it?
It's him, Lust.
It's him!
Him?
No, it can't be.
Not Greed.
We have to hurry.
Before our plan is interrupted.
Just checking, but we're
past all the weird traps, right?
No intruder has ever
been able to get this far.
Yeah, you mean you and your
brother killed anyone that ever tried.
So who was it who attached your
souls to that suit of armor anyway?
I thought you said we
were past all the weird traps.
This isn't a trap.
Damn it!
[High Pitched Wistling]
What happened?
The Chimera have their master.
The one who created them.
You're telling me
someone lives down here?
Someone? I think it could be
better described as something.
That's a chimera.
You mean this one
created all the others?
No.
Not all of them.
It's been a long time, Edward.
Tucker..
The Sowing Life Alchemist.
But how?
The military said
you were executed!
My brother and I were still alive in this place
even though the records say we were killed.
Why should it surprise you that
others were kept alive as chimeras?
Yeah, but that's not
what I'm talking about!
It's Nina!
Nina.
Your daughter is dead
because of what you did.
How could they
allow you to live?
I'm living for Nina.
I understand how you
must feel right now, Edward.
But please...
Let me explain.
Hey, uh, I was wondering if you could
stop hunting down my brother now.
It is the will of Ishbala.
He is a cursed alchemist.
And if that alone wasn't enough,
he seeks the Philosopher's Stone.
But why is alchemy so bad?
I mean, you use it.
Your right arm has a transmutation circle
on it, though I've never seen one like it before.
That is the brand I received
when I accepted my calling.
To kill all state alchemists.
And as for the
Philosopher's Stone...
He's not looking for
it to use as a weapon.
He wants to use it to
return me to my body.
You don't know the horror
of the Philosopher's Stone.
But we do!
Legend says that those who get
too close to the stone will perish, right?
But if we were afraid,
we'd never learn anything!
Now that I think about
it, I heard that Ishbal was
destroyed because someone
got too close to the stone.
Lies!
Ishbal didn't perish because
of the evil of the stone!
It was destroyed by another!
Brother!
Open this door!
Talk to me!
Brother!
Brother, is it true?
Are you trying to use alchemy?
I failed.
It cannot be done this way.
But maybe if I just had
the Philosopher's Stone...
No!
Alchemy is the practice of heretics
that distorts the world God's given us!
You know that!
But... God won't help
us now, my brother.
Ishbala won't bring her back.
Brother!
We're doomed!
They're coming!
Quick, brother!
The military!
They're...
Brother?
I can finally see
it clearly now.
I know what the
Philosopher's Stone actually is.
And I understand why our God,
Ishbala, forbids us from pursuing it.
It's so clear.
Please, brother!
The military's on its way!
The enemy is trying to destroy us by
using the power of the Devil's Arts against us!
Yes, it's true.
Ishbal shall perish.
But that is something
that has been preordained.
It is destiny.
In my soul, I honestly believe that if I had the
Philosopher's Stone, she'd come back to me.
And that Ishbal and all of
his people would be set free.
But no.
To bring her back,
Ishbal must be destroyed.
You can't say that!
Brother!
Brother!!!
Scar.
We've heard the Philosopher's Stone could
be made from the flesh and blood of humans.
We came here to find the
truth, because we need to know.
If it really is true, then
we'll... My, my, my.
This day is just filling up with all
sorts of unpleasant interruptions.
Who are they?
You again.
This time you're going to tell
me why you have that face.
My brother's work.
Did he succeed in
bringing you back?
What are you talking about?
Can I eat them now?
I don't know.
I think the armored one
might give you indigestion.
I still want to try.
The homunculi.
Homunculi?
They couldn't be...
So the military staged your execution
and then sent you here to make chimeras.
Is that it?
Not just chimeras, Edward.
I have several research projects in the
works, none of which can ever be made public.
You can understand.
There's still something
you're not telling me.
You've changed into a chimera, but you're
not like the rest of those beasts back there.
You've kept all your intelligence from
when you were human, and you're stable.
Something you
couldn't do before.
What alchemist
has that kind of skill?
Dr. Marcoh?
Basque Grand?
Or is it someone else?
Answer me, Tucker.
Who the hell's
running this place?
Please don't look at her head.
She's extremely bashful.
Nina.....
She's not yet able to keep her form
when she's exposed to the open air.
You still can't find a way to perform a
human transmutation and bring her back.
So you've created a chimera
that looks like her, is that it?
I tried and failed many times, and
in the end I wound up in this form.
But I'm... I'm almost there.
Almost.
You mean it's possible?
That's the same
stuff that Marcoh had.
This is the incomplete
philosopher's stone.
Yes, it's incomplete, but
it's still extremely powerful.
You've seen it used before.
If this amount of unfinished
material could be carefully
refined, you could make
a true philosopher's stone.
This is what you've
been looking for, Edward.
Many have tried, but no one
has ever succeeded before.
It's an impossible task
for any ordinary alchemist.
Yeah, you're right.
But you see...
I'm no ordinary alchemist.
Full Metal Alchemist.
Episode 22, Created Human.
Homunculi.
False humans created
through alchemy.
But they're only a
legend, aren't they?