Come on. EEEEEE!
I'll take the chrome steel spanner set,
this hydraulic torque wrench, and can I
take a look at that micrometer,
please?
Sure!
Oh, and please throw in whichever ultra
-hardtip drill bit you think is the best!
You got it!
It's everything that I dreamed it would
be.
Central sure puts her small-town selection
to shame.
And I just can't get over how good the walnut
handle on the screwdriver feels on my skin!
Are you almost done in there, Woodry?
Don't you think you have enough souvenirs
for one trip?
What?
But you told me you'd buy me anything I
wanted today!
Isn't that right, Ed?
Yeah.
I love these high-carbon chrome steel
cutting shears!
They'll cut through anything and never
rust!
Can I have these, too?
Sure.
Sir, could you add this sewing machine oil
to my tab?
Of course!
Here.
This is for you.
Without me around, you'll have to take
care of your own auto-mail.
Mr. Elric.
Mustang wants to see you.
There's a mission for me?
Yeah.
Now that you're a real estate alchemist, you
have to be ready to leave at a moment's notice.
It's our life.
Second Lieutenant Hawkeye?
Yes, sir.
Here are your orders and case file.
Full Metal Alchemist Edward Elric.
You are hereby ordered to inspect the coal
mine at Youswell.
Is this kind of thing really a job for a
state alchemist?
It entails inspecting the mine resources.
As an alchemist, you do have knowledge of
minerals, don't you?
As it's your first mission, I've decided
to keep the training wheels on.
But that won't mean that you can take it
easy.
Humankind cannot gain anything without
first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of equal value must
be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed that to
be the world's one and only truth.
It feels like we've got our own private
car, huh?
I like traveling by train.
You can just sit and watch the world go by
outside.
Al?
Hm?
I have to do this now that the state has
me on a leash.
But there's no reason you should suffer,
too.
We're brothers.
If we don't help each other, no one will.
You're line's, remember?
So, when can we expect to see you back
home?
We're not going back.
Ed...
Winry, there's no home left for us to
return to.
You're right.
Huh?
Look!
I think I can see it!
So that's the last town to the east.
Youswell.
It's supposed to be a coal mining town,
but it looks more like a ghost town to me.
Everyone here looks so worn down.
It doesn't look like there's going to be
much to do here.
Let's hurry and finish so we can blow this
ho-Hm?
Sorry.
Wait, are you guys tourists?
Where are you from?
Have you eaten?
Where are you staying?
Hell of a welcoming committee.
Pop!
We got visitors!
What are you going on about?
Over here!
Big Spenders!
Big Spenders?
Hey, my name is Holling.
I run the local inn.
We'll take good care of you.
So, what do you think?
I know it's not much, but since the coal
mine's wages are so low, at least with
this place, I can keep two irons in the
fire.
Now that'll be a room for two for one
night.
And what are your rates?
Well, they ain't cheap.
I'm sure we can cope.
Despite our appearances, we've got plenty
of cash.
$200,000.
What?
$200,000?
That's ridiculous!
You gotta put gold bars on our pillows?
It's a fair price, seeing how ours is the
finest inn in all of Youswell.
Not to mention it's the only one.
We ain't had any guests in some time, so
we've got to milk you folks for all you're worth.
It's not even close to enough.
We spent all that money on Winry.
Guess we go to Plan B.
Wow!
He fixed it!
It looks as good as new!
Come on!
What else needs fixing?
Well, if it's not too much trouble.
This is special to me, but it's broken.
You still haven't thrown out that old
piece of junk?
Maybe if you bought us some nice things
once in a while.
Here, I'll take care of that.
Thank you... so much.
Hey, that looks pretty nice!
Who'd have thought that our first tourist
in ages would be a real-life alchemist?
I took a crack at alchemy myself once,
but never went anywhere with it.
Hey!
So, what brings you to Youswelll?
There's not much here for someone like
you.
It's business.
In fact, I've come here to inspect the
coal mine.
Inspect?
Then you're a part of the military?
Well, yeah.
I'm a state alchemist.
Cool, huh?
Hey!
What was that for?
We have no food or beds to offer any dogs
of the military.
You one of them, too?
Well, no, not... He's
got nothing to do with it!
I just met him on the train, on the way
here!
Fine, then.
You can sleep on the street like the rest
of the dogs.
Your dad sure feels strongly about it.
Of course he does.
Everyone around here hates the stupid
army.
And that greedy sucker Yoki who's in
charge of this place is the worst of all of them.
Yoki?
And now he's got that sneaky little state
alchemist to do all his dirty work.
Alchemist, be thou for the people.
That's their crock of a slogan.
But the only people they care about are
their own damned selves.
But, sir... There's self-righteous
thugs who sell their soul to the state.
Moon, old pal, I'm so hungry.
I wish you were cheese.
Ah, winry.
If only you'd think about my human parts
instead of my metal ones now and then.
She does think about your human side.
I snuck this out for you.
Al.
After all, I can't eat it.
They really do hate the military here.
Yeah, I'll watch that from now on.
Maybe I should enlist, too.
And become a state alchemist alongside
you.
Are you nuts?
It's bad enough that one of us has to play
their silly games.
Having another lightning rod won't make
this any easier, Al.
But, brother... Step aside!
Your inn is as charmingly filthy as ever,
Harling.
Lieutenant Yoki, you know you should cover
up your face more often.
It's a good look for you.
Enough small talk.
The taxes on this place are long past due,
and it's not just you, Harling.
I could say the same for the whole town.
Our wages are too low to afford tax,
sir.
You're paid so little because that's what
you men are worth.
What?
You know you can't just lower our wages
and then turn around and raise our taxes
and expect us to... The state has given Lieutenant
Yoki unilateral authority over this mine.
Shut up!
He only got to where he is by taking the
money we sweat and bled for and using it
to bribe the higher-ups!
Hmph.
If you've got all this figured out,
then perhaps you should try bribing me.
But don't blame me, because you have to
grease the wheels.
It's the way of the world.
Yeah, and sometimes the way of the world
is the little man gets beat!
Nicely done, Lira.
It seems the rumors of this establishment
becoming a hangout for rebels,
toughs, and thugs are true.
I may have no choice but to suspend your
operating license.
What?
No, you can't!
You brat!
Oh, Kyle!
Don't kill him.
We just want him to be an example.
Please, no!
Who the hell are you?
When I heard the lieutenant would be
dropping in, I thought I'd come by and say hello.
Is that what I... Who does
this kid think he is, sir?
You moron!
That watch makes him a state alchemist,
which means he reports directly to King Bradley!
How terribly rude of my subordinate.
Please forgive his idiocy.
I'm Lieutenant Yoki, the man in charge
here.
So, what business might you have in our
humble little burg?
I'm just here to conduct an inspection.
An inspection?
Marvelous!
But you must come stay at my mansion.
I hope you haven't had to mingle with
these unwashed masses for too long.
Loathsome dogs.
Congratulations, Mustang.
I hear you're being promoted to a full
colonel soon.
And Hawkeye, you'll be bumped up to first
lieutenant.
Thank you, General Hikuro, sir.
Once the promotions go through, I'd like you to
supervise the Eastern Command Center for a while.
I think you'd do well there.
You're demoting me already?
I can see how having someone like me around
Central would... What are you talking about?
This isn't a demotion.
It's a transfer, Colonel Mustang.
But watch your back there, because I hear
our people in the Eastern Division...
are less than upstanding.
It's such a great honor for me to be
hosting a genuine state alchemist
such as yourself in my home.
And since we are so blessed as to have
such a talented scientist in our midst,
you should have him take a look at your
alchemic attempts, Lyra.
Yes.
Nah, I already saw.
She liquefied the air around her,
reduced its volume, and then
vaporized it, producing a shockwave.
The light came from the heat generated by the
forced compression, needed to maintain entropy.
You could deduce all that by just looking
at it?
Actually, my ultimate goal is to become a
state alchemist.
To be just like you, Mr. Elric.
To be like me?
Yes.
I wish nothing more than to do all that I
can do for the state.
And now, bon appetit.
You'll need strength for the work ahead.
I do hope that our provincial cuisine
suits your refined tastes.
You eat pretty well, considering the
economic conditions of this town.
Times are tough for all of us.
I tell you, I've had plenty of trouble
collecting taxes.
And those miners can be so brutishly
obstinate sometimes as you saw.
And by obstinate, you mean asserting their rights
and refusing to pay you more than they earn.
See?
You get it.
I knew you were a man of great
understanding.
To understand the world, we have only to
follow one basic principle.
Equivalent exchange.
The founding law of alchemy.
You can't get without giving.
Right?
Absolutely.
Eloquently put.
I myself have long conducted business
under a similar guiding principle,
in the spirit of which...
Lira?
Please accept this small token of my
appreciation.
This supposed to be some kind of a bribe,
Yoki?
That is such an ugly word.
Why don't we just call it equivalent
exchange?
Now then, there is the matter of your
inspection.
Yeah, I get your drift.
I knew you would.
You are truly a man of great
understanding.
Oh, and I have a feeling the townspeople
will start behaving themselves very shortly.
I hope Ed is doing all right on his own.
Hey, what's going on?
Kyle Kyle!
My God. My son's still in there!
You can't, boss!
It's too dangerous now!
We'll lose you both!
I don't care!
Let me go!
Kyle!
Come on, Kyle.
Where are you?
Kyle!
Dad!
I'm here.
Is this Yoki's doing?
Mm-hmm.
You're some kind of super alchemist,
right?
So, can't you just make some gold?
For my dad?
You could save the whole town.
I can't.
Why not?
It won't cost you nothing.
You're wrong.
The whole world is equivalent exchange.
I give you gold, and I'd have to pay the
price.
And I've got no reason to do that.
So we have to bribe you now, too?
And you call yourself an alchemist?
Alchemist be thou for the people.
What a load that is.
Transmuting gold's a serious offense.
If I'm caught, they'll not only strip me
of my state alchemist certification,
but they'll throw me in jail.
Then do it so you don't get caught!
Even if I could.
It'd just get taken away in taxes.
If it's that awful here, why don't you all just
saddle up and move on to another village?
Kid.
Huh?
This may not make a lot of sense to you.
But this place?
Well, it's both our home and our coffin.
Home and coffin.
That's got a nice ring.
What are you doing?
Al, we burned our home to the ground on
purpose.
We've got nowhere to go back to,
and that's fine.
Because we chose it.
But... I don't know.
Maybe equivalent exchange goes further
than we thought.
Al, what you're about to see stays just
between us.
You want to buy the Youswelll coal mine?
That's right, and while you're here I'd
like you to throw in everything from the
trade route to the town itself.
Okay?
Well, I'm afraid even for a state alchemist
like yourself, the mine just isn't for sale.
Oh, that's too bad.
In here we lugged all this in for nothing.
Huh?!
Is... Is that...?
Real gold?
Turns out the mine's full of unexploited
minerals that'd be a real booster shot for
alchemic research.
And I'd hate to miss out, but if it's not
on the market...
Don't be absurd.
Although, the mine was entrusted to me by
my state to govern.
Selling it for my own personal profit might
appear to some observers too, uh... Right.
Don't worry, none of this gold appears on
any of the books.
So as long as we both keep our mouths
shut, no one has to know anything about it.
But still... Hmm... I've got it.
What if you write up an official deed
stating you hand over all rights to the
mine to me, free of charge?
Then you can take all of this as an
unrelated gift.
Lieutenant.
Why?
Why can't I fight?
Because I can't risk losing you again,
son.
But they smashed our inn.
We have to make them pay for that.
It's just a building, Kyle.
Nothing that's worth dying for.
Hi!
So, let's see if I can't turn those frowns
upside down.
You leech!
What do you want now?
Come on!
Is that any way to talk to your new boss,
landlord, and all-around overseer?
Overseer?
What the hell are... As you can see, I hold in
my hand the title deed to the mine, trade routes,
and the entire town of Youswelll.
What?
In other words, pretty much everything
around here belongs to me now.
You follow?
However, I have to be getting back to my
busy life in Central.
I'm not even sure this is worth carrying
to the city with me.
It's so...
So heavy.
So, you're going to try and sell it back
to us for a profit?
You bet.
And it ain't going to be cheap,
to use your phrase.
You remember equivalent exchange,
don't you?
Hmm.
After all, not only is this deed written
on high-grade parchment, it's got gold
leaf trim on the edges.
It comes in a box decorated with finely
crushed Jade in a nonchalant, yet at the
same time luxurious, design.
Oh, yeah, this is craftsmanship.
And the key's sterling silver.
See, I'd say it's got to be worth a round,
too, if it's worth $200,000.
$200,000?
For the deed to use?
Well, that's all.
Really?
You know, now that I think about it,
a room at the inn costs $200,000.
I'll spend the night and let's call it
even.
Huh.
Equivalent exchange.
But our inn was destroyed last night.
Hmm.
Really?
Then what's that over there?
It's new again.
Like magic, but real.
So this should cover my stay here,
right?
Huh.
Yes, of course, Ed.
Good.
It's an even trade.
Elric!
What's the meaning of this?
All of a sudden, the gold bars you gave me
turned to stone!
Gold bars?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Don't toy with me!
I traded you that deed in exchange for a
mountain of gold bars!
No, I'm pretty sure you handed it over to
me free of charge, didn't you?
At least that's what it says in the
letter.
Oh.
No!
You swindled me, you little...
That's such an ugly word.
Why don't we call it a gift from you to
me?
The transaction's invalid!
Lira!
Alchemist, be thou for the people.
That's our motto.
If you really want to be like me,
you'll take that to heart.
But you are an alchemist of the state.
How can you defy the military you serve?
Because I never sold my soul to them.
You cursed boy!
Seize the deed from...
Sorry, sir.
Now we're gonna do to you physically what
you've been doing to us financially for years!
Never underestimate the strength of a coal
mining man, Lieutenant.
You know, honey, I think our inn's even
nicer than before.
Uh-huh.
I think so, too.
All thanks to Ed Elric, the Fullmetal
Alchemist.
Here's the report from Edward Elric sir.
Great.
Thanks to the incident there, the state
has decided to reorganize the personnel at
the Eastern Command Center, who oversaw
the coal mine.
Really?
That should make our jobs a little easier
when we head east.
It's almost as though Elric did you and I
a favor by going there.
Don't tell me you planned this from the
start, sir.
Come on.
You think I know everything?
I wonder how pretty the women out east
are.
As for Elric, it seems his reputation is
already spreading throughout the region.
They're saying there's a champion of the
people among the military dogs.
Edward Elric?
Yeah, I heard of him.
So, what do you know about the guy?
Well, what they say is that even though
he's one of them state alchemist guys,
he's still a friend of the common man.
Wow, he must be a man of great stature,
then, huh?
Actually, I hear he's surprisingly short,
like a dwarf or something.
Who are you calling for?
Stop that, brother.
Get back here.
Say that to my face.
Brother, if you keep scaring away cab
drivers, we'll never reach Lior.
Full Metal Alchemist Episode 10.
The Phantom Thief.
Isn't it funny, brother?
How sometimes you can look at someone Can
you look at someone and not know whether
they're good or bad?