Something wrong?
I was just hoping that
the others got away safely.
Throughout the East, there are many
towns of diversified cultures to blend in with.
I'm sure they headed there.
You, however, are considered
responsible for the revolt in Lior.
They'll be looking for you.
It... It looks like a
temple of our god, Leto.
It belongs to a far
more ancient religion.
One that was abandoned long ago.
They recognized only one god,
banning all other beliefs as heresy.
It seems they had
quite a following.
Because of their intolerance,
a great many people died.
How terrible.
Religion exists to save us.
That's what happens when
people try to become god.
Hush.
Hush now, my darling.
We're fine.
Don't worry.
Why did you let those two go?
I believe taking care of those two
brothers was your duty now, wasn't it, sloth?
Yours and Wrath's, that is.
Don't worry, I will.
But we didn't go against the
direct orders of our master.
I thought that you of all people
would understand my reasons.
I do understand.
You wish to be human.
You think you're the only one?
We were all born
with that goal in mind.
They have arrived.
The Philosopher's Stone.
Those who possess it, no longer bound by
the laws of equivalent exchange in alchemy.
They gain without sacrifice.
Create without equal exchange.
We searched for
it, and we found it.
Now why the hell did you two run
away without asking for my help first?
Tell us, boys, please.
What happened?
Führer King Bradley
is a Homunculus.
When you say the word Homunculus,
you mean an artificial human?
Yes.
They're after the
Philosopher's Stone.
And they're pulling all
the strings in the Military.
That can't be true.
The Führer had no idea about the
experiments going on in Laboratory Five.
The Military was being
infiltrated without his knowledge.
He had the Mark
of the Ouroboros.
I saw it myself.
What else do you
think that could mean?
You told us about a Homunculus
with the ability to shapeshift.
The Führer's secretary
is Homunculus, too.
I thought she was an alien.
If that's true, and the Führer and Ms.
Douglas are Homunculi inside the Military,
what purpose do they serve?
What is it they hope to gain?
Do you want me to
keep them busy, sir?
Take them back home?
Not through Lior.
I could produce false information to
keep attention away from Central for a while.
Do it.
Catch up later.
You'll go to Resembool?
Men, our mission is complete.
We can return with
our heads held high.
But aren't you supposed to
keep an eye on the Colonel?
Do you doubt the integrity of a
man whose muscles can do this?
No, Major.
That's not it.
I'll show you what they can do!
Breda, is Havok okay?
Uh-uh.
He's gone.
Sent back before us with fury.
I'm glad.
I didn't mean to hurt him.
Ed, where's your watch?
I see.
So you've already taken
off your pocket watch.
You must have really meant what
you said about retiring from the Military.
I didn't take it off
to prove a point.
Archer took it from me,
and I never got it back.
What?
But we told Al to
give it back to you.
I'm sorry, brother.
It's gone.
You lost it?
No, I didn't lose it.
See?
Kimbley threw it at Scar, and then
all the red stones fell out of it.
And Scar's arm absorbed it.
There was nothing I could do.
And why were there red stones
inside my state-issued watch, Al?
It's Archer.
He uses that trick to create
more alchemy-amplifying devices.
What?
When we were crushing the Ishbalan
Rebellion, Grand ordered us to do the same thing.
Wait a minute, Colonel.
You're saying that even though you
knew the Military had made a partial
Philosopher's Stone, you waited
until now to tell me about it?
I thought Dr. Marcoh had run
away and put a stop to the research.
I had no way of knowing they were
using human beings to... I don't trust you.
Brother!
You knew what it
took to make one.
And still... Stop it, brother!
You let me search
for that damn thing?
That's enough!
Brother!
Ah!
Al!
He can't go in the water.
Al!!
Al!!!!
Right here!
Brother look, I can swim!
I can swim!
You idiot!
I thought that blood seal of yours would
wash away if you ever let it get too wet.
Yeah.
Looks like we don't have
to worry about that anymore.
I guess it's cause of the
Philosopher's Stone, huh?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Okay.
I get it!
Put it back on!
What's that?
That glowing...
Oh!
Nothing!
Alphonse, what's because
of the Philosopher's Stone?
Ah, nothing!
Just a little inside joke.
Okay, let's go!
Brother!
Wait for me!
Wow, looks like the Military
hasn't arrived just yet.
Wait a minute.
That's Sergeant Bloch.
Is he...
No! No! No! No!
He's not after Ed and Al!
He's okay, I promise!
Sergeant Bloch!
Hey, what's the matter with you?
Lieutenant Ross!
A long time ago I saw an eagle
with wings as black as obsidian.
Your hair is the
exact same color.
I never thought
I'd see it again.
Thank you for bringing such a
beautiful memory back to me.
And thank you.
What a lovely thing to say.
See, she's falling for
it, hook, line and sinker!
Don't we have
bigger concerns now?
Bigger than love?
There's something
about that guy.
He seems familiar,
doesn't he, brother?
Brother?
What the hell are
you doing flirting?
Edward, what the...
You're gone for over ten years
and I come back home to that?
Damn you, old man!
Dad?
I remember him
from the pictures.
Dad!
He's home!
Dad's home!
I..I know you might not be able to tell
who I am because of the way I look, but...
Alphonse, you've certainly got tall.
How did you know it was me?
Edward...
So, do you still
hate drinking milk?
Who are you calling a micro sized half pint
who didn't grow up because he doesn't drink milk?
That's not what he said, Edward.
Are you still mad, Edward?
Who ever said I was mad?
There's nothing to be mad about.
I was just having a polite
conversation with that man, nothing else.
Is that clear?
You sure look like
you were enjoying it.
Oh, it was just the
Cologne he was wearing.
You never smell anything
like that in the Military.
No soldier I know
ever wears Cologne.
Maybe the soldiers you know don't
want to smell like flowery sissy boys.
And just what's the
matter with you anyway?
I hate his smell.
I still remember it from
when I was a little kid.
When Al was born, Dad left the
house to do some kind of research.
At least that's what Mom said.
But we never got any letters.
So eventually I caught on.
I could still smell that scent all
over the house when he was gone.
It never completely went away.
It's funny.
When I saw Lyra in
Lior, I smelled it again.
You saw Lyra in Lior?
So she got out of
Dante's place safely.
That's great.
Hey!
Hold on a minute.
Who is Lyra?
And how do you two know her?
You can't keep
talking around us.
- I'm sorry.
Why do you have to know everything?
Don't get mad at me. I'm just
tired of being kept in the dark.
- I'm so sorry.
Can you guys just stop yelling.
Come on!
You always do this to me.
You never tell me anything.
The Führer has been
accused of treason.
Your children have as well.
But honestly, I'm more interested
in discussing the pictures I've seen of you.
When a Homunculus is born,
it doesn't have a human shape.
It never would if left alone.
The only way for them to obtain one is to be
fed sufficient amounts of a vital energy source.
Shards of the stone.
You mean they have
to feed on human lives?
They may start out like innocent children, but
in time their desires and powers corrupt them.
You can't trust anyone
who lives that long.
No one.
It's important you
remember that fact.
Right.
I'll keep that in mind.
You said stone fragments
were created in Laboratory Five.
Homunculi can't perform alchemy,
yet how are they able to teach it?
And what purpose
would it serve them?
There's someone else.
Someone who's
controlling all their actions.
Oh well.
Even if they are Homunculi,
this country's great.
The Military's still as honest and
powerful as it's always been, right?
I'm sure there's
nothing to worry about.
Dad?
Why is it that Homunculi
can't use alchemy?
It's because all of them
come from beyond the Gate.
But let's not talk of that.
Tell me about Trisha.
Or about you boys.
I want to know what my sons
have been up to while I was away.
Dad...
By looking at your body... I can
guess that... There's not much to tell.
We failed a transmutation
and I lost my limbs.
Al lost his body.
That's all.
But Edward... Alchemy isn't
something you can... Shut up!
You just can't show up here
and start acting like a father!
Not when we had to
watch Mom die without you.
Come on, Al.
Brother!
Brother, I'm staying with him.
But Al... Let's go, Dad.
I wonder if we'll be able to restore my
body to normal with the Philosopher's Stone.
By using the Philosopher's Stone, you'll be
able to attach your soul to someone else's body.
Someone else's?
That's not what I want.
I'm afraid your body was lost.
In accordance with
equivalent exchange.
But by sacrificing your body, you
must have gained something else.
Gained something?
What we gain is
not always wanted.
If you returned everything you made,
perhaps you could have your body back.
Then, if I could defeat
that Homunculus...
Uh, nothing, nothing!
I'm just so happy
you're home, Dad.
Oh, I have another
question for you.
Yes?
Dad?
If I'd have known he was going to leave
this early, I would have beat him up yesterday.
I'm not kidding, brother!
Let's go find him, now!
Take it from me, Al.
He's long gone by now.
Fine!
Then I'll go alone!
Wait!
Neither of you will be
leaving here for a little while.
We got a call from Sergeant
Fallman at the station.
The investigation
group has arrived.
We're going to
redirect them to Central.
You sure that's smart?
Covering for a
couple of fugitives?
I don't fully believe
your story yet, Elric.
So I intend to find out the truth about the
Führer's connection with all of this on my own.
And if you found out that
everything Edward said was true?
Well, now...
I think we should put you in the
basement until it's safe to come out of hiding.
No need for that!
You too, girl.
Brother, where do
you think Dad went?
Will you shut up about that?
What I want to know is how the Colonel is planning to
check on the truth about the Führer and that woman.
Yeah.
That secretary can't have been in the
Military for more than four years, though.
I know.
Um... if you're talking about Juliet Douglas,
she's been in the Military for almost 14 years.
That's impossible, Sheska.
It's not impossible.
I mean, I happen to know that she was
the main cause of the whole war in Ishbal.
Oh, you mean that story about
a soldier who shot down a kid?
That's a lie.
The real cause was a covert
special ops division of the Military.
It was started on purpose.
That can't be.
I get it. They made the war for
the Ishbalan Philosopher's Stone.
That must be the reason.
Ingredients.
So that someone might create the
Philosopher's Stone using the Grand Arcanum.
They'd go that far?
The whole thing was
designed by those Homunculi.
So that's it.
Hughes must have
figured out that much.
And that's why they killed him.
I'll kill that bastard
with my own hands!
Wait, Ed!
Ed, what's wrong?
Let me go!
It happened right
after we left central!
Those Military
jackasses didn't tell us!
Did you know?
I'm sorry.
I've known about it for a
little while now, Edward.
There's nothing you can do!
Come back downstairs!
You've got to be kidding me!
If Hughes got killed, then it was our
fault for putting him in that situation!
He was our friend!
When are you going to grow up?
Colonel Mustang didn't keep you in
the dark out of malice, you morons!
I've heard about
this Hughes guy.
It sounds like he
was a great man.
But Mustang doesn't want you to
be driven by thoughts of revenge.
He wants you to realize that there
are more important things in life.
I bet your friend Hughes
would have agreed.
Yeah, but... I was... I was
wrong about him all that time.
I thought the Colonel didn't care about
Hughes at all, that he was out for himself.
But what... but what if he...
...he's determined to
become a great man?
Because he promised
Hughes he would.
So he forces himself to
search for the right path.
Not to be taken in by
thoughts of revenge.
He's an adult to look up to.
And why not revenge?
When someone close to you is
killed and you know who's behind it...
...how can there be anything
more important to you than revenge?
If that's being an adult,
then I'm never growing up!
You grew up when you made the
decision to become a dog of the Military.
That bastard...
From now on, I hate him.
Someone's coming, Lust!
Don't worry, Gluttony.
This place is...
Who's that?
I welcome you here, sir.
Unfortunately, my master is out.
So... Lyra is this
body's name, is it?
I'm impressed you know that
much, my Hohenheim of Light.
It's nice to know you've been
thinking about me while you were away.
I heard the name
Lyra from my sons.
But even if I hadn't,
it's fairly obvious.
You can't hide your smell.
Have you come with noble
aspirations to save me?
No.
Not this time, Dante.
Gluttony!
Scary!
Another alchemist
who doesn't need circles.
There's no need to
be worried, Gluttony.
He's spent too much time
in that body he's wearing.
I'm sure he's worn out.
Indeed i am worn out. But that means that
you're feeling your years as well, aren't you?
You may hide your decaying body with
clothes, but that masking scent betrays your lie.
Like you, Hohenheim?
Dante, I want you to stop using my
sons as pawns in your malicious game.
In exchange for that promise, I will tell
you the reason your new body is rotting, too.
Well, it looks like they
managed to turn the Military back.
Yeah, I guess so.
Hey, where's Edward?
He said there was
something he had to do alone.
Sory... I'm sorry... mom...
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 45,
A rotted heart.
Al.
I'm going to fight them all.
You don't have to do anything anymore.