It's beautiful here
and so peaceful.
Yeah, it's rural, a nice way of
saying there's nothing going on.
Four years, brother.
Has it really been that long?
Hmm?
You mean you haven't come
home once since you left?
You can't really come home to a place
where there's no family waiting for you.
You know our general
situation, don't you, Major?
Yes, I do.
Well, this sure is a surprise.
Winry! Better get out here!
Honored guests!
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Well hello to you too, Den.
Old Lady Pinako.
It's been a long time.
I need some more
of your handiwork.
Apparently so.
You really have done a
number this time, huh?
I don't know why you have so
much trouble keeping your arms.
Yeah, well, I've had a
lot of things to swing at.
Huh.
Yet it seems like
you've gotten smaller.
Who are you calling small,
you miniature-sized hag?
You're shorter than your temple!
You're so short,
you're two-dimensional!
Micro moron!
Grandma, please!
Edward Elric.
How dare you speak to your
elder with such blatant disrespect?
Let me remedy this fight
with my genteel decorum!
Who the heck is this guy?
He really doesn't
get the joke, does he?
Alex Louisa Armstrong,
humbly at your service.
Flattered. I'm Pinako Rockbell.
Brother!
Great! I buy you a wrench
and you try to kill me with it!
Well, apparently you're
trying to kill yourself!
What have you been up to?
Gone!
I'm serious, Ed!
I want answers!
How did you wreck the
best Auto-mail I've ever made?
I put my heart and soul into that!
Is it really my fault, though?
It fell apart so easily.
Al's armor is all busted up, too,
and steel doesn't shatter on its own.
You've been getting
into some real trouble.
Uh, no. I mean, ask Ed.
Guess I was wrong, Pipsqueak.
You actually have gotten
taller, at least by a inch.
Then don't say Pipsqueak!
You're off balance.
We'll need to make some height
adjustments to your leg while you're here.
and of course, the new arm will
have to be built from scratch.
Listen, I know I'm asking a lot,
but can you finish it all in a week?
We don't have much time.
Don't insult me, Ed.
We'll have it
done in three days.
You're the best there is, Grams.
But you just got in town.
What do you have
to do that's so urgent?
We... we just want to get to
Central as soon as possible.
We're looking for
something, that's all.
It wouldn't be something
dangerous, would it?
No!
It's nothing like that at all!
Just some research!
Right.
You're nothing but trouble.
We drive her crazy sometimes,
but she's always there for us, right?
Yeah.
She is.
Ah, yeah.
I know it's a spare, but there's just something
about the way the old lady makes them.
It's weird being back.
Kinda nice.
Nothing's really
changed here, has it?
Not at all.
Mr. Armstrong, was it?
I was hoping you could tell me
something about the daily life of those boys.
Living as far out in the country as we do, it's
seldom we get to hear any news from the cities.
and those boys haven't mailed me so much
as a postcard since they've been gone.
I worry about them, that's all.
I can only offer you this.
The Elric brothers, especially
Edward, have garnered
quite a reputation around
Central and in the East.
As the unfortunate result, they do get pulled
into a wide range of troubles from time to time.
But it's all right.
We take my word for it.
Those boys are strong.
Strong?
Really?
Please, help them.
Just bear with us, Ed.
This pains nothing.
I still feel like we're
wasting too much time here.
We've got to get back to
Central and find Marco's work.
and we will.
But don't you think you
should relax while you can?
Things probably aren't going
to be easy when we get there.
I know I should.
But I can't stand lying
around doing nothing.
I get all fidgety.
Brother, I've been thinking.
Maybe you should visit Mom.
You mean go to her grave?
They said the Auto-mail
would be ready in three days.
and you've got nothing
else to do until then.
Go see her.
I'll wait here.
You're right.
I'll be back in
a while, I guess.
I saw that your firewood
was a little low, Mrs. Rockbell.
Thank you.
That's nice.
But you know, you're free to relax
too while you're staying with us.
I appreciate that, ma'am.
But no, daily training
is essential for a soldier.
and do you know where Edward is?
I haven't seen him for a while,
and that makes me nervous.
He said he was going to visit
his mother's grave, I believe.
Hmm.
I told him it was dangerous
to venture out on his own.
He needs to stop
taking these risks.
Don't worry.
He's not alone.
He's got the best escort
in Risembool with him.
Ha!
Edward Elric!
Is that actually you?
Yeah.
It's been a while, huh?
I'll say four or
five years, right?
Yet you're just as puny as ever.
Hey!
Don't call me puny!
Don't mind him.
So are you still one of those
state whatever they're called?
I sure am.
Well, you be careful.
That must be a dangerous
job, you being puny and all.
Would you stop calling me puny!
Hey, you okay?
You're just staring into space.
Uh, Winry.
That girl over
there, who is she?
Oh, that's Mellie.
You know her.
Come on, you remember.
We played together
all the time as kids.
Hide-and-go-seek and tag,
exploring the river and stuff.
Oh.
Is something wrong, Al?
No.
I just couldn't
remember who she was.
That's all.
My mind was blank.
That's no big deal.
It's been years and
she's changed a lot.
You just didn't recognize her.
Yeah.
Maybe.
How are we gonna
live without her?
We're not Al.
We're gonna bring her back.
Ready to go home, Den?
Is that the watch they give you?
Hm? Yeah.
It's got amplifiers.
That boost your transmutation.
Can I see?
The loving workmanship.
The detail.
Now, this is the
work of a craftsman.
How's it run?
Do you wind it or
is it self-wound?
Or could it possibly
be a new technique?
I don't know.
and as long as it's
functioning, I don't care.
Can I see how it
works, Ed, please?
Are you crazy?
I know how you get when you
have your hands on mechanics.
You'll take it apart
to the last screw.
So what if I do?
I'll put it back together
and it'll work just fine.
You know I'm the greatest
mechanic on the planet, Ed, right?
Get somebody else's.
Hm?
I think I'll go chop about
a year's worth of firewood.
Yes.
Wow you guys are
stingy, aren't you?
Al, I talked to Pinako.
She said my arm's
gonna be ready tomorrow.
and I'll fix you.
First thing I do.
Things are finally looking up.
That's good.
Brother, did I
ever have friends?
What?
That's an
out-of-the-blue question.
I don't remember any of them.
I tried to.
But it's hazy.
They don't have faces.
You know how memories work.
You've had a lot of new
experiences and they just pile up.
It's natural for old
memories to fade a little.
There's something wrong with me.
So listen, Al.
There's this thing, see?
It's something I've been meaning
to tell you for a long time now.
But I've been kind of scared, I
guess, of what your reaction would be.
What?
Damn it.
It's just... Tell me.
No, it's nothing.
Forget it.
Brother, tell me!
Gentlemen, look up at the sky!
This night gives us a bounty of gifts, like
a blanket of shimmering, brilliant jewels.
It's a majesty that cannot be witnessed
in the city in its haze of electric light.
This is an amazing place you're
from, this quiet little village of Risembool.
In exchange for its barrenness,
it has much the city does not.
You can lose
yourself in the sky.
Years ago, we used to look up at the
stars almost every night, didn't we, Al?
Yeah.
and dream.
and now, the moment
you've been waiting for!
Docking time!
Yeah, right.
Connecting to each of my nerves.
I can't get enough.
Don't complain, you baby.
You want to hurry and get
back to Central, don't you?
You got that part right.
This is just more motivation.
I can't wait till I get my body
back to pure-grade flesh and bone.
Well, that's going to be a
real disappointment for us.
We make a killing off you.
Seriously, Ed, why go to all
this trouble just for human limbs?
You've got the smell of oil, the creak of
synthetic muscles, the hum of spinning bearings.
Who needs natural
when you've got Auto-mail?
Loser machine junkie.
Alchemy freak!
Okay, we're ready.
One, two, three!
You two get up.
We're going to lay
him down right there.
We could use some help.
I had no idea attaching
Auto-mail was so painful.
I've seen it make the most hardened
war heroes scream like children.
It's no small matter.
Well, what do you think about
the changed designs, Ed?
I tried to make the steel 80%
lighter than the last go-around.
After all, we can't have it weighing you
down so much you never grow any taller.
That's got to be illegal.
Making fun of somebody's
height when they're in pain like this.
Look at you.
You've already got
enough energy to argue.
You'll be fine.
Seriously, now.
The lighter weight should
make you faster, but that
means it's easier to break,
too, so don't be reckless.
You can replace Auto-mail,
but you've only got one life.
Right.
That's the first all-nighter
I've pulled in a while.
I'm beat.
Really, Winry.
Thanks.
Don't thank me for the rush.
I'm charging you a fortune.
How do I look?
How do you feel?
That's the question.
Great!
100%!
I'm glad to hear it.
Yeah, I bet you are.
It means now we
can take care of you.
So you're sure
this is everything?
Mm-hmm.
The Major and the rest were very
careful to pick up every piece of me.
Will he be able to
move once he's fixed?
Yeah, well, you definitely
have to know what you're doing.
See that seal in there?
Mm-hmm.
That's the anchoring point.
It's the intermediary
between Al's soul and the armor.
It really was a
close call, wasn't it?
If that gash had been
a little closer in... Right.
So no matter what else happens,
we've got to guard that better.
Without that critical area, Al,
there'd be nothing to tie you down.
It looks like it was
drawn with blood.
Yeah, that's my blood.
I was kind of in a hurry.
Hmm.
Oh, inspiring!
Such a bond!
Such a display
of brotherly love!
Back up, Major Spaz.
You're really getting in
the way of the work here.
Here goes.
I feel great.
Thanks, brother.
Aw don't mention it.
Should we do our usual routine now?
What does that mean?
Nothing.
Just a little skirmish
between brothers.
Our teacher told us a long time ago you
have to train the body to train the mind.
So we spar once in a
while to test our skills.
But I gotta say, in all these years,
I've never beaten this tin can once.
Is that so?
Then allow me to help
you in your goal, Edward!
We're okay, but thanks.
Thank you!
I hope you're
ready for this, Al.
Hey, now boys, don't get carried
away and break yourselves again!
Good grief.
Talk about your one-track minds.
There's still a
couple of children.
Next up, me!
Agh!
Uuh.
Huh.
It would be a crime against Discovery
not to find out how this thing ticks.
The polished form, the
curious workmanship.
It's clearly the
work of a master.
Custom jobs are so great.
I bet it's even better inside.
I want to take it apart.
Oh, please I want to
put it back together again!
Edward...
You better watch it!
You're strong, but
your attitude's soft.
You'll never win like this!
Ugh!
Brother.
Damn.
Forget what?
What's the matter, Erich?
Is that all you've got?
Alright!
Yeah!
I can't believe it.
We did it! We did it! We got him!
We really got him.
Good job, brother!
Yeah!
Winry?
Is there something wrong?
I'm sorry, Ed.
I'm sorry.
Ah!
You've got some nerve!
I know.
I didn't mean to see.
Ah, hell.
No one's seen that dumb thing.
Not even Al.
I'm sorry.
I'm one tough
survivor, aren't I?
Having to carry around my
guilty motivation in my pocket.
Like some sniveling little
kid with a magic charm.
Edward... We've got
no home, no family.
The only thing that makes
sense is moving forward.
But I'm still wasting all
this time here looking back.
What's wasted?
How can you say that?
What about Grandma and me?
We're a home that's
always been here.
Why do you want to keep
shutting everything out?
Don't be dramatic.
What the hell are you
getting teary about anyway?
Because you won't.
Neither of you will
after all this time.
So I'm crying for you both.
Where could they have gone?
Didn't you tell them that
we were having dinner?
You needn't worry
about them, Winry.
I'm sure they'll
be along shortly.
We just have to wait for them
to return like we always have.
This is where
the front door was.
and the living room.
The fireplace was here.
We'd start it when it got cold.
You'd always find an excuse so you
wouldn't have to chop wood yourself.
Whenever we stayed out too late, Mom
would flash a lamp from the second story window.
It was bright and it cut through
the darkness all across the hills.
and no matter where we were, we
could see it and we'd come running home.
Yeah, I forgot about that.
You boys are fools.
You do have a home with a
caring family waiting for you.
Brother.
Look.
Now you boys don't be strangers.
You come by and have dinner
with us sometime soon.
You hear?
We will.
Home sweet home, right?
Thank you, Granny.
Yes, your hospitality
has been immeasurable.
So you'll come home soon?
Yeah.
Granny.
Huh?
I read the inside of Ed's watch.
He engraved something on it.
Don't forget.
On the date they
burned their house and left.
But what exactly do you
think you wanted to remember?
Full Metal Alchemist.
Episode 18, Marco's Notes.
The first branch of
the library in Central.
From a pile of burnt ashes,
a stunning truth will emerge.