It's so cruel.
If the Devil really does interfere in
this world, we've seen his work tonight.
The Devil's work, huh?
We state alchemists are human
artillery they roll out if nothing else works.
And when the military calls, it's our duty to
respond regardless of how grotesque the scenario.
To serve, we have to distance
ourselves from emotional attachments.
In that way, we're not
so different from Tucker.
With respect, that's the
reasoning of an adult.
But those children
are still just...
Brother.
Brother, the Major.
There's no use, kid.
You can't go around trying to bring every living
creature that dies on you back to life, Edward.
It's not possible
and it's not healthy.
Anyway, who'd you be helping by
bringing back a malformed chimera?
It's an ugly world out there.
And from here on out, it's only gonna
get uglier on the path you've chosen.
Just be thankful it wasn't
you and get on with your life.
Get on with my life?!
There's a reason you became
a state alchemist, right, Ed?
Can you really afford to get
distracted by every little lost cause?
Great.
Well, so much for making it home
in time to kiss my little girl goodnight.
Crime scene's over here.
It's up to the investigations
department now.
Step aside.
We've got some
kind of mess here.
Is this the work of that serial
killer we've been tracking, Mustang?
No, that guy only
goes for women.
Besides, this thing
wasn't carved up.
Right.
I'd say it was almost as if that poor pathetic
creature were blown apart from the inside.
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Fullmetal Alchemist, Episode
8: The Philosopher's Stone
Why so glum, Elric?
This job's a little more
real than I bargained on.
I think I just need something to
take my mind off this whole mess.
So, uh, what's this
assignment you've got for me?
There you go.
Your orders are to go through
and organize all of this stuff.
You should familiarize yourself with
all the results of Tucker's experiments.
So you want me to take
over that maniac's research?
True, he might have gone about it the
wrong way, but some of his findings could
be of great use to the military.
Why don't you let that
whack-job help you himself?
He can't.
He's dead.
His guilt was so obvious that the higher
-ups decided to forego the embarrassment
of a trial and skip
straight to the execution.
So they covered it up!
How could they--
We don't question the
wisdom of the military.
See, that's the first law
of state alchemy, Ed.
Interesting.
It looks like Mr. Tucker was doing a lot
of research on the Philosopher's Stone.
Whoop-dee-flippin'-do.
How long are you planning
to sulk like this, brother?
Do you have any idea the power the
Philosopher's Stone holds for alchemists?
We could bypass all the laws of
alchemy, including equivalent exchange!
We could do the things
we weren't able to do before.
We could... We can't do
anything because it doesn't exist!
It's just a bedtime story!
But if the bonafide state alchemist like
Mr. Tucker was doing research on it...
Who gives a damn
about his research?
The man was a lunatic!
Or have you
forgotten about Nina?
It's a no-go, kid.
But why not?
What if that serial killer you guys
have been chasing really did kill Nina?
I could help you find him!
And the job that you
were ordered to do?
Have you finished
analyzing Tucker's research?
I couldn't do that.
In that case, I'll
investigate on my own.
Right.
Investigate on your own.
And leave that here.
Yeah, I intended to.
Brother?
Hold on, Ed.
You're not the only
one who's upset.
We couldn't do
anything for Nina.
But we're
alchemists, not police.
We can't catch a killer.
What we can do is put our
talents to better use doing research.
So that if another girl like Nina ever
comes along, we'll know how to save...
...her.
It's you.
You were outside the library.
Tell me, if you've got access to the library in
Central, then that must make you a state alchemist.
Well, I was, yeah.
But that's all behind me now.
Really?
You're better off.
Because if you were still a state
alchemist, this arm would destroy you.
I can't wait to see
Ed and Al's faces.
They'd never expect me to travel all
the way here just to congratulate them.
Surprise!
Have you ever seen it?
What can you tell me about it?
Not too much.
I'm afraid I've never heard anything
substantial about the Philosopher's Stone.
Well, about it actually
existing, anyway.
As far as I know,
it's just a legend.
I see.
But I can say, if you know what's best
for you, you'll find another hobby to pursue.
It's been said that bad things have a way of
happening to those who seek the Philosopher's Stone.
Did someone say
something about the Stone?
Who is this guy?
Are you kidding?
This guy is--
So, you'd like to get your hands
on the Stone, is that right, son?
Yes, sir.
And why do you want it?
For human trans--
I mean, I need it to recover
something important that my brother lost.
Is that so?
This brother of yours
must be very special to you.
It's some undertaking.
The crusade you're embarking
on is as old as alchemy itself.
Personally, I try
to stay above it.
But from time to time, you'll hear about some
alchemist who's succeeded in forging a Stone.
Such rumors naturally have a way of
congregating around military personnel.
So there should be plenty of records on
the subject down at the National Library.
Is that true?
Most assuredly.
Of course, only state
alchemists have access to it.
So what you're saying is, any state
alchemist could find out more about this thing?
Uh, excuse me.
With all due respect, sir, why would you
encourage him to chase a futile pursuit like that?
Hmph.
I think it's a good thing for
youngsters to have dreams to follow.
Don't you agree with
me, second lieutenant?
Yes, sir.
You see, I'm right!
You think she's just
too cute, don't you?
Uh, yeah, that's it.
You got me.
What do you think?
I know it.
You're thinking she
takes after me, right?
Well, the apple doesn't
fall far from the tree.
Yeah.
I've seen that same
picture a dozen times!
Now there's no need
for that attitude, is there?
Not when I've shared classified
files on the serial killer with you.
Yeah, and you owe me for the
train and delivering your baby.
So what else you got?
Touché, touché.
Well, anyway, the
investigation's at a standstill.
We've got no clues and
no witnesses to go on.
The bodies are all sliced and diced,
but none of us can figure out how he does
it in such a short time.
Maybe he killed them somewhere
else and then moved the bodies later.
How long between the time of
death and when they were found?
We've come a long way, but even
with modern science, we can't figure that.
But between us and the police, we must
have checked the trunks of every single.
..
...car entering
and exiting the city.
There must be some sort of
blind spot you're missing here.
A car that can hide bodies, or a... Or
maybe it's all been the work of an alchemist.
Alchemists are not
cold-blooded murderers!
[Laughter]
Excuse me, sir.
Are you Edward Elric?
Who's asking?
There's a visitor
here to see you.
Waiting out front.
A visitor?
Hey.
If it isn't our
prettiest delivery girl.
Behave yourself.
So they held the certification
exams recently, right?
Yes, ma'am.
And did you hear it?
This time, some 12-year-old alchemist
actually made the cut, if you can believe it.
All he has to do is... this.
And just like that,
he can transmute.
Very impressive indeed.
Right there.
He's the short
one in the red coat.
Look at him.
He's just a little kid.
By the way, I want you to be extra
careful out there with that freak on the loose.
They say he goes for the
young pretty ones like you.
How sweet.
It's nice to hear
you think I'm pretty.
Well, yeah.
I sure hope they
catch this creep soon.
You and me both.
So, working around here, you must get
all the inside scoop on this case, right?
Isn't that just like Ed to
keep me waiting forever?
That's one of those
new refrigerated trucks!
I've read all about these, but I've
never seen one up close before.
So cool.
I'd sure love to take it apart.
I'm afraid that would
make it a bit hard to drive.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Is this your truck?
Sure is.
I, uh, use it to
make deliveries.
It really is amazing!
Would you like to
take a look inside?
Really?
Can I?
Thank you so much!
That's odd.
I told her to wait right here.
I wonder where she
could have wandered off to.
What's up, Mr. Elric?
Is this...
Winry?
Was there a car stopped
here when you left her?
Well, yeah.
There's always refrigerated trucks parked
here when they drop off food for the mess hall.
Refrigerated trucks?
A car that can hide bodies?
Oh, no!
Where are you going, Mr. Elric?
Hey, miss.
Are you alright?
Have you seen
others like you in here?
Over there.
A young girl.
Okay, I'll just go grab her and
we can get the hell out of this place.
Don't worry, ma'am.
You're in safe hands now--
My hero awakes.
Why, you...
Word on the playground is you can
transmute without a circle just using your hands.
So to be safe.
Please, let me introduce myself.
My name is Barry, and
this here is my butcher shop.
You're a man!
Guilty as charged.
And to reward you for making it
this far, we have a special guest.
Let her go!
Since she enjoys taking things
apart, I thought I'd do the same to her.
If you watch us carefully, you just
might get to see what makes her tick.
You sick--!
Why are you doing this?
Why?
Huh.
What a strange
little question that is.
I suppose it's
because I enjoy it.
The first person I
killed was my wife.
She was nagging me about something, and
then without meaning to, I chopped her to pieces.
But when I saw how finely I
could slice her, I wanted more.
More people to cut up, to reduce
to their most basic building blocks.
And I wanted everyone to see.
How could a person murder
someone for such a ridiculous reason?
Because they can.
Given the slightest
provocation, anybody can do it.
Stay back!
Men have morals, but send them to war
and they have no problem slaying each other in
the most brutal fashions.
Why do you think that is?
I have no idea.
Because deep down
inside, we all want to kill.
Most just need the
go-ahead from their society.
Like the state alchemists I saw in a
village, slaughtering helpless people.
Splat big fountains of blood.
That's not true.
No!
You little--!
Damn it!
Don't!
It'll take more than
that to kill me, Brother.
Hey!
They're all in here!
Don't move!
Al...
I--
Brother, are you hurt?
I thought he was gonna kill me.
I honestly thought
I was gonna die.
I was so scared.
So scared!
Major Hughes was the one who realized
the truck from this particular shop had
bypassed numerous
inspection points.
Thanks to him, we
managed to get there in time.
Afterwards, the case of Barry
the Chopper became infamous.
And it would be spoken of as
Ed's first distinguished achievement.
But he would
remember it differently.
Brother?
It turns out the Philosopher's
Stone may very well be real.
But all the clues we need to find it are
off-limits to everyone except state alchemists.
Since I no longer have a mortal shell,
I can't feel the terror you felt thinking
you were going to die.
I'm sure it must have
been painful and lonely.
I want my body back, brother.
I want to be able
to feel what you felt.
To feel human again.
If we find the Philosopher's
Stone, I can have that.
And we can repair
what we've broken.
When I was certain that he was
going to kill me, my mind went blank.
And I didn't have
any hope anymore.
The only thing I could do
was scream my lungs out.
I felt so helpless.
I couldn't even bring myself to
believe someone might save me.
Then you showed up, Al.
And I realized if we don't take
care of each other, no one else will.
So I'll do anything in my
power to get our bodies back.
Even if it means being
the military's lab dog.
And we'll just have to hope our powers are
good enough to help us rise above our own limits.
Because we're not gods.
We're humans.
Tiny, insignificant humans.
Who couldn't even
save a little girl...
On one condition, you say?
I'll obey all your orders, sir.
But as long as I serve, I'd like to receive
all information on the Philosopher's Stone.
And then whenever I've finished all my other
duties, you have to permit me to search for it.
People will question
your motives.
You realize what'll happen if the state
learns about your human transmutation.
Al will be hauled off to some
lab as a precious sample.
Well, I can keep that in my back
pocket to make sure you behave.
Fine.
But you'll report to me everything you
uncover about the Philosopher's Stone.
Oh, and I almost forgot.
You've been issued your
official state title by the Fuhrer.
It's quite ironic, actually.
He's got a good sense of humor.
We give the name Fullmetal
to thee, Edward Elric.
In the name of
Fuhrer-King Bradley.
Along with the pocket watch, every one
of us is assigned a symbolic second name,
depending on your talents.
And yours is "Fullmetal".
The Fullmetal Alchemist.
Sounds heavy.
Tell him I like the feel of it.
I won't let it weigh me down.
To celebrate, you're going to buy me all
kinds of neat things I can't get back home, right?
I think you've got
it backwards there.
I forget.
Who fixed up your arm?
I heard that serial killer had
nothing to do with Nina's death.
Is that true, Brother?
Yeah, it didn't fit his pattern.
And he had an alibi that night.
So if he didn't kill
Nina... who did?
Fullmetal Alchemist.
Episode 9.
Be Thou for the People.
From the very beginning, I knew what it
would mean to become a state alchemist.
I only hope I made
the right choice, Al.