Good luck soldier I
hope you find your man.
I can smell the stray dog
Ishbalan but now he's goodbye.
Brother what's going
to happen to Dr. Marco?
Are you worried?
The Fuhrer said that he's
gonna protect him now.
Not much we can do unless
we want to start a new war.
Central Library?
And as a fugitive Marco
must have found a way to
hide his materials right
under the military's nose.
And the second part, what
do you think that means?
Got me.
But keep it a secret from the
Colonel and the rest of the state.
You sure that's a good idea?
Listen Al, I don't know if
we can trust them anymore.
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Leaving so soon, sir.
Funny how things work.
Now that Scar has shown up here in the
East, the bureaucrats are suddenly very
concerned about their
duties back in Central.
I'm sorry for the
inconvenience, you Colonel.
Can you choose
my punishment first?
Punishment?
I've known where the Crystal
Alchemist was hiding for some time now.
I've never informed the state.
It was a job well done, Colonel.
Sir?
I've been wanting to put the
good doctor in protective custody.
My second-in-command, the late
Brigadier General, was violently opposed to it.
But as you know, he's the one who ordered Marco
to use his work in battle, against his judgment.
This life has been hard on Marco,
and I wanted to make it up to him.
But in terms of his research,
sir, we have... That will be all.
I will continue to
rely on you, Colonel.
Have a safe journey.
Take my advice, Mustang.
The Philosopher's
Stone does not exist.
You see, I came
out fine as ever.
You know, maybe it would do you some good
to get your hands slapped every once in a while.
Don't blame me.
That guy's a wall.
I can't figure him out.
Creation follows destruction.
I'll fix him up nice and pretty.
Uh, that's okay.
Bonding a soul to steel
is no walk in the park.
Full Metal's the only
one who can fix Al now.
Go ahead.
Ask him.
That's right.
It's my burden.
But before I do anything, I
need to get my other arm back.
Well, that is an
interesting fix, isn't it?
I mean, if the great Edward
can't use his alchemy...
He's just a useless teen
with a grumpy-ass attitude.
Anyway, I have to
take some leave now.
I'm going back to my mechanic.
You know the one, don't you?
Sure, Ed.
How could I forget?
I saw you in her house, unconscious with
that same stump of an arm you have now.
Balling in your sleep, it hurts!
I'm gonna pee my pants!
So tough.
So, where are you gonna
go once you're fixed?
Central.
I've got something to
look up in the library there.
That's a heck of a trip.
You'll need some protection.
I would volunteer, but...
Well, since the Fuhrer's going straight to
Central and I'm part of his escort, I can't go.
They just put me
back in charge here.
I've got to look
after this place.
And I've got to look
after the Colonel.
You could send me, but I
don't know how much help I'd
be up against a fanatical
alchemist serial killer.
Same goes for me!
That settles it.
Sign me up!
I'll protect the boys on their
journey for repairs and investigation.
We don't need an escort!
Really, Ed?
And what do you plan to do?
What do you plan to do if Scar
shows up while you're missing that arm?
Can't fight.
Can't exactly carry your
hobbled brother to safety, either.
Children should
listen to adults!
You can't call us children!
Al, why don't you
stick up for us here?
That's the first time anyone's treated
me like a kid since I've been in this armor!
Thank you!
The train leaves
soon, Edward Elric.
We'd better go pack our bags.
And this is the first time
anyone's treated me like luggage.
Spacious.
Newspaper?
I've got tea, too.
Hey, I got a message from Roy.
You mean the Colonel?
He said, don't die
under my command.
You're enough of a pain
without the paperwork.
That was it.
Tell him, fine, there's no
way I'm dying before you
do, you morally bankrupt
Colonel with a God complex.
Tell him to take this guerrilla
escort here off my hands too.
All right, easy.
Look, Ed, I don't know what Marco said to upset
you, but I have some info you might find helpful.
Three years ago, we found the remains of a
young girl who'd been changed into a Chimera.
I'm sure you remember.
Nina.
The way she was torn apart?
Turns out it's identical to
how Scar's been killing people.
Thanks, Hughes.
That does help.
Now I can take him on.
See you in Central.
I'll apply for permission to browse
through the First Branch without restrictions.
Don't mind the
left-handed salute.
They're going to Central First
Branch, or something like that.
You mean the first branch
of the library in Central?
Now give me back my sister!
Please, forgive me!
What took you so long?
What was the Fuhrer's answer?
You told those boys where
your findings are, didn't you?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
But that's okay, Doctor.
The boy will move even closer
to the Philosopher's Stone now.
However, if you included any
extra information in what you wrote,
that's when I'll get upset.
Edward's much
smarter than you think.
Once he understands what I've
written, he won't do what you want him to.
And that's exactly why, before he
reads anything, I thought I'd look into it.
You won't have the chance.
You're going to die right here.
Monster!
That was heartless, Doctor.
After all, isn't dying
once enough for a girl.
Then it is true.
What you creatures
are, like the stories say.
Gluttony.
Huh?
Fair's fair.
You told those boys
where to find your papers.
Now you're going to tell me.
I've had enough
of that blowhard, Al.
It just goes on and on and on.
The whole time he's bragging
about his illustrious family background.
I'd rather try my luck
in here with the sheep.
Hey, Al?
Al?
You there?
Major problem.
They mistook Al for someone else's
cargo and they dropped him at the last stop.
We'll turn around
at the next station.
Are you crazy?
I can't wait that long.
Yes, you can.
Get off my back!
It is important that you
calm down, Edward Elric.
What could I do?
I'm empty armor with
half my pieces missing.
If I'd said, don't move me, I'm with
Elric, what would they have done?
Brother will notice, won't he?
No fair, Sky.
I'm the one who
feels like crying.
Nice.
What do you mean he ran off?
He wouldn't have done that!
The armor looks
something like this.
Are you sure that's
what you saw?
Yeah, you're quite a
talented artist there, sir.
The ability's been passed
down the Armstrong line for years.
How can you act so casual?
It's too dangerous.
We can wait here.
None of you can understand us.
We don't operate like you.
What's that mean?
Dr. Marko told us the truth.
We know what all
of you did in Ishbal.
About time I found someone here.
Listen, I'm looking for a suit of
armor that was left by the train.
It's really big and dark gray.
Wait!
Did you see it?
Hospitable.
Hey, get back here!
I said hold on!
Didn't your parents
teach you not to steal?
Damn it all.
I need more limbs.
It's gonna suck if I have
to start crawling after her.
This isn't good.
We're just getting farther
from the train station.
Hey!
I think I'm hearing voices.
Just one voice.
It's me, the armor.
The stuff I'm
wearing's incredible.
I didn't even get a scratch.
Excuse me.
It's doing it again.
Please don't be scared.
I'm, uh...
I'm the latest model of armor.
The sensational Model
S Talking Armor Suit.
We're very popular
in Central right now.
Okay, so how do I turn you off?
Where's the button?
Uh, you can't turn me off.
We're fully automated.
Well then, can you at
least keep yourself quiet?
Where are we going?
We suits like to,
uh, plan ahead.
To a fight.
A fight?
Boss Po said if I wanted to be like him, I should
go prove I'm a man and rub out a couple of guys.
So I told him I'd lay
into the Damesha family.
Cause they're always stepping into
our territory, and pushing us around,
and telling us how
tough they are.
If I can bring back one of their heads
looking like this, they'll see that I'm a
fighter you listen to, and they
won't treat me like a kid ever again.
And the boss won't have a choice
but to turn me into his right-hand man.
I'll win!
I'll flatten them!
You don't really mean you're
gonna kill anyone, do you?
What, you don't think I will?
You're some pretty good armor.
I won't even have to worry
if they pull a gun on me.
That's why you're wearing me?
So you won't get hurt?
Of course.
Once I know I'm
invincible, I can go all out.
Still, it's gonna hurt.
Why, are you a defective
model or something?
It's going to hurt
you in your heart.
Don't be stupid.
But I can fix that so
you don't feel anything.
That's what you want, right?
Relax your left arm.
Hey, what are you doing to me?
Stop!
I am the cursed wormy arm.
No, wait.
I am the cursed demon armor.
Once your body becomes one with my steel, you
will lose all emotion and be a warrior of death.
For I will take your soul.
I'm sorry about this.
It's been tough on her, having to live
out here with an old, broken man like me.
Watching me hobble
around all day long.
It's funny the way a
child's logic can work.
Just trying to make life
easier for a grandpa, huh?
You got a good eye,
noticing the leg, girl.
But I can't give it to you.
I've got my own needs.
If you want, I could point you towards
the engineer who designed it for me.
She's got a sharp
tongue, but decent skills.
I appreciate the offer,
but I don't need a fake leg.
Hey, don't knock it.
It's handy once
you get used to it.
Probably so, but
that's not the point.
There are more useful things than walking,
and I'd rather keep my leg the way it is.
It was a saber wound,
and it got infected.
By the time they carried me from the front line
to the rear, all they could do was saw it off.
Front line?
Then you were a soldier.
So which war did you fight in?
The North one?
Or was it... Wait, you
mean you went to Ishbal?
Men are not men
on the battlefield.
We turn into some
other creature.
You can do the cruelest things.
Doesn't even matter
if it's an order or not.
To protect yourself, your mind
shuts out any emotions you have.
It's like a steel door.
But once the war is over... You
can't keep it closed anymore.
I can never let myself forget
what I saw there and what I did.
This leg's my constant reminder.
When I look at it, the whole
thing comes rushing back.
That's your reason?
You don't want automail that could make you
functional just so you can wallow in your guilt?
That's not the only reason.
It's true I've lost my leg, but
I've gained something in return.
Something much more important.
Quiet.
Peace of mind.
The chance to live
with my grandchildren.
Watch them grow.
It's only after we've given something up
that we obtain the thing we really want.
Isn't that the way
of the alchemist?
Yeah, that's right.
But what about all those men who
went to war and came back in one piece?
That's the whole
dream of a soldier, right?
Those people who came back without a
scratch have lost something just as real.
Even if it's something
you can't see on their skin.
Looks like you've had your
share of losses yourself.
Surely you've gained
something back.
You do believe in equivalent
exchange, don't you?
But how can that be?
I've spent years
devoted to alchemy.
That damn principle.
Getting my arm and leg
back and my brother's body.
That's our dream.
And we keep looking for something
we can do to balance the equation.
To earn it back.
But I've never turned
it around the other way.
Where was the equivalency then?
What have we ever
gained for our losses?
It's always been
a one-way current.
Just a series of us
giving to the void.
Everything's been taken from us!
A dream to get everything
back the way it was.
But once you have it, what
will you do with your life?
The pleasure of a
dream is that it's a fantasy.
If it happens, it
was never a dream.
Maybe you're right.
But I still have to try.
Thanks for the tea.
Brother?
Grandpa, he's here!
Brother's come back home!
Wait a second.
I forgot!
Ow!
Yes?
You're here.
You're aware that you
reek of sheep, right?
It's disgusting.
Well, excuse me for being cargo.
A wash-up at Pinako's house.
You happy?
Listen, Al.
You remember when Colonel Mustang
showed up at Risembool, at the Rockbells?
He said he came in response
to one of the letters we sent.
Sure, I remember.
He said he was looking for Dad.
Yeah, well, you think
that was his actual reason?
Or was he coming
for something else?
Major.
I was worried about you.
It's my fault.
What's the matter?
Sorry, Major.
About earlier.
What I said.
That's our train.
If we don't catch it, we'll
have to wait till noon tomorrow.
Come on!
What are you doing?
Time to sprint!
This method of short-distance running has been
passed down the Armstrong Line for generations!
Put me down!
I'm gonna be sick!
And I'm gonna break!
Full Metal Alchemist.
Episode 17, House
of the Waiting Family.
On the day we left, we burned down our house
and we thought we had nothing to go home to.
But we were wrong.