Got my girlfriend to
bake you an apple pie.
You want it?
Roy.
It's called a taboo.
Forbidden alchemy.
It's kind of fun.
I don't understand
much about alchemy.
But I'm no fool and I certainly know what
happens to anyone who commits a taboo.
You can relax, Maes.
I haven't done anything.
Maybe not yet, but
you were planning to.
You just don't understand.
I killed a lot of
people out there.
It was a war.
Easy for you to say
you weren't there.
No, I wasn't.
And if you didn't want to kill enemies in
battle, you shouldn't have been there either.
You should have asked
for a desk job like I did.
Did you think if you became a state
alchemist you could fix everything?
Bring back anyone who ever
died in a controversial war?
Invent some utopian world?
I don't know.
Is a taboo so easy to commit that
you just need a little binge of studying
to pull it off?
Or do you just
want a way to die?
Because if that's the case,
there's plenty of easier means.
I had it in my mouth, Maes,
and I couldn't pull the trigger.
I was too afraid to end it.
I'd hope so.
It's just the kind of
cowardly human that I am.
Every sane person is.
But still, even my life, detestable
as it is, will have some use.
Huh?
Maes, I've got a plan.
Let's hear it, Roy.
Sir, wake up.
There's someone here.
It's okay.
I'll wait.
Führer!
Sorry, sir.
You seem to be conducting an
investigation on the military's higher-ups.
Yes, sir.
It's concerning Laboratory Five.
I've already headed
my own investigation.
I've found that Brigadier General Basque Grand
may have allied with some Ishbalan remnants.
and conducted dangerous
research which has been destroyed.
That was my conclusion.
Are you not satisfied with that?
With respect, sir, no, I'm not.
What?
Is it the Philosopher's Stone?
Yes.
I'm now under the assumption that there was research
within the military to create the Philosopher's Stone...
and there were many illegal acts
involved in trying to make it happen.
This goes a lot deeper than
just Brigadier General Grand.
At the very least, Dr. Marcoh's former
supervisors at the lab were involved as well.
And there's a high probability
the people on that list were, too.
A Major General, a Brigadier General, a
Colonel... You're implicating all of them?
Yes.
And during the past year, all the people on that list
have either passed away, been killed, or are missing.
But all indication is
the plan hasn't stopped.
Lab Five was still running.
And just a few days ago, someone hired a band
of mercenaries to attack an Ishbalan refugee camp.
My sense is the people on that
list were just the puppets in this.
So you're saying a faction
still exists in the military...
that will commit unspeakable crimes
to create this mythical cure all, right?
If such a thing got out, we'd
lose all respect and credibility.
Our control of this state
would crumble at our feet.
I'm joking, Hughes.
Investigate it fully.
The military has endured great storms of
mutiny in the past, and we'll ride this one out as well.
These outlaws ran vile,
forbidden human experiments.
And sent killers calling
themselves Homunculi to cover up.
We'll extract the bad part out.
Thank you, Führer, sir.
Now, there's one more thing.
It's about Dr. Marcoh, correct?
Yes, sir.
I have some questions for him.
Well, Juliet?
He's safe and hiding.
I'll have him brought
to Central now.
She's the only person who knows the exact
location of the doctor at any given moment.
It's to prevent me from leaking
information if I were tortured by the enemy.
Can't be too cautious.
Please take me to him.
Uh, Miss Douglas.
Extract the bad part out.
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
All right.
So, all the higher-up officers who we assume were in
Lab Five's chain of command either died or fell off the map.
You'll note that the criminal with
the Ouroboros tattoo isn't on that list.
Sounds like they're talking about
some really heavy stuff in there.
Well, I'm not going to listen.
I've gotten myself in enough
trouble already that way.
The scientists who worked
under Dr. Marcoh aren't on the list.
Maybe they were thought not to have
enough information individually to be a threat.
If we can find
them... Leave it to me.
Um, about that... The thing is, we
honestly don't care about that stuff anymore.
What do you mean you don't care?
Are you crazy?
We just don't think we should have to
deal with dangerous things anymore,
like the Philosopher's
Stone or Homunculi.
Yeah, we thought it would be better
to look for a different way, you know?
Well, boys, it would
definitely be better, but...
If you really thought there was another
way, why did you go through all this trouble?
Who knows?
Maybe there's not, but
there's someone we should ask.
Our original teacher.
She lives south of here,
in a place called Dublith.
We're planning on
taking a trip there.
But it's just so sudden.
There!
On the way to Dublith!
What is it, Winry?
Only the world wide Mecca
of Automail, Rush Valley!
You really gotta take me there!
You gotta!
I've always wanted to go!
Come on, you guys!
Please!
Vacation on your own time, okay?
Well, and who would pay
for my travel expenses?
Very funny!
We can manage it.
It's on the way, like she said.
Okay, fine.
Hooray!
So, they're finally gonna quit throwing themselves
into dangerous situations they don't need to be in.
Must have learned their lesson from seeing the
trouble we had to go through as their bodyguards.
That's my bet.
It would be a perfect ending if
they actually meant what they said.
They told us that to protect us, so we
don't become the next victims on the list.
It's easy to forget
they're kids sometimes.
What do you mean
we're not going to Dublith?
Don't worry.
We'll still take
you to Rush Valley.
Well, okay then.
But what about your teacher?
Didn't you want to ask about another way to fix
yourselves besides with the Philosopher's Stone?
If we go for any
reason, we'll be killed.
Wait a sec...
Killed?
The brother never told her
he became a State Alchemist.
Even worse, if she realized from our
bodies that we tried to do human alchemy.
Personally, I'd like
to live a little longer.
I at least want to fall in
love before I'm through.
And even if those
weren't issues.
Honestly, I just don't think
it'd be right asking her that.
So, where are you going?
We've learned about a pretty sizable Ishbalan
refugee camp hidden in the mountains to the south.
I think Scar and the others may have
gone there after the mercenaries attacked.
You're going after Scar?
It's been said that a philosopher's stone was
created in Ishbal, but no one ever taught them alchemy.
In fact, their culture rejected it, so we
think they may have made it some other way.
A completely different method.
I'm gonna beat the pulp out of him
and force him to tell me their secret.
Brother, about Scar...
He's really not that bad
of a person, you know.
He's murdered dozens of people,
and he's done it by using alchemy.
I can't forgive him for that.
Brother! Master!
Hi...
Why have you come here?
You're not an Ishbalan.
Who are you?
Where are my manners?
I've forgotten to
introduce myself.
I'm the State Alchemist who's been sent
here to annihilate this part of your race.
You've got a visitor!
Master!
I'm glad you are safe.
I did not know you had survived.
Where have you been hiding?
A number of our people are
in the Southern Mountains.
I've spent much
of my time there.
Yes, we've heard
of that encampment.
We're planning to head
out that way ourselves.
A group of us have just completed an
expedition and escaped the military's notice.
We were picking up our kin
who were isolated in Central.
On our journey, we
heard stories about you.
I gather that you've been on a
hunt, finding and killing all the state
Alchemists you could
over these past three years.
State Alchemists burned our
homes, slaughtered our people.
I understand your anger.
Yeah, he's brave.
I think these trash
are from Ishbal, boys.
They must think it's safe
wandering around the canyon.
You're only supposed to
live in the designated camps.
It's dangerous out here.
Someone might hurt you.
But your revenge, is it not taking out your
anger on strangers who did you no harm?
Revenge is a beast that
begets itself and solves nothing.
It only leads to more pain.
Remember the great
words of Ishbala, my student.
Even in the darkest of
suffering, a man can sleep.
But for the man who inflicts the
suffering, his mind cannot rest.
Ever.
That arm with the markings.
Is that not the right arm
of your older brother?
You honestly don't think them being
hospitalized was important information for me?
I'm sorry.
I thought I told you.
It was just some minor scrapes.
- He couldn't use his arm anymore. But
more importantly Roy, I've heard some things.
Sounds like your transfer to
Central may become finalized soon.
You need to hurry up and get important
here so we can have an easier time.
And find yourself a good wife.
Easy on the phone, sir.
Lieutenant, book us a train.
To Central, Colonel?
Something's going on here.
I don't think it's unreasonable.
Roy's worried about
those boys, too.
He shouldn't worry about something he doesn't
have to, or get bogged down with trivial things.
Besides, if it's really
coming from the inside...
there's a good chance
our line's been tapped.
Sorry, but I still have
to check on something.
Just be careful.
Daddy has a lot of work to do.
Bye-bye.
Get me all the files
on the riots in Lior.
The drawing of the
transmutation circle in Lab Five.
Where is it?
Coming!
Volumes Three and Four
on the Ishbal uprising.
Let's go!
Am I gonna get paid
overtime for this, sir?
I'll give you this
picture of Elicia.
Ishbal.
Lior.
Mugear's mine in Xenotime.
They've all been destroyed
when they got close to it.
Why?
If this faction wants to motivate people
into making the Philosopher's Stone,
why would they cause so much destruction, starting
the rumor that anyone who gets close to it will die?
Is it because they wanted
to destroy all the evidence?
No.
That can't be.
It should be the opposite.
What if it's all opposite here?
Wait a minute.
Wasn't the original cause of the war
in Ishbal a soldier named... Douglas?
Why is that... familiar?
Excuse me, sir.
The Führer's
secretary is on the line.
Dr. Marcoh has
arrived in Central.
He'll be waiting
for you at the hotel.
Right.
Thanks for working so late.
I'll head over there now.
Douglas.
Juliet.
Sheska, put all those books back
exactly where you found them right now!
What?
As soon as you're finished,
I want you to go home.
And you're fired!
Never come here again!
Thanks again for
going to all this trouble.
Tell me, Miss Douglas, do you know
anything about the Ishbalan Rebellion?
No.
I've done office
work my entire career.
Yeah, the same goes for me.
I had to look some
stuff up recently.
Did you know the Rebellion was triggered by a
soldier who was posted there to keep the peace?
Apparently, she shot a helpless Ishbalan
child and it became their rallying cry.
Weird thing is, that soldier's
name was Juliet Douglas.
A common name,
Lieutenant Colonel.
Here's where it
really gets interesting.
According to a little article, the soldier with that name
died two years before the Ishbalan Rebellion started.
That is strange.
One more curious thing.
Although that soldier was reportedly
killed, the name Juliet Douglas was never
removed from the
military's active duty list.
In fact, that same soldier with the identical file and
matching ID number landed a big promotion two years ago.
She was selected to become
Führer Bradley's next secretary.
Who are you, actually?
Were you an Ishbal, or did you come later, using
the military's mistake to sneak in with her records?
The doctor's waiting for you.
Is Marcoh really
behind that door?
I guess I'll find out.
A pleasure to meet you.
Or should I make that
goodbye, Lieutenant Colonel?
That's one sexy tattoo
you got there, babe.
Run, sir!
Pretty good for a man, isn't he?
Come, sloth.
Let's make sure he's taught.
Lieutenant, the enemy's moved in
very close to the Führer, and they've
infiltrated the military deep enough
to effect large-scale decisions.
Their goal's not to create
the stone directly...... but...
Never mind.
Let's go.
Sir.
Dammit!
This is taking too much time!
What?!
What do you mean he's gone?!
He left for Central with
Lieutenant Hawkeye.
Is there something
the matter, sir?
Dammit, Roy, you're
acting stupid again!
With this information, you
could go straight to the top!
Lieutenant Colonel, we
should go somewhere safe.
Yeah, you're right.
It's not like I've lost
any evidence here.
But now there's something
I'd like to bring up with you.
Lieutenant Ross has a mole
right beneath her left eye.
Oh, is that so?
How careless of me.
Heh, that's an amazing talent.
I hope you'll forgive me, but I've got a
wife and kid waiting for me back home.
You're right Hughes, maybe
this is a more fitting end.
I'm going to become
the Führer, Maes.
I'll transform how this
whole country runs.
It's the only way I can
justify taking my next breath.
To do that, you're going to need someone
who understands you and the system,
and supports you
from the inside.
I'll work under you, stay close to the
higher-ups, and help push you to the top.
Mom, how come?
Why are they burying Daddy?
Who are those people?
Why are they burying him?
Why?
He's gone, baby.
They can't.
I don't like it.
Daddy said he had lots of work to do, and if
they bury him, he can't do it when he wakes up.
Elicia
Stop them, Mommy.
Daddy needs to do his work.
He told me.
Why are you burying
Daddy, Mommy?
Why?
Daddy, wake up!
We'll catch up, sir.
Killed in action.
And promoted two ranks for it.
Brigadier General Hughes.
You're the guy who was going to
work below me and push me to the top.
Then you get yourself killed
and pass me in the ranks.
I don't know what's more
absurd, you or the state.
Are you ready?
You know, years ago, I had a
theory on human transmutation.
After all we've seen, I was
actually trying to remember it now.
We Alchemists are such
hopeless, predictable things.
Why didn't he tell
me, Lieutenant?
Ed and Al in danger?
Lab Five?
Maybe I could have
done something to help.
Maybe because he
knew you'd try, sir.
What's that mean?
When those two boys are in harm's way, sir,
well, sometimes your decisions aren't exactly rational.
Maybe Brigadier General Hughes
didn't tell you because he wanted
you to concentrate on your
own goal instead of the Elric's.
So you could make it to the
top... without any more setbacks.
It's going to rain today.
Yes.
I guess that's what they
call a mother's touch.
I could eat this stuff all day.
That Mr. and Mrs. Hughes and their cute little
daughter Elicia, that had to be the perfect family.
Yeah.
Come on, perfect?
The guy's nosy and
obsessed with his kid.
He's annoying.
You like him.
He came to see us all the time.
Yet he's always complaining
about how busy he is.
I'm telling you, that big
goof doesn't make any sense.
Why do you think he cares
so much about us, though?
Seriously.
Beats me.
Really, Ed?
You'd better tell him thanks
when you get back to Central.
Ed...
Did you see something, brother?
No.
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 26 Her Reason
It never
really occurred to me until now
that all this time she could have
been thinking of me that way.