I heard you on my way in here.
You say you're an agent of God.
Well, then why don't you try passing
judgement on me?
That's Alex Louis Armstrong, the Strong
Arm Alchemist!
Don't pray just yet.
You're facing the technique
that's been passed down the
Armstrong line for generations.
That's hardly a blessing!
Next shot!
It's true what you said.
The opposite of creation is distraction,
and both must be served.
Destroy and create!
It's the grand currency of the universe,
and it's the charge of the Armstrong’s to
carry out both!
That's why I was going to track you down
once Full Metal and Crystal were finished.
A unique combination of alchemy and
physical power.
God help me.
If you have red irises, red eyes,
and brown skin, you must be from...
But the god your people kneel to forbids
alchemy.
It's modernity's greatest sin!
I see your rationale.
Alchemy has three parts.
Determine the makeup, then break it down
and rebuild it as something else.
You stop at step two, so you're
saved by a loophole, like
killing for a religious cause.
But murder's murder, and you're still an
alchemist!
I only do as this arm instructs me.
Contrary or not, leave it to the prophets
to interpret God's will!
Humankind cannot gain anything without
first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of equal value must
be lost.
That is alchemy's first law of equivalent
exchange.
In those days, we really believed that to
be the world's one and only truth.
The Ishbal Massacre.
Brother, what are we gonna do now?
I don't know, Al.
Let's just get some distance from that guy
with the glasses.
Get down!
Ma'am, have you got a back door?
What about Eastern Command and the
Colonel?
Yeah, there's no way we can get there.
With the Brigadier General showing up like
that, I get the sense not even Mustang can
protect Marcoh right now.
Oh, yeah.
All those people from Central are there.
Maybe you're right.
People from Central have been deployed
here?
Just the Fuhrer and his entourage,
yeah.
I don't understand.
Is this for me?
No, it's not like that.
Don't worry.
Too slow!
That's no fair!
Just catch me.
Lets play a new game, Priests and Dragons.
Yeah ok.
Too slow!
I can't do this.
I get to be the pocket watch.
I've run away
from it long enough.
I won't do it now.
I don't care if that man kills me.
This is the Village.
You go over there.
How can I, when it's something that I
deserve?
Wait for me!
Colonel, we found him!
Come on, talk to me, Major.
What happened?
Close call.
This is turning into a real mess.
That's a hell of an understatement.
What about Grand?
We found him on the road a few blocks up.
Let's just say there'll be some
promotions, unless Ironblood can survive
his brain turning into hamburger meat.
But he was the Brigadier General.
He was an expert in hand-to-hand,
right?
Scar's MO.
No doubt about it.
That man... he's an Ishbalan.
I'm sure of it.
I saw his red eyes.
Just stay down.
You're hurt.
I'm sorry, Lieutenant Colonel.
You sent me with direct orders.
And I failed.
I hope Elric is okay.
But the brown skin and the red eyes... I
know the man chasing him is from Ishbal.
I even confronted him about his God.
Well, well.
There's a decent break in the case,
Hughes.
Now you know why he's killing us.
I'm missing the connection.
Why do you deserve death just because he's
from Ishbal?
The rebellion, right?
Ed told me Mustang was sad about that too.
But why?
Ishbal started that
war for independence.
They lost lives, but so did the military.
If all of us fought for revenge every time
we lost a war, there'd be no end to it.
It'd be a cycle without a point.
You're not listening.
That was no war.
It was a massacre.
The people of Ishbal are an ethnic tribe
in the East.
They worship Ishbala as the one and only
creator.
They draw from a different history, so they
see the world through a different lens.
Our world is sulfur and nitrogen,
science and math.
We believe everything can be explained
with numbers.
An equivalent exchange is our sacred
canon.
But to them, alchemy is a perversion of
the world God has given us.
The devil's miracle, corrupting man by
putting us in Ishbala's place.
As a result of this collision of views,
resistance movements would pop up from
time to time.
Hey!
What'd you do that for?
One day during a house inspection,
an officer in the military accidentally
shot and killed a Ishbalan child.
The incident became a rallying cry.
Massive riots and uprisings broke out all
over the region.
It was too much, too fast.
The military couldn't control its soldiers
in the chaos.
More fuel for the fire.
It escalated into a full-scale rebellion
that lasted seven years.
Until the Fuhrer had had enough.
He sent in the problem-solvers,
the state alchemists.
Why?
Because of their doctrines, the Ishbalans
have neither alchemists nor up-to-date
weaponry.
Want them to demonize us even more?
You think that's a long-term answer?
Did you bring the materials?
I did, Colonel, but they're still under
research.
And like I told you, we don't need them.
Have you not seen the reports?
The resistance is growing.
That's because your excessive use of force
is creating sympathizers.
It's easier for the Ishbalans to recruit
the other tribes.
Hehehehe.
What are you trying to say?
That our Fuhrer's great cause is unjust?
We've lost several thousand men.
The civilian casualties are well beyond
that.
The whole country is unstable.
This isn't a humanitarian summit.
This is war.
Now turn them over, Crystal Alchemist.
That's an order.
Dominance in a bottle, men.
Alchemic augmentation.
It's my job to end this war quickly,
and with this, I can.
So what happened?
How did the Ishbalans respond to your
weapon?
They didn't.
What?
Every gathering point of resistance the
state alchemists were sent to.
They were all wiped out in a single night.
That's him!
Over here!
No more running, Colonel.
Take him down.
Sir.
My ankle.
Let me help you, son.
During the war, there were doctors who
would treat the wounded.
Didn't matter what side you're on,
Ishbalan of the state, if you were in
need of help, they would treat you.
How's that feel?
Thanks
I'm it.
However, they were casualties,
too.
Colonel Grand, what happened here?
This became an underground contact point
for Ishbalan insurgents.
These doctors were involved.
Involved?
They were treating them!
They were trying to save anyone they
could!
That's right.
And the ones they saved were coming back
to murder my soldiers.
Stop that!
You're a soldier following orders in a
time of war.
It's my soul that carries the sin.
These doctors gave everything in the name
of saving lives.
I mean well.
How can we ever make this bearable?
If I run away, will you keep quiet and let
me escape?
So I left with the Philosopher's Stones
and all the research that explained how to
create them.
But I acted much too late.
The people of Ishbal had largely been
exterminated.
I heard that our military let only a
handful survive.
It's grim, granted.
But that's no reason for him to come after
you.
He wants revenge.
What could be more legitimate?
He's dragging people in who had nothing to
do with it.
How can you talk about legitimacy?
He's a fraud.
He's on a tirade of personal vengeance,
and he hides behind this excuse of God's
will so he can claim it's noble.
Still, if someone took you away from me,
brother, I think I might do the same thing.
Isn't that equivalent exchange?
No!
That's not how the principle works.
Haven't you learned that yet?
Destroying lives doesn't bring lives back.
We all just need to live and be content
while we can.
Come here.
Dr. Marcoh, why don't you let us hide you
in our hometown for a while?
It's just three days on a train from here,
right?
It might be hard on us going back there,
though.
Not at all.
We have friends there, the Rockbells.
They make automail.
I'm sure they'll be...
Rockbell?
No, I can't.
I can't go there.
I'm sorry.
Dr. Marcoh, what...
Foolish troops.
Don't think you'll be spared.
You're all using weapons with alchemic
modifications.
God judges you!
That's far enough.
Colonel Mustang, wait!
Colonel Mustang?
Flame Alchemist Roy Mustang?
The one and only.
But, sir!
I'm awfully sorry about your grievances.
But no one hurts my men.
Yet another soul who departs from God's
path.
Death will be swift.
Brave enough to attack the Flame
Alchemist, I'll make you a funeral pyre.
Colonel!
Stubborn man!
That's no way to get promoted,
Hawkeye.
Relax, sir.
I just saved your life.
Your flame attack's no good in the rain.
She has a point, Colonel.
Wet gloves can't make a spark.
Fire!
He's certainly a fast one.
After him.
Now!
Lieutenant Breda, go to the train station.
Wait for fullmetal.
But how do you know he's going there?
Isn't it obvious?
He's shielding Dr. Marcoh.
He'll try to get him out.
Marcoh, wait!
It's your call.
We don't have to go anywhere you don't
trust.
We're not trying to steal your research.
No, Ed.
There are other reasons I can't go there
with you.
I'm a stained man.
This time I have an attack made just for
you!
By clasping
Al.
By clasping your hands, you make an array
with your body and circulate
the alchemic reaction within.
I know your secret, and without this
sinful arm you can't transmute quickly.
That is your weakness.
BROTHER!!!
No, brother!
Get up and run!
Get out of here!
I will give you a moment to pray.
Thanks for the gesture, but I don't
believe... Stopped a long time ago.
Back in the tunnel you told me you lost
your older brother.
Died in Ishbal, right?
Correct, Fullmetal.
He was killed by a State Alchemist.
Well, I'm the oldest brother.
So take my life and go.
That's an equivalent exchange,
don't you think?
No!
What are you talking about, brother?
You just said yourself that life doesn't
equal a life!
You stay out of this, Al!
I'm doing what's fair!
He's not a State Alchemist.
I should be enough!
I promise.
I promise before God I won't hurt your
brother.
But you should listen to him, Fullmetal.
Your life for another is not a fair
exchange.
There is nothing in this world that can
equal the loss of my brother and my people.
Nothing will make it easier to bear!
Really?
Then why are you murdering all these
people?
Brother,
what are you doing?
Get away from him!
Brother, run!
We're all we've got, remember?
We're all we've got!
I don't want this.
No!
Dr. Marcoh?
Don't you have any sense?
You should be long gone by now!
I investigated some ancient texts written
by your people in Ishbal.
I remember discovering the alchemic
drawing you have tattooed on your arm.
Maybe this has flaws, but it is a
philosopher's stone and sure enough your
arm is responding.
Don't say it!
You know nothing!
It's some kind of reaction.
Dr. Marko, what's going on?
Is there a different way of using the
stone?
Aaaaaaaaaaaaah!
The classic sewer escape.
Don't follow him.
Damn it, I was about to jump in.
Nice mess.
Is it over yet?
You know you can try to help while you're
here, Hughes.
Lay off!
I'm as normal as they come
and this is a contest of freaks.
What do you want me to do?
Fire my slingshot at him?
Lieutenant Hawkeye, take crowd control.
I don't want anyone getting close.
Yes, sir.
Say something, Al.
Are you still with me?
You idiot!
What's that for?
Why didn't you run away when I told you
to?
Because steal for brains,
then he would have killed you!
So you decided to die instead?
That's really smart.
Don't call your older brother an idiot,
idiot!
That's not how we do things.
Live and be content while we can.
Live to research more alchemy so one day
we can get our bodies back.
That is how we do things, brother.
Dying, and dying by yourself, and leaving
me on my own?
That's something I won't let you do.
Oh, this is perfect!
Now my arm's falling off, too!
Today is a terrible day!
We're really falling apart at the seams,
aren't we?
Everyone who sees us must think we're a
joke.
But we're alive, right?
Yeah, we are that, Al.
A hollow suit of armor.
We've never seen a soul transmutation that
actually worked.
Yeah, they must have risked their lives to
make it possible.
What do you think makes the bond between
those two so strong?
Colonel, the Fuhrer's secretary has
arrived.
Has she really?
And what does she want?
I have orders to take Marcoh into Fuhrer
Bradley's custody.
He assures you that the doctor will not
come to harm you.
What?
Yes, of course.
Marcoh, don't!
It's like I told you, Ed.
I can't go with you.
Your hometown is not a place where I could
ever be welcome.
Why not?
The two doctors that we executed in
Ishbal.
Their names were Rockbell.
Let's get going, sir.
Yeah.
Brother, I think I just heard Mom's voice.
Come on, Al.
You just had a brush with death.
Don't go unstable on me now.
Full Metal Alchemist.
Episode 16.
That which is lost.
Equivalent exchange.
Brother's arm and leg?
My body?
We lost them, but what have we gained?