What are you doing
calling me this late?
Well, there's something that's
been bothering me for a while.
What?
That we haven't caught Scar, or is this about
Dr. Marcoh being taken into the Fuhrer's custody?
Yeah, well, okay,
there's that too.
But mostly it's that I haven't
made an appearance lately.
What an egomaniac.
He doesn't realize
the mess we're in.
Maybe you should inform him.
Colonel Mustang could
be of some help here.
Hmm.
At least with the
Elric's disappearance.
He doesn't need to know that.
Not yet, right?
The soldier detachment I requested
to guard the library is standing by now.
They're all gifted marksmen.
Pretty damn useful in a raid.
Does that mean... It does.
On my own authorization, you three can
lead a full dive and sweep of Lab 5 at daybreak.
But you'd better be ready
to confront whatever you find.
Yes, sir!
It's the Bad Place!
I've been watching you, child.
The first time I caught a glimpse
of you was almost four years ago.
The sky was ablaze
with fireworks that night.
Who are you?
He called you a Homunculus.
But that can't be true.
Oh, really?
And why is that?
A Homunculus is an
artificially created person.
A human that's not human.
A living doll.
No one's ever successfully
made one before.
It's impossible.
Oh, it's very
possible, believe me.
It's no less possible than a boy who
has a soul, but not a body to go with it.
You really aren't
human, are you?
Oh, goody, can I eat him now?
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
I think I get it now.
What this facility
was being used for.
It was an operation to develop
large-scale military applications for alchemy.
Or more specifically, how they could harness
human alchemy to the military's advantage.
That explains what they were doing
with these incomplete philosopher's stones.
If you want to do you could use them
to forge a complete philosopher's stone.
Does that mean you know how
these fragments were made?
Not quite.
By the time I came this
room was already here.
Created and abandoned.
Most likely by the man who
had run this place before.
One Dr. Tim Marcoh.
I can only guess his methods.
They're made of... Edward, does it honestly
matter any more what it is they're made of?
Even if they were in fact
created using living human
beings, are you capable of
restoring them back to life?
Using what's left of them
to make a complete stone
is the only way to give
their sacrifices meaning.
I couldn't have
said it better myself!
You're agreeing?
Their lives have no value
in this disembodied state.
I sympathise.
But Al, your life has value.
Even in this state, doesn't it remain?
Well, you're all working
overtime, aren't you?
Fuhrer, I apologize
for the disturbance.
I know.
You're eager to get to the bottom
of this business at Laboratory Five.
I've heard rumors over the
years, but turned my blind eye to it.
I trusted Basque Grand had
the good of the state in mind.
However, if the lives of
those two young alchemists
could be jeopardized
by it, I can't stand idly by.
I'll let the Major command the exploratory
mission, and I'll personally accompany you.
You won't go it alone.
Yes, sir!
And where's the scarred man?
He fell into the Bad Place.
Really?
That's no big loss.
Greed may show up to put a
wrench in things at any moment.
We've gotta get Fullmetal
Boy to hurry up while we can.
Is this it?
Are we directly above
the array I made?
Behind that door is the
storage tank that feeds into
the room below with the
ingredients for the stone.
Okay, I can work with this.
I'll be right back.
Amazing.
After thousands of years of evolution, you human
beings remain as vile a creature as you ever were.
And who does he think he is?
Some kind of a high-up
military muckety-muck.
I find it absolutely adorable that
you believe everything you see.
But that thing is definitely not
the Brigadier General Grand.
You're going to transmute
both rooms at once?
That's the plan.
Even combined, there's not enough
pieces of the stone in this room alone.
In Dr. Marcoh's research journal, he
recommended using two transmutation circles.
I'm hoping to take all the leftover
materials from above and collide them with
the fragments in here through the
two circles, smashing them into one.
But I'm gonna need a serious
explosive charge to make all that happen.
I'd better beef up the array.
Heptagon circumscribed in it.
I've never seen that before.
Neither have I.
If this theory of mine
actually pans out, I'll give
Alice body back and we'll
get the hell out of here.
Then you people can do
whatever you want with the stone.
That's very generous
of you, Edward.
They can't do this.
We gotta get out of here!
Would you people
shut up already?
Ha, you can drop the monk
act and admit you're scared.
Even a head case like you
who killed his own men has
to realize he's helpless
in here, crimson alchemist.
You've been gossiping.
Yes, I did kill my men.
But do you know how?
Yeah, you blew them all to
hundreds of little bits with explosives.
Explosives?
I've never relied
on anything like that.
Did you know that even though the
human body is made mostly of water.
It's also comprised of
small metallic particles.
Intriguing, isn't it?
By reshaping them with basic
organic compounds, a skillful
alchemist can easily transmute
a person into a human bomb.
And, taking into account the abundance
of red water we're surrounded by,
the reaction will
be even greater.
Where are we?
[Multiple People Talking]
All these people... who are they?
Why didn't you tell me there
were other scientists still here?
Last I checked, scientists wore
lab coats, not prison clothes.
What are they doing here?
If I'd have performed that transmutation
without knowing, I would have...
Everybody listen up!
Who brought you here?
I did.
Fullmetal Alchemist.
I personally requested these criminals be
transferred here from the prison next door.
And what are you doing here?
What gave me away?
The Brigadier General
was killed by Scar.
I had a front row seat.
Who are you?
What's your name?
Well, that depends.
I can be whoever you want.
So who would you like,
Mr. Fullmetal Pipsqueak?
Huh?
Maybe a taller version of you?
My, my.
The determined little
Pipsqueak wants to start a fight.
But I don't know.
I'm really more of a pacifist.
You should stop
calling me a Pipsqueak.
It puts me in a really bad mood!
Just remember that you were the one
who started this sparring match, Pipsqueak.
Do you have any idea who you're
trying to pick a fight with here?
Huh?
The reason you're still around, the only reason
I haven't killed you, is that we were told not to.
But I can never forgive you.
And there'll never be a time
when I'm able to forgive you.
For carrying that bastard's
blood in your veins!
Envy.
Don't take it out on him because you failed
to screen the ingredients thoroughly enough.
I've seen you.
If you don't want to suffer
any more physical punishment,
then I suggest you get
on with the transmutation.
We've had a minor unexpected
setback, but the ingredients are still fresh.
You want me to use these convicts
to make a philosopher's stone?
Was that your plan?
You really think
I'd take their lives?
I think that you have no
choice in the matter, Edward.
AL!
Brother... these people...
they're... Homunculi!
Homunculi?
That is correct.
These people are
indeed Homunculi.
Perfectly created
artificial humans.
They've promised to provide me with
the secrets of generating a Homunculus,
so I can at last bring my
precious Nina back to life.
Why are you even trying to recreate your daughter's
body when you can't do the same for her soul?
But I already have her soul.
I keep it here.
My Nina's indomitable spirit
lives on in all my memories of her.
I can implant those in the mind of the
Homunculus, giving birth to a Nina even
more perfect than the
real one that inspired her.
Memory implants?
It still won't be the real Nina!
This pointless
chit-chat stops here.
So, Pipsqueak, why don't you shut up
and get to work on the transmutations now?
You can start by
fixing the ceiling.
I'm embarrassed to admit, but our group
is incapable of using alchemy on our own.
We have to rely on
others to do it for us.
If you can't use alchemy,
then what's the point?
What could you possibly do
with a philosopher's stone?
Same as Cornello, huh?
Let me guess.
You've got a god complex and a
desperate need for world domination.
I want to become a human.
Nothing more.
If you guys really are
Homunculi like you say, then
there must be an alchemist
somewhere who created you.
Why don't you get him to
do your dirty work for you?
We weren't created by anyone.
We were born.
Given our limitations, all we could do was leave
a trail of breadcrumbs pointing towards the stone.
And advise some eager alchemists on how to
go about constructing the stone for themselves.
Wait a second.
You mean you're the ones who showed
Mugear what to do with that red water in his mine?
And when Marcoh was working here in this lab,
you must have told him about the secret ingredient.
Not to mention Tucker's experiments and Cornello's
fake stone, which I guess you were behind, too.
We laid the fake bait, and sure enough,
every idiot interested in the stone came flocking.
And that's the way
we found you boys.
You found us.
Are you saying that me coming
here was part of your plan all along?
No.
Al and I started this journey three years
ago for our own reasons, of our own free will.
And we went through
hell to get here.
You're here because
that is what we wanted.
Al and I are nobody's puppets, not
the states, and definitely not yours!
It's an equivalent exchange.
I'm going to tell you everything you need
to know to make a Philosopher's Stone.
And in return, you are going to
use it to turn all of us into humans.
And why the hell
should I trust you guys?
Oh, but you misunderstand
me, Fullmetal.
We're not asking.
We're telling.
Do you have any idea what'll happen
to an attached soul when you do this?
Stop it!
You can't do that!
He's still a human being!
Edward Elric, I want you
This won't take long.
No!
Please don't hurt him!
He's my little brother!
Please don't take him away!
I'm begging you!
Ed!
It's okay.
What am I, after all?
What if you're a fake?
An imitation?
How would you
know the difference?
You see, it's something I've been
meaning to tell you for a long time now.
Don't give up on
me now, Al, okay?
[Envy Whistles]
Brother, no!
You can't do this!
It's not worth it!
Foolish child.
I should have sent him to his
maker when I had my chance.
That's it.
You can do it, kid.
I have faith.
This is crazy!
Quit doing this, brother!
Those people...
they're... they're human!
Yeah, and soon
you and I will be.
So what's your problem?
I don't want to get my old body back if it
means having to take someone else's life!
I thought for sure you and
your brother would have gotten
the message after your pathetic
attempt to bring back mommy.
You gotta spend
life to make life.
Come on, this is
basic alchemy here.
Don't kid yourself into thinking there's
some way around that, because there's not.
As they say, death is
the high cost of living.
In order to achieve anything in life, you
inevitably have to take it from someone else.
That is what any
honest adult knows.
But we're not adults!
When Edward decided to join
up with the State Alchemists,
he gave up all claims to
childhood in exchange for power.
So don't start behaving like a child
now, because you can't have it both ways.
I see now.
This is really the
truth behind all truths.
Huh?
I'm sorry.
I promised... that I'd get you
your body back, no matter what.
Sorry, Al.
But I just can't do it.
Ah!
Fullmetal Alchemist!
Huh?
Take your brother
and get out of here!
I don't need your help!
Maybe not, but your
younger brother needs you.
Let's go!
Oh no!
You aren't leaving until you
finish what you've started!
That's not good.
Even though it's unrefined, this much exposure
to the stone material could turn the boy into a god.
Come on.
The rear door is secure.
We're all set to go in.
We've got a blockade
around the whole perimeter.
Now listen up.
Our chief mission is to secure
the safety of the two young boys.
Apprehend anyone who
looks like civilian personnel.
And everyone else.
Mow them down.
Now move out.
This way, men!
Who's that?
Is that the Crimson Alchemist?
Fullmetal, sir!
The boy's Alchemic
power is multiplying rapidly.
Lieutenant, wait!
Good work, troops.
Fullmetal Alchemist.
Episode 23, Heart of Steel Brother, there's
something you've wanted to tell me for a long time.
And now, I want the truth.