I've never seen
an Ishbalan before.
I wonder what they're
doing in a place like this.
Looks like the state military
is escorting them somewhere.
This is taking forever.
Yeah, seems to be a real
problem with the water supply.
Hey, what the hell
happened here?
That should delay
the train for a while.
I can't believe our good luck stumbling
across these Ishbalans halfway through our trip.
Tell me, what'd you guys
do to get thrown in here?
We're innocent, okay?
Some troops took us by surprise
and packed us in here for no reason.
That's awful.
The way that the state treats you is dead
wrong, but you still should have seen this coming.
If you leave the camps,
they're gonna round you up.
Listen, we could really
use your people's help.
Scar told us a Philosopher's
Stone was made in Ishbal ages ago.
We're looking for someone
to fill us in on more details.
You guys were pretty
close to Scar, weren't you?
We aren't friends to
people like that guy.
You won't be getting
any information out of us.
None of us can help you.
But there's an elderly man living on the outskirts
of Kishua who probably has the answers you seek.
But... but Chief... These two young
men will take you to meet with him.
I don't want to go
to that place again!
Don't worry.
Look, we don't make
very good chaperones.
We have to exchange
something for the information.
We'll give these
kids their freedom.
Equivalent trade.
Though it's not one of our people's
philosophies, I admire its attempted balance.
We'll go, Chief.
Maybe I could give you
guys some heat relief, too.
Get those people off the train!
It's not safe in there!
Let's go.
Sorry.
Hey!
What are you doing?
Hey guys!
Need a ride?
Where'd you get that?
Did you steal it?
Of course I didn't!
They said I could
have it if I fixed it.
But I don't think they knew
they were dealing with me.
What the hell?
Let's get moving.
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Next stop, Kishua.
Straight ahead.
This is too easy.
She was great,
wasn't she, brother?
I need to know, Winry.
How much longer do
you plan on tagging along?
If it weren't for me,
you'd be captured now.
I had it under control!
That's not the point.
I don't want you
out here with us.
Then who would
fix up your Automail?
You break it about once a week.
I don't want you
here either, Winry.
We may have to
do some bad things.
I wanted to rip Ed's limbs
right off that Homunculus boy.
But I couldn't do
it in front of you.
Oh please, you wouldn't
have done it anyway.
I agree, Al couldn't do that.
But then, he doesn't need to.
Because I can and will.
Brother... I met someone one time, who thought
it was easy for humans to kill after they did it once.
Maybe it was inevitable,
but I did cross that line.
I killed an Alchemist
named Majhal.
That was an accident, brother.
You know it.
You were trying to save him.
But then at Lab Five, I came so
close to killing all those prisoners.
When it met a chance to return Al to his
body, their lives seemed like nothing to me.
But you couldn't
bring yourself to do it.
And now I'll face Scar.
And if he insists on holding me down,
the way that Greed did, I'll have to.
Cool.
You'll really kill him?
What are you saying?
He's a traitor.
It's okay to kill those guys.
Enough of this talk about death.
I've heard enough.
We need to keep
our heads about us.
Winry!
Still think I'm scared
of a little danger?
It looks like a
battlefield, doesn't it?
We've never seen a battle.
How would we know?
We have, both of us.
It's just like that day...
when Mom died.
The state military
surrounded our entire town.
We didn't do anything
wrong, but they didn't care.
They just started shooting!
Mom!
Rick!
Rick, stop it!
It's over now.
What's the matter?
I don't want to go.
I've seen it all before.
Fine.
Stay here.
Winry?
Pardon the intrusion.
Brother.
That marking... It's the same
as the tattoo on Scar's arm.
It was in the basement
of Laboratory Five, too.
All right, you two.
Come out peacefully.
What do you think you're doing?
You could have killed us!
You think missing
was an accident?
Well, if you knew it was us, why
did you shoot in the first place?
That shot was for the
bruise you gave Fury.
They'll be all right.
They know them.
Let's just wait here, okay?
Where's the Colonel?
He's gone back to Central,
with Warrant Officer Falman.
So he leaves you guys to clean up
his mess while he runs back home.
Sounds great.
Is that what this is
about, then, Edward?
The Colonel's actions
against the Ishbalans?
Is that why you
attacked the train?
It's more complex than that.
But you don't have to
suppress them, you know?
They weren't planning
on starting a war.
They just want
somewhere safe to live.
Don't misunderstand.
There wasn't any Ishbalan casualties after the
Colonel stepped in, and they were the ones who killed first.
Yoki, a former officer,
I think you knew him.
Yoki?
You mean that
buffoon from Youswell?
He was serving as an informant when
somebody from their side opened fire.
The mood was tense, and
his death took it over the edge.
But the Colonel stepped forward,
and with a controlled display of power,
he made a barrier and
took away their will to fight.
Had not acted so quickly, there would
have been untold casualties on both sides.
So even a soldier can keep things
innocent every once in a while.
You're dogging on the Colonel
just because he's military, Ed?
Don't forget,
you're a soldier too.
We've decided to transfer most of the
Ishbalans to the Southern Encampments.
But first we have to find the one responsible
for Yoki's death and give a fitting punishment.
To that end, we're holding
several here for interrogation.
There's an old man
with them, right?
The man you used to live in
the hut where you found us.
Security's pretty tight.
Do you think he's the shooter?
No, no.
The old man isn't
considered a suspect.
But we are protecting him.
From who?
Those are Ishbalan
prisoners, right?
They attacked the old man,
called him a heretic and an exile.
Seems he's even been banned
from being with his own people.
I don't believe it.
The Ishbalans have been
treated like outcasts for so long.
Now you're saying they're even
cutting themselves off from each other?
Why?
Exiles?
So what kind of
people are these exiles?
The filthy kind.
They're people who've
betrayed the laws of Ishbal.
That's why their
faces are marked.
So we'll all know what they are.
And what's their
betrayal exactly?
Just what did they do?
I guess I don't know
the exact details.
Yeah, our mom just told us
they didn't believe in Ishbala.
So that meant they couldn't
be with our people anymore.
But I can't believe he's
considered an exile, too.
Who is that?
The man you call Scar.
And he is one, okay?
He's a dirty traitor.
Can you tell me what
your mom was like?
She was the nicest mom ever.
And even though she couldn't see, she gave
all her time to help others up at the hospital.
Is that so?
The Philosopher Stone?
You know you're the third
person to ask me about that.
Really?
There was a
scarred man recently.
And many years ago the man's brother
came to me wanting to learn all about the stone.
I see.
And he was an Alchemist.
Then does that mean Scar's brother is the
one who created the Philosopher's Stone?
No, he didn't create it.
That young man was
far too gentle for the work.
But how do you know so much
about the Philosopher's Stone?
Aren't you an Ishbalan?
Yes.
But I am an exile.
Because I learned
the Grand Arcanum.
The Grand Arcanum?
What's that?
The great knowledge passed down through the
Ishbalan people in whispers and sacred rooms.
Through it, Ishbal prospered.
But the tides of
culture changed.
And it was labeled blasphemy.
Sealed.
And hidden away.
After that, those who practiced the art were exiled,
never allowed to return to the land in which they were born.
The Grand Arcanum gave us the power to
transform anything in the world to our own design.
And so it was declared to be an act
against God and it was made forbidden.
The Grand Arcanum is... Alchemy?
That can't be.
It's impossible.
You don't believe the Ishbalans.
Having no industrialized society and
living in the middle of the desert could.
possess such a
knowledge as Alchemy.
Is that what you think?
Well, you wouldn't be the first one to see
different eyes and skin and turn yourself away.
Who could possibly believe this other world
could have the same depth and spirit as you?
Then could you teach us too?
Your method of making
a Philosopher's Stone?
Yes, I could.
But I'm afraid there's very little
difference in theory between the Grand
Arcanum and your people's
method you've no doubt discovered.
The only variance is the
number of sacrifices required.
Number of sacrifices?
A fallen city or an entire
tribe lost to genocide.
Atrocities of war so horrific
all that remain are the graves.
Tens of thousands or hundreds
of thousands of misplaced souls.
In the hands of a skilled Alchemist
these lost souls are brought together,
forged into the
Philosopher's Stone.
Then you were right.
The theory is the same just
to a more gruesome degree.
It's hardly the answer
we're looking for.
Well, can you tell
us where Scar is?
He said he was on his
way to create a stone.
Why would you tell
my brother that heresy?
He was desperate.
He just wanted to bring
back the woman he loved.
But you told him all of Ishbal
would have to die for that to happen.
Then the war came and my brother
blamed himself like he'd brought it all upon us.
For all I know, he did.
He's in here!
Look!
Don't do it!
You make it!
The horrors keep repeating.
Will the Ishbalan people never receive
the peace that they were promised?
Unless I forge a power
greater than the Military's.
The Philosopher's Stone.
So, then will you
too become an exile?
I'm already an exile, old man.
The lives of tens of thousands
of people lie trapped in this arm.
An exile?
You can't be.
You can't!
Even in the darkest of
suffering, a man can sleep.
But for the man who inflicts the
suffering, his mind cannot rest.
Ever.
Then from this day forth,
I'll never sleep again.
Don't let us see your face
again, you stinking exile!
Really?
Are you sure they
were the Rockbells?
We're sure.
The lady doctor was really scary when she was
mad, but she gave us treats and stuff all the time.
They helped all the wounded the same,
whether they were Ishbalans or soldiers.
Mom was so sad when
she told us they'd been killed.
You're telling me it was really a
state Alchemist who killed them?
Yeah, I heard it was an
Alchemist whose power was fire.
And somebody praised
him for what he did.
Mom was crying a lot.
What's wrong?
That's weird.
The flesh around the
wound isn't burned at all.
You're right.
And the exit wounds for most projectiles
are larger than the entrance wounds.
Not here.
You know what I'm
thinking, brother?
There's a lieutenant colonel named
Archer you might want to talk to.
He's been after a Homunculus.
A Homunculus?
Their bodies are fluid.
One can turn her fingers into
daggers in the blink of an eye.
They can make those wounds.
Go tell Lieutenant Colonel Archer and
Major Armstrong to redirect their investigation.
This wasn't done by an Ishbalan.
Well, I suppose I can't take the opinions
of a famous State Alchemist lightly, can I?
Stop struggling!
Huh?
Uh, Winry?
Rick, Leo, listen to me.
I've managed to get
you guys acquitted.
You're no longer in any trouble and the rest of
your people will be released from this station too.
But they're still going to
send you back to the camps.
If you two want, you
can go live in Resembool.
I got permission.
No thanks.
We'll go to the
camp with the others.
Your call.
And where are you off to now?
We're going after Scar.
If we don't, something
really bad will happen.
Will you kill him?
Why would I?
Because he's an exile, a
filthy traitor and he deserves it!
We'll make sure he doesn't
cause any more damage.
But because we're both Alchemists,
or no, because we're both human,
I don't want to kill
him or anybody else.
I've decided that.
Don't feed me that!
I know you all hate Ishbalans!
Are you scared?
Why should I be?
Well, there's something
that's had me afraid.
Your red eyes.
The first time I saw Scar on those
library steps, I was scared of him.
He was the first
Ishbalan I'd ever seen.
But now, well, I've learned that you
can't always trust the way that you feel.
And you can't trust everything you've
heard about people like me either.
From your mom and your dad.
Because even they can be wrong.
That's why we've all got
to find our own answers.
Slowly.
Over time.
So what about you, Winry?
Where are you headed now?
I'm going back to Central.
And if it's alright with Lieutenant Hawkeye,
I'd like to go back with her to see Mr.
and Mrs. Hughes and Elicia.
Right.
Winry, when did you decide this?
Let's see.
Guess we'll try Ishbal first.
I hope Scar hasn't created
his Philosopher's Stone yet.
Yeah, feels strange to say that.
Since the stone's
what we're looking for.
Guess this is the ignition.
Lieutenant?
You can call me Riza.
I was just wondering, have
you ever shot anyone before?
When I had to.
To keep the peace.
Did you know a pair of doctors?
The Rockbells?
Yes.
I don't know what you've been told, but
there are times when a soldier has to take a life.
Even when he doesn't
understand why.
The orders may not even
make any sense at all.
That's the way it is when you're a soldier,
and it can be a stupid and terrible life.
If you hate it, why
don't you get out?
Because there's
someone I have to protect.
And it's not a burden
someone forced on me.
It's a decision I made for myself, and I
take full responsibility any time I fire a round.
But he's the reason
I squeeze the trigger.
And I won't ever hesitate to do it
until the day he accomplishes his goal.
But how can you be certain?
What if he isn't
worth protecting?
That's another call I
have to make for myself.
This is WWrath.
Our number seven.
Wrath, ooh!
Pleased to meet you, Wrath.
I want you to go after
Fullmetal and his brother again.
Affect them.
I thought you said we
shouldn't count on them.
That they didn't have the
constitution to make a stone.
And yet they are headed
to Ishbal as we speak.
Really?
If they discover what really happened there, any chance we
do have of them creating a stone will permanently dissolve.
Not to mention the blow to
our mobility if the truth got out.
Then... can I eat them?
Perhaps.
If worse comes to worse, we might
just need to get rid of them altogether.
I'm sorry.
I had no idea all
this had happened.
I will push him to the top.
That's what he would always say.
That he would support Roy
Mustang until he became the Führer.
Is that so?
He really seemed
happy to help his friend.
It can't... It can't be...
Fullmetal Alchemist
EPISODE 37 The Flame Alchemist, The Bachelor
Lieutenant, and the Mystery of Warehouse 13
What's the Colonel up to.