Father, you've come home!
Mind your volume, please, Selim.
For you.
Go ahead and open it.
All right.
Oh wow!
Thank you, Father.
It's not every day a young man turns ten,
my son.
Where are we?
We're at my master's house.
What?
You mean the one who's forced you all to
search for the Philosopher's Stone?
I wouldn't say forced.
It's more like we're obliged to help in
return for the master's generosity and care.
If you think any of this is for your
benefit, you're wrong.
Listen, kid, you don't have to tell me
that.
I don't?
Of course not.
I'm well aware that this serves the master
and the master only.
But to tell you the truth, I don't really
care.
Just seeing all the human suffering makes
it worthwhile.
Hey, hey, you're carrying precious cargo.
So try not to overdo it.
I hate you!
Do you have any clue how many people Scar
had to kill to create the Philosopher's Stone?
Of all the soldiers that invaded Lior,
7,000 never made it home.
But don't fret.
They're right in here.
Oh, I bet you didn't even realize all the souls of the
Ishbalans that were sealed in Scar's arm are inside you now.
Isn't that great?
So now that you're fully aware of just how
valuable you are to us, I suggest you be...have!
There's so many moments when I should have
died.
Time... after
time... after time...
But I survived.
And for what?
Why do I deserve to live when so many
others have died?
The Philosopher's Stone.
Those who possess it, no longer bound by
the laws of equivalent exchange and alchemy.
They gain without sacrifice, create
without equal exchange.
We searched for it.
And we found it.
It's Edward.
Took you long enough.
Sorry.
So this is the place?
Yep, this is it.
Let me see that letter again, would you?
A number of years ago, my father wanted to
learn how to make red water.
So he came to Central.
When he got here, he managed to work his
way into a place called Laboratory Five.
There, he became acquainted with a certain
gifted Alchemist.
It wasn't long before this man began to
share his secrets, like how to transmute
red water into the Philosopher's Stone by
using human lives, as well as the secret
location of what was to be referred to by
insiders as the True Laboratory.
From the sound of his note, it seems like
we've just scratched the surface.
Secret as Lab Five was, it's still a front
for something deeper.
And there's no time like the present to
find out if he was telling the truth.
I'm going alone.
But if Al's in danger down there, maybe
we can use our alchemy to help you save him.
Oh, don't worry.
I'm gonna get him out of there alive,
no matter what.
Edward.
Huh?
I just want to be clear about something.
I didn't tell you all this so you could
create the Stone.
Trust me, Russell.
That's the last thing I would ever plan on
doing.
Not anymore.
Just come back.
JUST COME BACK ALIVE!
According to my father's writings,
if you enter this hidden temple and
journey far below Central, you'll find a
city buried beneath it.
Not long after Father arrived,
he began to hear bizarre rumors about a
city that once stood where Central stands
today.
But four centuries ago, it had somehow
mysteriously vanished in one night,
along with all of its inhabitants.
At first, Father chalked it up to local
folklore, but as he became more entrenched
in the secret happenings of Laboratory
Five, he soon found out that these.
seemingly ridiculous stories were,
in fact...
True.
They were all sacrificed for the
Philosopher's Stone.
Then all evidence of their existence was
erased.
Using alchemy, the city was pulled underground,
leaving nothing behind but a rumor to fuel the curious.
Only monsters could come up with such a
plan.
Are you in here, Dad?
You did this!
You came up with the whole plan,
didn't you?
Tell me!!!!
No gluttony.
You've had lunch.
Why must I always remind him that you're
too important to eat?
Exquisite.
No wonder Edward loves you so much.
He does, you know.
And you love him, too.
Will someone tell me what happened to my
lust?
I don't know.
Maybe she's Lust.
Now we must make sure to wear our finest
dresses.
I want everything to be perfect for him.
He's here.
My, my.
Sooner than I thought.
Wrath: Where is he?
What now?
Tell me, please!
Get off of me!
I need the Philosopher's Stone!
What's he doing here?
I clearly told you I wanted Wrath to keep
an eye on Edward.
Please, give it to me!
It's not my fault he can't follow orders.
Please, Master, I need the Stone now!
Wrath, if you can't behave properly,
you'll have to remain a Homunculus.
There's no time!
My mommy!
Mommy's gonna die!
Mommy?
I don't know.
I think he's talking about Sloth.
Don't be ridiculous.
Sloth isn't your mother.
Homunculi do not have mothers.
Understood?
Save her, please!
I need her!
You're not a human, Wrath.
Stop acting like one.
Mommy!
Envy?
Please!
Don't even think about it.
Now come here.
No wonder that Elric brat enjoys using his
Automail so much.
The amount of power it supplies is
absolutely exhilarating.
That's precisely why I hate the military.
Because of power-hungry, blood-sucking
filth like you.
For the last time.
Give up this
foolishness and join me and my men.
We will soon be waging a war in all
directions, ushering in a new era of domination.
You can still be a part of it.
I'd rather rot in hell.
Permission granted.
Your students will soon follow.
You fools!
I'm your superior!
You'll regret this!
Izumi!
Edward.
Ed must be the temple now.
Don't tell me you've risked your careers.
On the word of kids.
Those children hold the state's future.
It's our duty to enable them.
At least that's what Hughes used to say.
Rose..
Edward.
I've been waiting for you.
Honestly, Din, how many times do I have
to tell you crawfish aren't for you to play with?
Why do you insist on always learning
things the hard way?
Is something wrong?
Not really.
I just realized something.
What is it?
Before Hughes died, he always used to say
that nothing is ever completely negative.
At the time, I wasn't sure what he meant.
But you're sure now?
I used to believe the Homunculi were evil because they
did unspeakable things just to find the Philosopher's Stone.
But I'm starting to think maybe I was
wrong.
We've seen what humans do with power.
We might use the stone as a weapon and create
tragedies even worse than the Homunculi have.
But they take it away right after
it's made and destroy anyone
who is near it, starting rumors
of danger about the stone.
So this rumor makes people think... You're
a little too scared to go searching for it, right?
But do you realize what I'm saying,
Winry?
Those monsters might actually be doing
mankind a favor!
Maybe not.
Sometimes danger can add an element of
excitement.
And that could make people want to go
after it even more.
So, do you think Ed and Al are all right?
Of course they are, silly.
There's not a doubt in my mind.
You know, Winry?
You make a good point.
But for humanity's sake, I hope you're
wrong.
Uh, Rose?
What are you doing here?
I've been waiting.
For you.
For us.
Edward, I love you.
You do?
Look, Rose, I don't think you realize what
you just said to me.
We're just friends.
My baby.
You couldn't give her one little dance?
Seeing as how she's been waiting here for
you ever since she came into hiding.
You're despicable.
Lyra
why'd you bring Rose to this place?
Before Dante died, she told me about a
city that only old Alchemists knew about.
It sounded safe.
I know you said before that Dante had been
murdered, but you were awfully vague.
You never told me who did it or why.
That Homunculus named Greed killed her.
I could have sworn I told you that.
You're lying to me.
Am I?
The transmutation circle in Dante's mansion was
designed specifically to drain a Homunculi's power.
And the human remains that were Greed's
weakness were laid out in the same room.
Even if he wanted to, Greed couldn't have
made a move against her.
That's all very interesting.
But I saw her corpse with my own eyes.
That proves nothing except that the body she
was squatting in could no longer serve its purpose.
What?
Let's say the Philosopher's Stone could be
used to jump from one body to another.
That would make a human capable of living
for hundreds of years.
I think Dante faked her death and used the
stone to take over a younger body.
A body like yours would be just the right
fit.
Edward, stop it!
It's not true!
That was too close.
When did you see the gate?
That's the only way you could transmute
without a circle.
And Lyra couldn't do that before.
Your secret's up, Dante.
When did you find out, fair son of
Hohenheim?
So it's all true.
Indeed.
Every last word.
So how many times have you jumped bodies?
Well, in four hundred years you can lose
count.
It's less than ten.
After all, I had to use the Philosopher's
Stone each time.
And that's what happened to this city.
Lives for the stone.
Don't forget the fabled Lust civilization
in the East.
It was the same.
But I'm not the one who made it happen.
No, it was Hohenheim of Light.
You say it so formally.
Why don't you just call him Dad?
Did he live this way too?
Stealing bodies, creating wars?
And for what purpose?
Because we were worth it.
What the hell's that supposed to mean?
You ruined thousands of lives to create
each Philosopher's Stone.
Then you take it for yourself so you can
live longer.
And you actually think that's justified?
Humans can't handle the stone.
Right.
So you have the mercy to take it from
them.
The grace to kill anyone who was involved.
So only the legend remains.
I'm glad you understand so well.
Humans are controlled by their sins.
And the Philosopher's Stone has power far
greater than any weapon ever forged.
So I've taken cities.
Humans would destroy the world.
The lives Lust have been necessary
martyrs, saving mankind from itself.
I am the Guardian.
The Shepherd of Sins.
I have to live on to prevent you humans
from doing something foolish with the stone.
Don't kid yourself!
You're a human just like us!
Not anymore.
Lust!
Where are you?
You're breaking my heart, Edward.
Talking to me this way.
I was looking forward to taking her body
and being loved by the son of Hohenheim.
So it's Rose this time, huh?
Yes.
I have to celebrate the newly born stone.
What have you done with Al?
No, no!
What have you done with Lust?
Why don't you ask him, gluttony?
Where's my Lust?
Where's Lust?
Look I'm sorry, but she's gone.
Not gone?
Yeah.
Wrath killed her.
She died trying to help me.
Gluttony, stop this.
I can't.
You don't have feelings.
Lust.
Let's do it!
I knew it.
Your soul can't sustain bodies anymore.
It's been attached too many times.
Equivalent exchange.
Every time you jump, you lose part of
yourself.
Equivalence?
Don't tell me you still believe in that
naive theory.
It's no theory.
It's the absolute law of alchemy.
No, of the whole world.
To obtain anything, something of equal
value must be Lost.
You couldn't have gotten anywhere without
knowing that.
A beautiful story.
Told to comfort the oppressed and make
children do their lessons.
The truth is, the law of equivalent
exchange is a lie.
Impossible!
To gain something of equal value must be
Lost.
Conversely, if you give something up, you
will always gain a prize of equal worth in return.
Exactly.
That's why people work hard at anything
they do.
Because it pays off.
Wrong.
People work because they believe it will
pay.
But equal effort does not always mean
equal gain.
Like what?
Consider the state alchemy exam which you
passed with flying colors.
How many others took the test that day?
Spent months, years preparing.
Some working much harder than you.
Yet you were the only one who passed.
Where was their reward?
Is it their fault they lacked your natural
talent?
Or what about the equal value of each
person's life?
If I just clap my hands, this baby won't
survive.
Stop it!
And if I do it, where is the world's
balance in that?
Does it mean the baby was only born so
that it could die?
It's doing all an infant can to survive.
Breathing, crying for help.
But what does it get in exchange?
People can say there is a balance, a
logic that everything happens for a reason.
But the truth is far less designed.
No matter how hard you work, when you die,
you die.
Some spend their entire life trying to scratch
their way to the top and still die in poverty.
While others are born into wealth without
ever working at all.
It's a cruel and random world,
and yet the chaos is all so beautiful.
That's enough, Dante!
My baby!
Equivalent exchange is a myth, a contrived
order to give sense to a world that has none.
Can you accept that now, or do you need
another demonstration?
Don't use a child to fuel your agenda!
Your dad said that too.
Hello?
Where am I?
Oh, my head feels like it's been put
through a...
What?
Okay...
That's odd.
Are those sirens?
Edward, quick!
It's an air raid.
We have to go now.
Come on!
Wait!
What the hell's going on here,
old man?
What is this place?
Where are we?
Wait, what?
Edward, you're not sounding like yourself.
Funny, I don't really feel like myself
either.
And what is this city?
What's happened to my body?
Did Dante do this?
Transmute.
Does that word mean anything to you?
Of course it does!
But how did you get here?
Yeah, good question!
We'll talk later.
What's attacking?
Zeppelins!
Zepp-what?!
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 50.
Death.