A simple rock, red as blood, which
promised to turn pain into delight,
war into victory,
and death into life.
It was a thinking person's
dream, reason conquering all.
And it was in deference to this that
it was called the Philosopher's Stone.
How could this be possible?
I don't know.
After all this time, years of searching,
sacrificing, and this is the answer we get?
The secret ingredient to make a Philosopher's
Stone the only way to make it work?
Live humans and in mass numbers?
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Major, please!
Will you wait a minute?
Major Armstrong!
It's just the boys
seem exhausted, sir.
They've had a long day.
Maybe we shouldn't
disturb them right now.
Tired, you say?
Then I'll have to take them
to dinner in the mess hall.
Nothing like food in the
stomach to energize the mind.
No, uh, sir, actually, I think they've
already gone to sleep for the night.
Why don't I just tell them that you came
by when they wake up in the morning?
Very well, Lieutenant.
I guess we do want
those boys to get their rest.
God must really hate
people who go against him.
I was 11 years old then,
and he still has me marked.
Every time I thought I was in reach,
he's pulled it away, so I'd fall on my face.
And then, when I finally
got my fist around it, he
raises his big, obnoxious
foot and kicks me in the teeth.
Just face it, Al.
It's gonna be this
way our whole lives.
Don't say that.
I really thought it was
gonna work out, brother.
We would find the Philosopher's
Stone and it would all be okay.
It still will be.
We'll find the Stone, brother.
We will.
And we'll get our
bodies back to normal.
And be happy.
People say you're
a dog of the military.
That you sold your
soul to get this far.
But that isn't true.
And it didn't stop us.
And this won't either.
We've worked too hard.
Brother?
Let's look at it again.
From the beginning.
I've looked at it enough.
But there's a chance
we misread something.
Maybe we got it wrong.
I said I've had enough.
But what if our code's wrong?
Maybe that's not what it says.
Or maybe we missed
some key paragraph.
Like a loophole or something.
We should read the
whole thing again.
I said enough!
Brother?
Is something wrong, sir?
It's just a broken cup.
Back in the hall.
Sorry, Al.
Yeah.
So, Ed.
That's really the end of it?
You won't regret it, then?
Giving up before
you're finished?
That's interesting.
I didn't realize what you were searching for
was so incidental you'd abandon it this easily.
Stop going on like you know
what you're talking about.
You don't know anything.
Wrong, Ed.
I know that what you boys have been
searching for is the Philosopher's Stone.
And I know it's created
by sacrificing human lives.
...
I know it was uncalled for, but I
was listening through the door.
Well, if you eavesdropped,
then you must know.
It's pointless to
chase after it now.
Leave us alone.
You really are a
child, aren't you?
You're frightened of it.
That all the answers
will disappear.
You're terrified you might have to admit
that everything you've done was wasted effort.
Am I wrong?
It's okay to feel lost
and not have reasons.
Verifying whether Marcoh's research is
the truth or not is worth something in itself,
if you ask me.
After all, what you're looking
for is a lot bigger than you or Al.
Why don't you try searching a little longer,
Ed, but without worries about the final result?
You're right.
It's like a book.
Just because you're mad and stop
reading doesn't change the way it ends.
That's right.
We've had roadblocks and
we've conquered them all.
I'll be damned if
we stop halfway.
We'll take this all
the way to the finish.
Let's do this, Al!
Right!
Dr. Marcoh's research is sound in theory,
but even with the inclusion of humans in
the forging process, it still never
made a perfect Philosopher's Stone.
So there still might
be other methods.
Right.
But let's check
his method first.
I want to see the truth
of it with my own eyes.
Wait a second...
Truth...
Bottom of the page,
like an afterthought.
The genuine
truth... behind truth...
Of course!
He was saying there's
still something more!
According to his data, it takes huge
refining equipment to create a stone.
You'd need a massive
facility, like a whole complex!
Well, there are currently four alchemic
laboratories running under the military's watch.
They're all pretty big.
I know Dr. Marcoh was
assigned here, at the third lab.
No, I already went to all four labs in the city
and there wasn't anything remarkable going on.
Just a lot of
fast-talking bureaucrats.
Hey, what about this?
Oh, right.
There used to be a fifth lab,
but they closed it down years ago.
It's just an abandoned
building now.
Apparently there were structural
problems, so they made it off-limits.
That's it.
Look.
There's a prison
right next door.
So they had a spacious
lot of federal land.
What are you getting at?
If people are the key ingredient in a
philosopher's stone, doesn't it make sense
to put a lab in a place with a
convenient state-controlled supply?
You don't mean
they use the convicts?
Why not?
You couldn't have
a cleaner plan.
Take condemned prisoners, say they're
executed, then use them for experiments.
Who was running this laboratory?
Lab 5.
That would be
Brigadier General Grand.
And he was killed by Scar,
as you're obviously aware.
What do you think?
There's no choice.
What do you say we go
check it out ourselves, Al?
Sure.
Now just hold on a minute.
From here out, this
is grown-ups' work.
Besides, as long as Scar is
loose, you're a walking target.
You can't afford to
stroll around Central.
Yeah?
So what?
Let Bloch and me be
your eyes on the ground.
We'll go to Lab 5 and see if
anything's out of the ordinary.
If we see anything,
we'll give you a full report.
It's our duty.
She has a point.
All right.
I clearly can't argue with you.
You guys can take care of it.
Sir, it's the right choice.
Okay, Lieutenant Colonel.
I'm done writing down the
court record for case 3263.
Can I please go home now?
Great.
Glad you're done.
Yeah, you mind
holding for a minute?
All right, Sheska.
Let's keep that ball rolling.
Case number 9572, please.
They're going to be using that in court
tomorrow, so let's make that a rush job.
Yes, sir.
What's wrong?
You need an energy boost?
No!
That's not necessary!
Look!
This is the special little swimsuit
edition with Mommy's hat on!
Isn't she the most adorable
angel you've seen in all existence?
One look at her happy face
and all fatigue just flies away!
Doesn't it?
yes
That's what I said!
She's a natural born healer!
A shaman of sunshine!
What's going on there?
So, have you found Scar's body?
Not yet?
Okay.
Well, don't forget
about the securiy.
for the library.
Send them tonight.
Hmm?
Oh.
Oh, yeah.
She's a real miracle worker.
I definitely owe Ed one
for introducing me to her.
Are those tripwire alarms?
Yep.
For an abandoned facility,
the security sure is tight.
It keeps getting
more suspicious.
Come on.
Let's try the back.
Al, boost!
Up you go!
I hate to say it, but you
can't fight convenience.
It's times like these I'm glad not to have
an arm and leg made of flesh and blood.
Same here.
The little barricade.
Yeah.
We'll have to find a
more creative way in.
Hey!
Up there!
Looks like it goes
all the way in.
All right, Al.
You wait here.
Will you be okay by yourself?
Okay or not, it's
our only choice here.
We're not going to get your
big metal body through this vent.
Sit tight.
I'll be back in a bit.
You know it's not
my fault I'm big.
Lieutenant Maria Ross.
I need to speak with
Major Armstrong, please.
What is it Lieutenant?
Sorry, sir, but there's
something I need to tell you about.
Hey
Contact Command!
Tell them we need
reinforcements!
ASAP!
Yes, sir!
You are not my
concern, foot soldier.
The Full Metal.
Where is he?
You two stay here.
The rest of you, move
to the other stairs.
He's going to Ed's room.
So, Full Metal, now you
understand the truth as well.
Scar!
Freeze!
Damn.
Lieutenant, look!
What about Ed and Al?
Where are they?
Here's a good clue.
Damn those two.
The town of Lior has
been handled tightly.
Just a harmless
spot in the sand now.
There's no one left who
knew anything useful.
Beautiful work, Envy.
We're glad to have
you back in our midst.
Things are going well here, too.
But what about
this runt, Full Metal?
I've heard he's
gotten wind of the lab.
Don't you think we
should take care of him?
Before he tells the
military our secret?
I'll kill them!
Let me!
Please!
Be patient.
I've watched them for a long time,
and I still think they could grant our wish.
We can always kill
them after that, can't we?
I don't care what you do with them, Lust, as
long as they don't mess up our precious plans.
Although I do think it's unlikely that
they'll get past those Funhouse guards.
No one ever does.
I gave them direct orders not to lay a
hand on the boys, but that ensures nothing.
They are idiots, after all.
If it starts looking like too much
trouble, we'll have to kill them all.
I know that.
Damn it.
This is smaller than I thought.
See, if I was normal sized, I wouldn't have
fit, and we would have had to call this off.
It really is a good
thing I'm so small.
No, it's not!
Lights are still on.
How do they explain that when they
say they don't use this place anymore?
Just running up
the bill for fun?
The hell was that?
For them to go to all this
trouble, they must have
something here they
really don't want to be seen.
I'm getting excited.
I just love being right.
[Evil laughing]
At last!
Where are you going?
We're under orders not
to lay a hand on them.
Orders?
I don't care about orders.
This one's all for me.
I'm going to drain out their marrow.
Wait.
There are two in our
quarry, and two of us.
You can't monopolize
the pleasure.
You know, for a lifeless ball
of rock, it sure is persistent!
Oh, no!
See?
And all this time I thought being
normal-sized would be a good thing.
Dammit!
Enough is enough!
Finally, a nice basic door.
Nice of you to come.
Graciously, do I
welcome you here.
You don't look too
welcoming with that sword.
I have been entrusted
with guarding these grounds.
For now, you may
call me Number Forty-eight.
Forty-eight.
Catchy.
It's been silent for too long.
I'm pleased to face
someone capable again.
But your luck has run
out running into me.
Do not think ill of me, child.
And you don't think ill of me for
being the child who defeated you.
How about a little
blade-on-blade?
It's sure taking a while.
What could he be doing?
Aaaaaah!
Nice.
You move well for a big thing.
Who are you?
Oooh, so demanding.
I guess I should answer.
I'm Number Sixty-Six, though
that's just what they call me at work.
Number Sixty-Six?
Yes.
I have a proper name, too.
But if I told you, you'd be so
shocked you'd wet yourself.
I'll tell you when
I'm peeling your skin.
As guardian, you must
know this place pretty well.
I've got a question for you.
Defeat me.
Then I'll talk.
Hmph.
Now, let's see how good you are!
Quick!
Auto-mail up to the shoulder.
Perfect!
My sword can even
cut through steel!
I hope you're kidding, pal.
If I break this arm again, there's
a girl who's gonna wring my neck!
That's Ed's.
Whoppsie.
[Fighting Sounds]
Those reflexes.
Why, you!
Curious child?
An anchoring seal.
Bodiless armor.
He's just like Al.
Episode 20, Soul
of the Guardian.
We've cried some, laughed
a lot, even seen hell together.
How could all of my
memories be fake?