I see.
Now I understand you, Elric.
You crossed the line.
You did what is strictly forbidden.
You tried to create human life and
your bodies were taken to the other side.
You were crazy enough
to find out for yourself.
You are the Fullmetal.
The Fullmetal Alchemist!
Well, that does answer a riddle.
Why the military would give a pup like you
such a stern name, Fullmetal.
But it's literal.
See, Rose, alchemists forbid their own
from transforming lead into gold.
But there's one practice more taboo.
A technique forbidden
by man and nature itself.
Alchemy.
On human souls.
You miserable little boys.
Dabbling in human alchemy
without knowing its penalty.
You stepped on the toes of God!
You don't know the story.
Al.
But we just wanted...
We just wanted to see Mom's face again.
See her smile.
But you failed, didn't you?
Yeah.
I'd label that a failure, all right.
Al lost his whole body
and I lost an arm and a leg.
I ignored every signpost because I
was reckless and I wanted it bad enough.
Rose, this is what happens when
you try to bring back what's dead.
You really want to go through with that?
Don't let them worry you, Rose.
You forget that the great sun god Leto
has blessed me with the philosopher's stone.
Besides, I have far more experience than
these heretic boys did.
Don't be stupid.
No matter what kind of powers
you have, some things can't be done.
Oh, then why are you so
anxious to get this stone?
You want to beat the laws of equivalence
just as I do and bring your mommy back.
Wrong, holy man.
All we want is to get
our bodies normal again.
See, we don't lie about what's possible.
We didn't start a cult.
ERRRRRRR
We will ask one more time.
Please give us the stone.
You are damned, state alchemist.
May the wrath of god fall upon your head.
Stop hiding behind that crap.
Get down here and I'll
show you some wrath.
Sinners!
PEW! PEW! PEW! PEW! PEW! PEW! PEW!
[Snickering]
ERRR
Close call.
Father Cornello!
Huh?
You!
Al!
This way!
Idiots!
You're running into a dead end!
Like I always say, if you can't
find a door, make your own!
After them!
Now!
Father?
Is it true what they said?
That ring you're wearing, are
your miracles just alchemy?
Just because you can explain a thing
doesn't mean it's not the will of god, Rose.
What matters is that I have been given
the power to do things that no one else can.
Let me show you.
Rose.
Cain!
The sun god's rewarded
you for your faith, Rose.
Your true love soul has been resurrected.
But the work is not finished yet.
His body still needs a few more days.
I always believed it.
This really has been the work of god.
If Ed knew...
Why do they treat us like we're evil?
If we really wanted the stone at all cost,
we would have taken it by now.
People of Lior, this evening a pair of
unbelievers tried to take the life of the
great prophet Cornello.
One short and blonde,
the other wearing armor.
Father Cornello asks you
all to stay in your homes.
Damien, I'll tell you what I'll do.
They found him on Goma Street.
Please, take all necessary precautions.
No question, guys.
They're the ones.
The short newcomer and his tin man.
Who are you calling a
mousy little pipsqueak?
Nobody said that.
Now back off.
We got more important business to settle.
What kind of depraved souls are you?
How could you go after the prophet?
We welcomed you here.
You made us believe you were good.
Look lady, I never asked you to believe
anything.
That's your priest.
He's a phony.
He's just using alchemy.
Liar!
Just now, my boyfriend spoke to me.
Cornello's bringing him back.
You mean old cain
we lost in the accident?
He was a good kid.
Good for you rose.
There, you see?
He's not the first either.
There've been many others who've come
back.
She's right.
Yeah.
That's not a miracle.
Tell me what is.
Has anyone actually seen
these people close up?
Cause I heard they all left town
as soon as they were brought back.
Look!
Another one!
A sun god statue!
You wanna call him a phony now?
Yes.
Al!
Give that back!
So this is the official pocket watch of
the state alchemist.
Never seen one close.
It's the reason you can do alchemy
without a transmutation circle, isn't it?
It amplifies all of your work.
I think you'll be quite
harmless without it.
MUHAHAHAHAHA
HAHAHAHAHAHA
HAHAHAHAHA!
How could I sleep after last night?
Where's the... bell?
Great, you came to feed me.
And I thought you were mad.
I hope he's real, Rose.
I just don't want you to get disappointed.
The real secret behind that
philosopher's stone stays between us.
Right, love?
Sorry, Cain.
I know you're healing.
But I just needed to talk.
So much has happened and I'm confused.
Rose?
I'm sorry, father.
I shouldn't have taken
the key without asking.
I just needed to see.
Oh!
What's wrong, Rose?
You got your wish.
I'm afraid that even with the
stone, I couldn't forge a human soul.
I had to use the
souls of these birds.
You know, they can be quite
adept at mimicking the human voice.
You shouldn't have
acted against me, Rose.
You've fallen out of the Sun God's favor.
Give the real Cain my best.
Rose!
Rooose!
There's only one soul left who
knows the secret of the stone.
But not for long.
I guess I don't need to
tell you it's dangerous here.
Come on.
This little charade of yours
will be found out soon enough.
The faithful are not likely to distinguish
between alchemy and the works of God.
Really.
As long as I'm bringing them happiness,
what do they care where it comes from?
Right.
So what's in it for you, besides all the
kowtowing?
It's alchemy's basic principle.
To obtain, you have to give up something
of equal value.
People say Ed's a prodigy, but that's just
because he paid with enough effort.
But how did you survive those statues?
Easy, really.
Ed handled it.
The two of you really have
paid a hefty price, haven't you?
An arm and a leg.
A body.
And yet here you are
now, trying to get it all back.
What about your mom?
What happened to her?
I should get started.
It's about time.
What?
Is it the money you're after?
Edward?
Oh, I can get all the money I want from
the offerings.
But you think too small.
I'm making believers who would gladly
throw away their very lives in my name.
And why not?
They believe I can resurrect them.
They aren't afraid to die.
There is no greater army
than those with a holy call.
Mark my words.
In a few years, I'll have a following
large enough to tear this country apart
and rebuild it in my name!
Makes no difference to me.
What?
After all, there's no real way to bring
people back to life, right?
Once you cut me down, I'm gone for good.
I'm afraid that's right.
Even with a Philosopher's Stone,
I wouldn't dare try human alchemy.
I'd end up like you.
And why would a king risk his life for the
sake of his mindless pawns?
Wait a second...
Gee...
WHAT!
How long has that thing been on?
Long enough for the mindless pawns tearing
this country apart comment, I think.
How did you get my broadcasting equipment?
Al rigged it up.
I know, you smashed him into pieces.
But that was just some metal I whipped up
to look like him.
Pretty clever, huh?
No, my children, he lies!
Don't believe him!
Oh, and by the way, I don't get
my skills from a pocket watch.
Father, that broadcast,
I don't understand.
Tell us what's going on.
My children, the non-believer has used his
science to impersonate me.
It is a conspiracy of the devil!
But witness as the great Leto
redeems me with his vengeful light!
Behold God's power!
That has to be a miracle!
What else could it be?
I'm warning you, give it up.
You didn't fool me with that little
display down there.
Without this, the only alchemy you
can perform is to your own metal arm.
Know what?
You're not the only one who can't stand
doubters preach.
Here's the real Hammer of God!
I don't believe it
Not even the philosopher's stone
can move something as big as that.
Rings and watches
have nothing to do with it.
My brother's the Fullmetal alchemist.
AAAAAAAHHHHHHH!
No!
I wont let you have it.
You can't take the stone!
What the?
It's recoiling.
An imitation?
After all this... all the trouble you put
me through... even the stones are fake?
Stop jerking me AROOOOOUND!
Just another wild goose chase.
And here I thought we could
finally put you back in the flesh again.
No, brother.
You'll be the first we fix.
That automail's so tough on you.
Nothing left to do but
start the search again.
You should never have come here!
Huh?
Father Cornello gave us hope.
What right did you have to take that away?
With him, we believed we could do
anything, even bring back the dead.
We're a desert village!
We had nothing before that!
You're saying we should have
just let everything go on as it was?
Well, why not?
What do I have to live for now
that I know Cain won't come back?
You tell me that, Ed!
You'll have to decide for yourself.
Walk on your own.
Move forward.
You've got a good,
strong pair of legs, Rose.
You should get up and use them.
Brother was trying to help you.
He just doesn't always
handle things well.
Just go away, would you?
You can still believe in hope,
Rose.
I still do.
AHH What's going on here?
That damn boy was right!
The ring you gave me wasn't the real
Philosopher's Stone!
Of course not.
This village is nothing but a juicy bait.
As rumors spread, real
alchemists who've searched
for the stone all their
lives will come to me.
And then...
Cursed souls!
Who are you really?
What are you after?
Come on, Lust.
Isn't it time you let me
eat the old preacher?
[Wet macaroni noises]
Where'd that miserable preach run off to?
Rotten fake.
I can't believe we were duped.
What do you think that's about?
I don't know.
Something messed
up's been going on here.
Father Cornello?
A miracle.
How do you know it's not another trick?
You don't trick things to life.
It seems the devil has worked his
wickedness while I was gone away.
But I'm glad that you're all safe.
I knew it, Cornello.
I knew someone who gave us
so many joys couldn't be bad.
Good, Envy.
I'm sorry, but we'll have to ask you
to keep that form for a little while.
Long live Cornello!
Before we go, Rose, listen to me.
My brother and I have seen all sorts
of things over our years of searching.
And I need to tell you about them.
So you don't repeat our mistakes.
We were born and raised in a small
village east of Central named Resembool.
That's where it all began.
Hahahaha
mom, look mom, look
What you got there?
See?
Brother made it.
Isn't it awesome?
I can still only do this one.
Well, I think they're both gorgeous.
You two really are his kids, all right.
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Fulmetal Alchemist.
Episode Three, Mother.
What I remember most were her lullabies.
For Ed, it was her stew, even
though I thought it just tasted like milk.
We loved her more than anything,
and that's why we had to try.