Oh, that was close!
Hi, mind if I come in?
Oh, that's so..
Ooh, nice place you got here.
Gross!
I know I can't feel you in
there, but this is so creepy!
Get out!
Oh no, I like it in here.
Just because you're inside of me
doesn't mean you can control me!
I'm still stronger than you!
Oh, don't worry.
I don't expect to match
you in strength, big guy.
I'm just trying to slow down
your movements a little bit.
And that's my cue.
You okay, Marta?
Just a little headache.
You're going to come
with us now, Mr. Elric.
The boss wants to meet you.
It'd be a pain in the
ass if you followed us.
So maybe I should just
break one of your legs off, huh?
Let's go.
No, wait!
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Where are they?
Alphonse was kidnapped shortly
after they came to my estate.
And young Edward has gone
after the kidnappers, I'm afraid.
And you just let
him go all alone?
The kidnappers dropped this.
In my garden.
The Devil's Nest.
Yes, a pub on the
outskirts of town.
You truly love those
boys, don't you?
I hope you don't have
anything to do with this.
If I did, do you think I would
have had them taken from here?
Outside this forest, in the real world,
how can you expect to protect them?
The Blaze of conflict is fed by malice, and
it consumes all that it comes in contact with.
And it will smolder until people
put an end to all of this fighting.
Not everyone sees the world the
way you do, from your secluded hilltop.
Some of us live in it.
As long as those boys seek the Philosopher's Stone,
their paths will be lined with misfortune, and death.
Why haven't you stopped them?
I have my beliefs, but they have to
find their own answers within themselves.
No matter what that answer is, it will
be different from the one you gave me.
And that will be enough.
So, I see you still
disagree with me.
And I always will.
We're very different, you and I.
Our lives and our alchemy.
You're going after them?
Yes.
Farewell, then, Izumi.
I doubt the two of
us will meet again.
Sorry about this.
I know how creepy this has to be, but I'm supposed to
keep an eye on you, so you'll have to bear with me a while.
It's alright, I'm
already used to it.
Just be careful about
my blood seal, okay?
If you accidentally
touch it, I could die.
Hey, how'd you guys get
to be Chimeras anyway?
Well, all of us were
serving in the military.
We were stationed in
the east on assignments.
Some were injured, others... well,
let's just say we weren't useful anymore.
They took us somewhere.
For experiments.
Laboratory Five?
That's right.
Greed.
He saved us from that damn place and
offered all of us jobs, working for him if we wanted.
Greed?
He took us out of the cages and gave
us something we could all call home.
That's right, guys.
See, this place is hand-crafted for outlaws, where people
who don't fit in on the outside can hide out for a while.
Tucker?
Tucker!
Why are you here?
Don't misunderstand, Al.
I'm not here by
choice, I promise.
If things don't go as planned, the doctor
here is the only one who can cure us.
Chimeras.
I'll be damned.
Just like you said,
Dr. Tucker, it really is empty.
But... but I'm not the one who
told them how to apprehend you Al.
It's a treat to meet you, kid.
You can just call me Greed.
I'm your new friend.
A tattoo of the Ouroboros.
So you know what that is.
Well, this should
go quickly, then.
That makes you a friend of Envy,
Lust, and the Others, doesn't it?
I wouldn't say friends.
More like sworn enemies, if
you want to get down to the grit.
I don't get it.
Well, Al, that is
your name, right?
Tell me, how does it feel to have
your soul attached to this empty armor?
To exist as a chunk of solid metal
rather than a soft and cushy human worm.
In other words, completely unaffected by
weaknesses like hunger, fatigue, and old age.
You could call that
eternal life, couldn't you?
Eternal life?
That's why you kidnapped me?
They don't call me
Greed for nothing.
I want money.
I want women.
Status.
And power.
I want everything this world's
selling, and eternities topping the list.
Do you understand?
You can help me achieve
what I'm going for, Al.
And you will help me here.
Because if you don't tell me how your soul's
bound to that armor, I'll break it apart to find out.
I won't help you.
You're a bad person.
You can act tough
for a while if you insist.
Just remember that nobody's
on their way to save you, kiddo.
So you're at my mercy now.
My brother knows you took me.
I bet he's on his way right now.
Oh yeah, about him.
When I left him, he
wasn't feeling so good.
You better not
have hurt my brother.
You let your guard down.
Now, all I need to do is use this
chain to... To do what, exactly?
Now that was silly.
Oh, sorry about that, Marta.
I forgot you were keeping house.
I like a man with guts.
But did you honestly
think it'd be that easy?
I mean, if you really want to hurt me,
you have to do something kind of like...
What'd you do that for?
I thought he was your friend!
See I've got quite
a shell too, Al.
Hey, bud, a little
cleaner next time, Kay?
Yes, sir.
I'm sorry.
I know what you're thinking.
If I have this body, then why
do I need your secret, friend?
Brother!
Excuse me for the
interruption, gentlemen.
T-teacher!
I'm sorry.
Who the hell are you?
Pissed off!
Edward Elric.
You're looking for
your brother, aren't you?
Have you been following me?
I bet you saw Al get
kidnapped and just sat there!
We, too, are
following these people.
Your brother's safety is not our
first priority at this time, Edward.
Yeah, I bet it's not!
The military is preparing to
raid the Chimaera Sanctuary.
We believe that your
brother is with them.
Where is it?
Tell me!
A pub called the Devil's Nest.
Hey, hey, hey.
Nice manners.
I can see where
the boy learned his.
Are you the one
who's in charge here?
Thank you for taking
care of Al for a while.
But I'll be taking him home now.
I'm afraid that's not true.
I see.
Well, you're just
full of surprises.
Tell me.
Did you break
three fingers or four?
Teacher!
That's a pretty weird
body you've got there.
I suppose.
I never did bruise very easily.
Oh.
Well, I'll just have to
start trying harder, then.
Teacher, where's my brother?
Is he safe?
I should be asking you that.
Apparently the two of you can't
even run a simple errand for me.
You're both in for a long lecture
later, so you better get ready!
I'm sorry!
No Transmutation circle.
Not even gonna try?
I have no intention
of fighting a Woman.
All I want from him is the
secret of his Transmutation.
Simple as that.
And if you get it?
Why, then I'll have the secret to eternal
life and the world will be on a platter.
This is getting us nowhere.
You did it!
Don't look so surprised.
I told you before I
don't bruise easily.
Don't you listen, doll?
Sig, no.
Yes, I've had my
fill of doing nothing.
It's just I...
I can't watch.
As more babies
are taken from me.
I can't.
No.
Gimme a break.
Are you still up for more?
Grrrr!
Izumi!
Teacher!
Oh, I guess you've been pushing
yourself a little hard there, huh?
Well, are we done
playing games now?
This sort of business
isn't my style.
But if you don't cooperate,
I won't have a choice.
Get your filthy hands off her!
Hurry!
Squad Five, block the rear exit.
Squad Seven, take
the area around the bar.
The rest of you, come with me.
Now it's the older brother, huh?
Looks like everyone's here.
Tucker.
Edward.
You too?
You messed up.
First you take my brother,
now you hurt my teacher, too.
Come on.
All you have to do is tell me how to
transmute a soul into an object and... Shut up!
Put my teacher
down and let Al go!
Now!
Careful, brother.
He's a Homunculus
like the others.
Hey, listen.
- I see. I've got
a hostage here.
- No wonder. Is everyone
forgetting about that?
Come on.
Isn't anybody paying
attention here?
Hello?
Teacher!
Edward!
Here!
You just don't get it.
I told you both, I am
the ultimate shield.
Teacher!
Izumi!
Hold it.
Let's do this man to man.
Keep her safe from me, okay?
Yes.
I hope you're ready for me to
fight back this time, Mr. Elric.
Don't worry!
I'm always ready
when I'm...pissed!
We've completed
preparations at the back.
The alley is completely blocked.
We're ready to move in.
Not good enough!
You know, you and your brother
are being completely dense here.
How's that?
Well, as two cunning boys who
have so diligently pursued their goals,
how can you not
be understanding?
When somebody like me
simply wants to pursue his own.
Our goals are completely
different from yours!
You think so?
Homunculus or Human, we're all
really the same now, wouldn't you say?
I mean, we all live to chase after our
own goals and to hell with everyone else.
Not us!
Oh, come on.
You're looking for the
Philosopher's Stone, right?
I don't care about the
Philosopher's Stone!
All I care about is returning my little
brother to the body he was born with!
But he's far better off staying
in the body he's got now.
What the hell do you know?
Not everyone's like you!
I didn't come here to negotiate.
If all you Homunculi are mistakes created
by Alchemists, the results of their sins,
well, then an Alchemist should be
responsible for correcting those mistakes,
starting right now!
Huh.
All right.
I didn't want to have to show
you this since it does get a bit ugly.
But since you're getting all serious
on me, then I'll get serious too.
What the.....
This is my real form.
Come and get it!
Didn't even hurt.
You're lying!
My body's structure and
composition are completely unaltered.
So you are the ultimate shield.
You've never killed
anyone, have you, kid?
What's that got to do with it?
I'm saying you
lack the guts to kill.
You'll never beat me like that.
And you'll never beat
the other Homunculi either.
So I'll help you
find the guts now.
By showing you some of your own.
Damn it!
Hey.
Greed!
The military!
They're here!
So what now?
Well, damn it.
Those bastards went
and ruined our fight.
Well, hell, boss.
Don't sound worried or anything.
Play it cool.
There's no one in the military
who can do us any harm.
Kimbley?
Bastard.
You've betrayed us, haven't you?
It's time to move.
Greed, let's go.
No!
Wait!
See ya, kid.
It's been fun.
You're not going anywhere.
What is this?
Please don't resist, Mr. Elric.
Resist?
What are you talking?
Lieutenant Commander
Archer is asking for you.
Please come with us.
Those criminals just ran
off with my brother again.
And you expect...
I'm afraid this is an order.
Fullmetal Alchemist
Episode 34 Theory of Avarice.
This time I have
only one goal in mind.
To defeat greed.
There are some sins
that cannot be forgiven.