Roy Mustang Surveillance Log?
What's this about?
You got me.
I've been ordered by Internal
Affairs to keep an eye on the Colonel.
To assist with our ongoing investigation
of Colonel Mustang, we order you to
confidentially report back to us
with surveillance of his every move.
You mean, you've
been spying on Mustang?
Yeah, but this surveillance
gig's too big for one man.
So if any of you
want in on the action...
Hmm...
Saturday, 0946 hours.
With papers waiting for his approval and due by
noon, the Colonel decided to take a nap instead.
1026 hours.
The Colonel attempted to
feed Lieutenant Hawkeye's dog.
The dog was not biting.
At 1103 hours, he started
obsessively cleaning the windows.
Still no progress on those papers,
with the deadline fast approaching.
Then, at 1147 hours, the Colonel began
to furiously sign the papers, all the while
cursing that he didn't
have time for this.
In the afternoon, Mustang
left to research a hot tip.
During that time, he received an envelope
from the young woman at the flower shop.
The letter appeared to be instructions for a
rendezvous, as it contained two tickets for a play.
That night, Colonel Mustang claimed to be
going on an overnight exploratory mission and left.
But judging by the look on
his face, I think he's got a date.
Wait, the girl from
the flower shop?
You don't mean
Grace, not my Grace!
I thought she was just
playing hard to get with me!
If she's seeing two guys at
once, she can't be that hard to get.
In a head-to-head with Mustang
over a girl, you're screwed.
I'm sorry, but there's no
way she'd pick you over him.
Shut up, you jerks!
They don't
understand my feelings.
I really thought this was love.
Damn, Havoc, is that a
surveillance log or a diary?
You take that back, loser!
Look who's talking!
What?
Yes, I love a good fight!
Come on, guys.
Lay down your
pencils and make up.
That's it, I'm through!
I can't take this
stupid investigation!
Ah!
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
Here at Central Headquarters,
there was a band of brave soldiers,
all willing to make that
sacrifice in the name of peace.
This is a tale of
love and courage.
A tale of the Flame Alchemist,
Colonel Mustang, and his loyal team.
Hey.
You know what, Black Hayate?
You don't know how
good you've got it.
No worries, no
friends to betray you.
Does anyone know what's
eating Lieutenant Havoc?
He probably got dumped again.
He's psychic!
It's hard balancing this
job and a relationship.
You have no time, and good luck
meeting someone worthwhile here.
Please.
A man should be able to handle
both his job and his women.
I do.
Yeah, that's his problem.
Hey, wait.
Grief affects his
performance, which affects me.
Hey, when do you guys
find a girl for Havoc?
Huh?
But I'm a highly
trained officer!
I can't find a girl for me!
Just toss him one
of yours, Colonel.
What's that?
Uh, nothing.
Nothing.
I don't guess any of you know what
he's looking for in a woman, do you?
Well, when we were drinking, he mentioned
wanting a cute, smart, funny girl with a
good personality who
wasn't likely to cheat on him.
Right.
Fallman, scour the city for a cute,
smart, funny girl with a good personality
and introduce her to Havoc.
You want me to what?
You heard me.
That's your new mission.
A mission?
For me?
I need all the records pertaining
to Brigadier General Grand, Dr.
Marcoh, and Shou Tucker.
And include any documents regarding
Laboratory Five or the second execution ground.
Yes, sir.
But what about the ones that
were destroyed in the library fire?
Of course I want them, too.
That's why I've
come to you, Sheska.
If I can use this assignment to gain
access to the military court, maybe I can
find out what Hughes was
investigating when he died.
So what do you say?
Yes, sir.
I accept the mission.
Some mission?
They didn't cover picking
up women and basic training.
Where am I
supposed to find a girl?
That hurt.
I'm so sorry.
Are you okay?
Sheska?
Oh, Fallman.
Nice running into you.
Have you been well?
Um, yeah.
Something like that.
Hold on.
You're a girl.
I'm looking for a cute, smart,
funny girl with a good personality.
Know where I could
find someone like that?
Hold on a minute.
Are you somehow suggesting you think I am not a
cute, smart, funny girl with a good personality, officer?
Oh, no.
I didn't mean it like that.
It's all quite silly.
Colonel Mustang ordered me to
find a girlfriend for Lieutenant Havok.
Oh, it's for Havok?
Yeah.
So you have any ideas?
Look no further.
I know the perfect woman.
Armstrong's sister?
You're kidding, right?
No.
He says she's single because she's
shy, not because she's not good looking.
It's so big.
All right.
I'm going home.
Are you out of
your freaking mind?
You've hit the mother
lode with this one, Havok.
You just have to convince her to
marry you and you're set for life.
You'll fly up the
ranks in no time.
Marry her?
But I don't even know her yet.
Well, according to Major Armstrong, she's
every bit as beautiful as the Major himself.
You mean she looks
just like the Major?
Get your damn
hands off me, guys.
I'm going home.
Ah, here at last.
Welcome to our home,
Lieutenant Havok.
We've been expecting you.
Bye, don't blow it.
For the past 180 some odd years, the
House of Armstrong has played a vital
role in the nation's financial,
political, and military circles.
Generation after generation, we've remained
pillars of strength and beacons of integrity.
We've supplied the country
with countless Generals.
Why, I myself was a General back in
the day when that meant something.
We didn't have motor cars... Oh, father's
stories always touch me in a profound way.
Oh, my.
I hope he's not boring our
poor guest with old war stories.
Oh, hello, Mother.
Mother?
That's a relief.
The mother looks pretty normal.
She's a freakin' giant!
That's not normal!
That's not normal at all!
Think about it
rationally, Havok.
If the father's large horizontally and
the mother is large vertically, then it only
makes sense, mathematically speaking, that when
you combine them, the sun would end up looking like this.
Which, uh, which means
the daughter must look like, uh...
Won't you come frolic with me
through the flowers, Lieutenant Havok?
No, that's not how it works.
Some traits are more dominant.
So there is the possibility if you cross
A with B, it could resemble A more.
Here she comes, Lieutenant.
My baby sister.
Come now, Catherine.
Don't be bashful.
You know it's not
an attractive quality.
Moment of truth.
Does she look like
her dad or her mom?
Either way, she's a monster.
But if she's gotta be a potato or
tomato, please let her be a tomato!
Um, hi.
It's nice to meet
you, Lieutenant.
I'm Catherine L.
Armstrong.
Jackpot!
I told Foreman she was beautiful,
and doesn't she look like me?
How so?
The Armstrong eyelashes.
Oh, yes, of course.
Where are your
manners, Catherine?
Let's not be shy.
Hi, again.
So, uh, what do you,
what do you do for fun?
Well, um, I'm pretty
good on the piano.
Aw, she's so cute.
She can't possibly be
related to the Major.
Or should I say I'm pretty
good under the piano.
Hmm.
Something wrong, Lieutenant?
Forget what I said.
She is 100% the Major's sister.
But wait.
If I look past her freakish strength
and focus on what matters, her looks,
her sense of fashion, her
estate, her lineage, it all adds up.
I suppose I... I really
have hit the mother lode!
Miss Catherine.
Yes?
You'd make me a happy man if you would
allow me the privilege of taking you on a date.
Huh?
Lieutenant Havoc?
Yes.
In my dreams, I've always imagined meeting a man just like
you, except with a more muscular physique like my brother's.
I'm sorry.
It's just that I only
like good-looking men.
Maybe we should forget
this ever happened.
Guess it wasn't meant to be.
Hmm.
Should I inform the cook?
Ten thousand says
he blows the date.
I say they don't even have one.
My money's on him chickening
out before he even sees her.
You realize you're all
bidding against him.
Safest bet!
That's it.
I'll just die alone.
Well, it looks like Major Armstrong is
turning out to be exactly the man I thought.
Lieutenant Hawkeye,
let's track this tiger.
Right.
Oh, man.
I'm starving.
I haven't been able to afford a decent
meal since I lost my money in that bet.
And I've been stuffing
my face silly ever since.
Take pity and feed me!
Then the bet wouldn't
mean anything, now would it?
Hmm.
They still haven't
fixed these lights?
I know.
It's pretty creepy
around here at night.
Of course, I don't buy the
haunted warehouse rumors.
What is that?
I don't know.
It's here!!
Stop that.
Oh, you're so bad.
That tickles.
Wait.
Now sit.
Shake.
Other paw.
Down.
Good.
Good morning, Lieutenant.
As you were.
Are you serious?
As a heart attack.
Those rumors aren't rumors.
They're true.
Stop.
Why are you telling me this?
I'm not going to be able
to walk home tonight.
Something happen to you boys?
They claim to have seen
the fabled warehouse 13.
Idiots.
There's nothing idiotic
about being aware Colonel.
Especially when there's a
bunch of ghosts out there.
A warehouse 13, huh?
I'm pretty sure that according to the records,
the military has only 12 warehouses here.
There may only be 12 now,
but sometimes a 13th appears.
They say this warehouse shows up on the old
execution grounds where thousands have been killed.
When the sun goes down and darkness
falls, the haunted building mysteriously rises
from the blood-soaked soil.
And you can hear the ghosts of the
executed clawing their way to the surface.
Slash.
They climb over the corpses of fellow
victims seeking vengeance against soldiers.
Did you ever stop to think that it's because you live
in this state of fear that you imagine seeing things?
Your minds are
playing tricks on you.
Doesn't anything scare you, sir?
Of course not.
I'm a trained
Alchemist after all.
We look at things in a rational manner
and there's nothing rational about ghost stories.
But we saw it with our own
eyes, and we aren't the only ones.
I've heard stories
all over headquarters.
What is this?
A children's slumber party?
You superstitious nitwits need someone to
give you a reality check, and it might as well be me.
Wow!
Really, boss?
Did you hear that, guys?
The colonel's volunteered to
help us with our midnight stakeout!
He's a noble leader, always
looking out for his men.
What a relief.
If the colonel's with us,
there's no way we'll be impaled.
Now wait a minute.
What stakeout?
Our mission is to prove whether
or not Warehouse 13 is real.
And you said you would
give us a reality check.
Well, yeah, that's what I said, but... I have to go by there
every night on my way home, and it's eating away at my
insides, and soon
there'll be nothing left.
Please, colonel, help me.
Damn it!
Still don't see why I have to tag along
on their stupid little midnight ghost hunt.
Because they admire
you more than you realize.
What good is admiration
from other men?
They're soldiers.
How are they going to deal with living,
breathing people when they're afraid of the dead?
I didn't tell you to
stop here, lieutenant.
You looked like you
wanted me to, sir.
Oh, Colonel Mustang.
What a surprise.
I'm sorry for dropping
by unannounced.
I was just in the
neighborhood, so... Nonsense.
I appreciate you
taking the time.
Elicia, you remember
Roy Mustang.
Say hello.
Hiya, kiddo.
You've grown.
I'm sorry.
She's just a little shy.
But please, come in.
No, I better not.
I have tons of paperwork.
I'll be seeing you.
Like I was saying, it's always a
lot scarier dealing with the living.
Give me a ghost
to talk to any day.
So this is absolutely
everything.
You left nothing out.
No miscellaneous documents
that Hughes had lying around.
No, that's it.
Very well.
Have all of these
files incinerated.
Scatter the ashes.
Uh, what?
But these are official records.
They're one of a kind.
I don't care.
Laboratory Five has
been closed for years.
I'd hardly expect there to be
much documentation these days.
There is more to it, sir.
Don't you find it odd that there are absolutely no
records at all from the years when the lab was operational?
That's about someone
neglecting their work.
But that someone was Boss Grand.
What exactly are you implying?
People don't Bury nickel, sir.
They Bury gold.
It suggests Grand discovered
something valuable enough to cover up.
Of course, I can't imagine that you would
have had any pre-existing knowledge of
this breach, Führer.
But think of it.
A humanoid chimera.
A Philosopher's Stone
that amplifies Alchemy.
I don't have to tell you that these could
be powerful weapons in our arsenal.
And I don't have to tell you those are
forbidden practices, Lieutenant Colonel.
Scientific progress
is trial and error.
Neglecting to learn from
past experiments, or forbidding
research because it's immoral,
is not only myopic, but reckless.
I have Kimbley and
Shou Tucker under my control.
Ready to be
unleashed at any time.
I'm just waiting for
your command, sir.
Apparently, another civil
war has broken out in Lior.
We also have reports that
Scar may be hiding there.
Sound like a problem that you
and your friends could solve?
Yes.
This is ridiculous.
Five grown men trying to sneak a
peek at a ghost on their night off.
By ridiculous, you mean scary.
Well, it means a lot to us,
you coming out, Colonel.
Let's just hurry so I can sleep.
Oh, yeah.
Did we forget to tell you that the
lights are out from this point on?
What the hell has the
maintenance staff been doing?
And Breda said,
let there be light.
It's just a shadow, moron.
Yeah, calm down.
These shadows can
be your friends, Fury.
Look, I have a
cute little puppy dog.
Stop freaking out!
What for you to say?
Well, stop jumping when
things stop being scary.
I want to go home.
How did I get such
a pathetic staff?
Come on, I'll prove to you
there's no such thing as ghosts.
Don't leave us alone, Colonel!
This, ladies, is the twelfth
and final warehouse.
And over there is
nothing but open space.
So where is your phantom
13th warehouse?
Maybe it's a Warehouse, like a
Werewolf, and it needs a full Moon.
Give it up, Fury.
Hold on, I think I know what
you guys saw the other night.
Take a look over there.
Hmm?
That letter B.
Doesn't that look an awful
lot like... The number 13.
I guess I see how you
can make that mistake.
So you misread it thanks to
the darkness and your own fears.
I guess that's better
than the alternative.
I told you it was a figment
of your own imagination.
But then what about the ghosts?
They don't exist either, Fury.
Oh, good.
Whew, starting tomorrow night I
can take my normal route home.
And we're all happy for you.
Can we go now?
You know, now that my nausea's
settling down, I'm getting kinda hungry.
Yeah, I could go for some grub.
Dinner's on you guys.
What?
But I'm broke!
Consider it
payment for causing this trouble.
Hold up.
What's wrong?
You see that?
See what?
The dirt.
It looks like it's
been dug through.
That doesn't sound good.
Fallman.
Yes, sir.
I found something.
Yeah, it's a bone.
The dead really are
digging themselves up!
Look at how this could be
the haunted execution ground!
Pull it together.
Even if this was where they executed
people, they wouldn't have buried them here.
This is more likely
the work of a murderer.
I think this bone is our only evidence of a
crime that someone would rather have forgotten.
But what killer in their right mind would
sneak onto military soil to dump a body?
Unless this could be the result
of an incident within the military.
I'd say there's a
strong chance of that.
We may be looking at
the bone of a slain soldier.
Our mission is to identify who our victim was,
where they came from, and if we can, how they died.
Don't miss personal effects.
And it may not all be buried
in one spot, so spread out!
You got it!
Well, I can't exactly
say I was expecting that.
Who the hell is
responsible for this fiasco?!
So how was your night?
I've had better.
Hello?
Colonel, the
Tiger's on the prowl.
I fully expect you to
deliver us to victory.
Excuse me.
Hm?
What is it?
Führer, I'm requesting permission
to join this Eastern campaign.
I'm afraid you've
come too late, Colonel.
Major Armstrong's already been
assigned to help me with command.
With respect, the Major hasn't served on the
front line since he was hurt in the Ishbal War.
Now is hardly the time to redeploy him into combat,
especially in a region where he has no recent experience.
I also feel partly responsible for this
latest uprising, seeing as how I was
formerly stationed at
the Eastern headquarters.
Please, let me tag along.
Hm.
I have no objections
to his request.
Very well.
Colonel Mustang, you are hereby ordered to accompany
the expeditionary forces to suppress the insurrection.
I accept it with honor, sir.
Full Metal Alchemist
Episode 38,
With the River's Flow.
In the past when we fought, and it seemed like we'd never
be happy again, I'd always go sit by the river's edge.