On the day we left, we burned down the
family home and all the familiar things inside.
Because some memories
aren't meant to leave traces.
Al.
You're okay with this, right?
Huh?
I mean leaving
everything behind.
You don't have regrets, do you?
There's no turning back now.
And remember, I'm the one
who insisted on coming with you.
Besides, we both know you'll
miss home more than I will.
Good riddance,
that's what I say.
Because you know who's on his
way to becoming a State Alchemist?
Me!
Me too!
And when I become a State Alchemist,
the first thing I'll do is fix your body.
I told you, Al.
That's not your burden.
You just have to
take care of yourself.
I wonder how one goes about
becoming a State Alchemist.
Do you think we'll
have to take a test?
Whatever it was,
I'm happy I came.
These boys can try
human alchemy and survive.
I gotta tell you, their dad just
dropped a rung on my priority list.
Whatever it takes, I'm sure
Mustang will guide us through it.
[Laughs] What am
I stressing for, Al?
With talent like mine,
this'll be a cakewalk for me!
What?
Are you thinking about Winry?
There's nothing we can do.
Those stubborn boys
made their choice.
But they'll realize their
mistake and come back home.
I hope so.
I really do.
Humankind cannot gain anything
without first giving something in return.
To obtain, something of
equal value must be lost.
That is alchemy's first
law of equivalent exchange.
In those days, we really believed
that to be the world's one and only truth.
Fullmetal Alchemist:
A Forger's Love
Brother, do you know what
time our next train leaves?
Yeah, not till tomorrow morning.
Let's get some shut-eye.
[A woman screams]
My purse!
He stole my purse!
Break's over.
Yep.
It's almost too easy.
Huh?
Off to bed with you.
Like good little boys now.
What the...
I think you're the one who
crawled out of the crib too early.
Nicely done.
Now that was something else.
Your trick there wouldn't be
what they call alchemy, would it?
Yeah.
Hmmmm. To think kids your age could
be such accomplished alchemists already.
Around these parts, the only
alchemist I ever get to see is old Majahal.
Majahal, huh?
Yep.
They say he does great things for
people with his alchemy, like you boys did.
He's quite well respected.
Where can we find him?
Oh, the next town over.
But you really don't want
to go there right now, boys.
I've heard it's become
a dangerous place.
They say the dead have risen from their
graves and are sending the villagers to them.
Why are you so interested in
meeting this Majahal person, brother?
That name.
That same name kept popping
up all over those old letters.
You mean Dad's letters?
Yeah.
And if I remember, he wrote
about human transmutation.
I figure if it's the same Majahal,
it can't hurt to pay him a visit.
Yeah.
I have a feeling this is
going to be a good trip.
What's wrong?
You seem almost happy.
Hm?
Well, we did snag that purse snatcher,
and then everyone was so grateful to us.
I guess I'm just starting to see
how alchemy has the power to make
other people's lives
a little bit better.
[He groans]
Are you alright, Brother?
Yeah, I'm just peachy.
I love turbulent carriage rides
and seats as soft as granite.
It didn't bother you at all?
Uh-uh.
[Groan] Well, you look at that.
Someone's throwing a party.
With torches and everything.
But they forgot to invite us.
That one got a little
too close to the village.
You aren't supposed to be here.
This place is off limits.
You could get yourself killed!
In the middle of testing fireworks
for the -- [Ed] Yeah, we noticed that.
They're for the festival.
I'm in charge.
Hey, you guys aren't
from around here, are you?
What is this ugly thing?
Some kind of a giant
robot from the future?
Quit it!
Show them how we
welcome strangers.
My back!
We sure showed them.
What's going on here?
Huh?
You must be Majahal.
Such fine workmanship.
That's truly an impressive
spirit attachment.
He knows about me, brother.
I'd expect nothing less
from the sons of Hohenheim.
Apparently you've
inherited his great talent.
Now then, tell me what I
can do for you boys today.
Surely you've come here seeking
something particular, and I can't very well
disappoint the
sons of a dear friend.
I've read the letters
you wrote to my dad.
I want to know more
about human transmutation.
No doubt you're aware...
that human alchemy is strictly
forbidden by the laws of the state.
Yeah, I know.
But I don't care!
I will return my
brother to his body!
I think you have already
seen firsthand the incredibly
high toll of messing
around with human alchemy.
I know how it feels to lose someone,
but the act of molding flesh is better
left to the hands of God.
Okay, if that's the way you feel, then why
were you so obsessed with it back then?
Youthful optimism.
Or youthful foolishness.
Hello, Mr. Majahal.
I made a batch of rose jam and had some
extra, so I thought perhaps you might enjoy.
Of course.
You spoil me Lebbie.
You're too kind.
Not at all.
Was there something else then?
No.
I'm sorry.
Excuse me.
Well, all right.
Take care.
[Eating]
So, what is this
festival we heard about?
Oh, yes.
The Requiem Festival.
It's when the spirits of the dead are sent
up on fireworks to be returned to heaven
on fireworks to be returned
to heaven where they belong.
And what about all these rumors we
heard about the dead coming back to life as
murderous zombies
on a bloody rampage?
Did that have
anything to do with it?
Silly rumors of a
superstitious town.
My, my.
I certainly am popular
this evening, aren't I?
You--Little brat!
Out with it,Claus. Don't you
have something to say to Majahal?
But I don't really see why
I should have to apologize.
It's their stupid fault for being
so weak for boys, anyway.
What?
Let me at her!
Oh, Claus.
I know your sister's
death affected you.
But you were once such a
sweet and gentle little girl.
What would your late sister think if
she could see what you've turned into?
Shut up!
You don't know how I feel!
Nobody does!
My sister didn't
just up and die.
She was killed
by that dead girl!
Okay.
Come again?
[she cries]
Claus, no!
Wait!
Hey!
Come back here!
You're alchemists?
And you saved me?
It's been nearly six
months since my sister died.
We had no idea how or why.
One of the villagers
just found her.
Lying there like she was asleep.
But she wasn't asleep.
And then, on the
night of her funeral...
Oh, Claus.
K-Karin?
My father told me that
she was a woman who lived
in the village a long
time ago before she died.
Don't you see?
From there, it wasn't
hard to put it together.
The dead lady came back
to life and killed my sister.
And others, too.
It's all because of her.
But if you guys really are alchemists,
you can help me avenge her death.
I've begged Majahal to help,
but he refuses to take part.
What do you say?
I can see why Majahal
wouldn't consider it.
Your theory is as logically
sound as a ghost tale.
Besides, I don't believe
in revenge as motivation.
You're just saying that because you're
nothing but a couple of chickens posing as
alchemists when you're just a cowardly
pipsqueak and his walking trash can!
Pipsqueak?
Trash can?
Nobody calls me a pipsqueak
and gets away with it!
Not even a little girl!
Oh, is that so?
Gosh, I'm so terrified of
the whiny little pipsqueak.
Shut up and take
a look at yourself!
If you're a girl like they all say,
why do you look like a paperboy?
None of your business!
Karin?
Ah yes, I remember her.
She was a florist and
the exquisite beauty
of her flowers was
surpassed only by her own.
I can't believe it's
been 20 years now.
She had recently succeeded in
cultivating the extremely rare blue Rose.
Oh, the woman's smile
at the time was simply...
But then, on her way to
deliver her blue roses into town...
And so she fell to
her death that day.
She fell out of all
of our lives forever...
But they say this same Karin
has been terrorizing the villagers.
Absolutely impossible.
We both know the dead
don't simply come back to life.
And even if they could, if you knew
Karin at all, you'd know it would be
inconceivable for her to
harm anyone in life or in death.
Hmm... So, what do
you think, Brother?
Well, I don't buy ghosts or
zombies or the living dead.
But supposing someone were to perform a
human transmutation, the only one around
here capable of such a
thing would be Majahal, who...
What was that?
You hear that, or
am I going crazy?
Hear... what?
So, we're really gonna do this?
Yeah, we're gonna catch
this Karin zombie on our own.
Because no one else
is gonna do it for us.
Are you wussing out on me?
If this keeps up, someone
else is gonna get killed.
And it could be you.
Yeah, but what
if she tries to...
Come on, lady.
Are you trying to
give me an ulcer?
I'm so sorry.
It was an accident.
So then we make
our move tonight.
You got that?
Brother, wait for me!
What's with you?
Are you scared?
Of course not.
There aren't really any
zombies around, are there?
Don't be thick, Al.
If Karin is roaming these woods, it
would only be thanks to human alchemy.
Which is the only
reason we're here.
[He yells]
It worked!
We got her!
Huh?
Ow, my back! Again!
False alarm!
Over there!
You took my sister from me!
Wait!
Claus!
[She yells]
[Screeching]
[Gasp] That sound again.
Majahal is just a two-bit
alchemist after all...
How disappointing.
To Majahal! A real
hero! Yeah! Majahal!
It weren't for you, this town
would be overrun by zombies.
I knew you'd put
her in her place.
What are you doing, Ed?
I was right about her not being a
zombie, but she wasn't a transmute either.
That sound she made, it's
the same one I heard in here.
Majahal will be very
cross if he finds you.
He doesn't like it when
people snoop around his home.
Yeah?
And what do you call
what you're doing?
[He cries out]
Brother!
Wha-What's all this?
Hey, are you alright?
At last, he awakens.
It appears you've
stumbled across something
that you really shouldn't
have seen, Edward.
Oh, you mean the
so-called zombies?
Yeah.
I saw your toys.
Toys?
They're canvases
for spirit attachments.
Mannequins I've carved into exact
replicas of my beloved Karin, onto which I bind
the soul of any
village girl I can snare.
In doing so, I've formed
living versions of my fallen love.
It's shocking that
plan ever went awry.
It is true that souls tend to reject foreign
vessels that are unlike them in nature.
They usually malfunction.
That's why Al is so special.
Some of my dolls escaped, wandering
free about the village, fueling superstitions.
You crazy, selfish nutcase!
Do you even know
what you've done?
Why the hell did you do it?
For the same reason any man has
ever done anything that is visionary.
Karinne was the only
woman I ever loved.
Even years after her death,
my scars refused to heal.
I committed myself to bringing her back,
using the only talent I had at my disposal.
Alchemy.
When my attempts at human transmutation
failed, the least I could do was create
something that
resembled her beauty.
I did it for love.
So you chose body over soul.
Shut up!
You're a child.
What could you
possibly know of love?
But you do know
something of alchemy.
And now you're going to help me with
an attachment like you did for your brother.
Yeah, right.
It figures.
You're just as stubborn, if not
more so, than your father was.
Huh?
I just wanted to
thank you for earlier.
You foolish girl.
Run, Claus!
It's gone too far.
I can't turn a blind
eye any longer.
Then you should try turning
the other cheek, wench!
Do something, Al!
Just a little more.
The rare blue rose.
Little soul, accept
your new vessel.
Wherever you
are, Karin, bless us.
Let her become just like you.
No!
Let me go!
Let her go, Majahal.
Nothing you think
you know is the truth.
And what you've been seeking
all along is under your nose.
What is this nonsense?
I'm trying to tell you
that Karin never died.
The day of the accident, she hit her head, lost
her memory, and started a new life somewhere.
Twenty years later, her
memory returned in a flash.
And in a true gesture of love,
she came straight back to you.
But you were too blinded by
obsession to see it was her.
Yes, Majahal.
It can't.
Are you telling me this
wrinkled old woman is Karin?
Karin was a woman of
incomparable beauty and perfection.
Just like a rose.
Exactly like a rose.
Flowers wither, Majahal.
But despite what you've become,
Karin's feelings for you have not.
Silence, child.
Say one more word...
and you're dead!
Oh!
Majahal...
I... don't see it.
There's just no way you
could possibly be my Karin.
Karin... I'm coming for you.
[She wails]
Good to see you're
depressed and back to normal.
Huh?
I'm sorry.
I was just thinking how alchemy
has the power to delude people, too.
Yeah.
Guess it does.
Hey!
I'm sorry about
everything I did and said.
You guys really are
terrific alchemists!
Uh...Yeah, we are.
But who are you?
Call me crazy, Ed.
But I think that's Claus.
Mm-hmm
Huh?
Will you boys grow up?
You're definitely much prettier
when you don't dress like a paperboy!
[She laughs...for some reason]
Full Metal Alchemist.
Episode 5.
The Man with the Mechanical Arm.
Rather than give him power, his
arm seems to have power over him.
He says we're one and the same.
Are we?